<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wealth on Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/tags/wealth/</link><description>Recent content in Wealth on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'>Basil Labib&lt;/a> | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Basic&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 16:56:47 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/tags/wealth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Closer Look at 'Inside Job'</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-closer-look-at-inside-job/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 16:56:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-closer-look-at-inside-job/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Inside Job&amp;rdquo; is a 2010 documentary written, directed and produced by Charles Ferguson on the 2008 global financial crisis. It won the Oscar in the &amp;ldquo;Best Documentary Feature&amp;rdquo; category in 2011. Notwithstanding, it makes for an enlightening and thrilling watch that every citizen, who cares about where their hard earned money goes, should watch.
This documentary is not an easy watch that one can grab on a lazy afternoon comfortable on their couch.</description></item><item><title>Notes: The Millionaire Fastlane by MJ DeMarco</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-millionaire-fastlane-by-mj-demarco/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 21:02:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-millionaire-fastlane-by-mj-demarco/</guid><description>Are you able to successfully leverage the opportunities at your disposal? That is the question that this book tries to answer and provides advice backed by the author&amp;rsquo;s own experiences. The book is written in a comfortable conversational style, including way too many metaphors and analogies.
The author, himself, has a remarkable lifestyle: starting a tech company during the dot-com bubble, growing it, selling it and so on. Below I have aggregated few core ideas from the book.</description></item><item><title>Notes: I Will Teach You To Be Rich by Ramit Sethi</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-i-will-teach-you-to-be-rich-by-ramit-sethi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-i-will-teach-you-to-be-rich-by-ramit-sethi/</guid><description>Sethi&amp;rsquo;s book, at it&amp;rsquo;s core, is a set of rules and tricks that can be applied by an aware and motivated individual to ensure a life of abundance relative to their current financial standings. Motivated to become rich himself (and hailing from India) at a young age, Sethi learnt from his blunders and noted his successes. He started blogging about his wins which eventually evolved into this book. Needless to say, his advice are well-researched, practical and tested.</description></item></channel></rss>