<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Univs on Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/univ/</link><description>Recent content in Univs on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'>Basil Labib&lt;/a> | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Basic&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 09:28:23 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/univ/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Minority</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-minority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 09:28:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-minority/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post should have come 20 days before, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t gather the peace of mind to actually sit down and write it. But since 20 days &lt;em>have&lt;/em> elapsed, let&amp;rsquo;s make it a narration of my experience so far at IITD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I appeared for my first university minor exams, a new experience. I met seniors and club representatives and got myself involved in a small development project for Rendezvous, our institute&amp;rsquo;s cultural fest. I arranged for a bicycle from a senior and got it repaired from the shop yesterday. The Omicron variant is out at large, and the management is apprehensive of keeping students on campus. Most of my wingmates and friends have returned home. I just don&amp;rsquo;t feel like going home, that 24-hour journey, all the packing, I hate that. Besides, the Delhi cold is suiting my skin in a way (Although it&amp;rsquo;s too dry than I want it to be). As a result, I&amp;rsquo;m alone in my wing with few other boys, typing away at my laptop, looking out the window, and strumming the guitar I borrowed until mine arrives. No, but really, I like not having to make small talk with people, being disrupted doing something important, putting my thought into behaving.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reaching IIT Delhi</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/univ/reaching-iitd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 19:19:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/univ/reaching-iitd/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This post is a penned down expression of my personal experience. It is considerably less &amp;ldquo;lean&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;unpolished&amp;rdquo;. That is by choice, as I wanted to capture the spontaneity of the moments. What you&amp;rsquo;re about to read is arguably personal so be considerate! Have fun!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="dec-21-2021-817">Dec 21, 2021 8:17&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I look out the scratched glass window out at the receding landscape. it&amp;rsquo;s buildings and bridges. The sun is above my head, looking directly down at me, kissing me gently. And the railway tracks meander and merge like serpents and timelines, streaks of solid steel gleaming in the sun, hypnotizing the wry traveler like the sirens of Messina.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The First 15 Days</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-first-15-days/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 13:39:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-first-15-days/</guid><description>&lt;p>I wanted to capture my exact thought processes and emotional turbulence during the first 15 days of &amp;ldquo;housewarming&amp;rdquo; (if so you will) at IITD. This is that post.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One line summary for the TLDR peeps: Overwhelming. Hectic. Slightly intimidating academically and abysmally solitary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We had our rightful hostel online meet on December 1st. I&amp;rsquo;m from Udaigiri. A serious meetup where our BSW reps laid down the rules and regulations of the hostel. Things like the disciplinary committee (DisCo), abuses, tolerance, offensive views, and so on. I would, obviously, respect other people and uphold the integity and sanctity of the university. And yet, one never knows when one crosses a line, either consciously or unconsciously, which is something that I must admit I&amp;rsquo;m a bit apprehensive about. It was also slightly uncomfortable &lt;em>being told&lt;/em> to follow rules that should be given for a freshman. I mean, respecting girls, tolerance towards diverse views etc., ain&amp;rsquo;t these basic ideals of a civilized individual? Yet, as I was about to learn, IITD isn&amp;rsquo;t as safe and glorious as I had thought (Will come back to it later).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Accidental IITian</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-accidental-iitian/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 18:43:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-accidental-iitian/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are events and people beyond our control who affect our lives in deeper ways that we can comprehend. 2020 was such an year for me. A most memorable year. I knew it from the moment our honorable PM announced &lt;em>a&lt;/em> lockdown in March 2020 that my JEE was going to be a &lt;em>much&lt;/em> different ride than how I had envisioned it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some people are unfazed by sitting in front of a screen for hours, listening through a headphone clasped around their skull. I feel suffocated. Pandemic time was memorable as school teachers and coaching tried to make sense of online education, setting standards, and establishing SOPs. They failed of course but anyway, that&amp;rsquo;s not the point. I analysed why my body has such a drastic physical aversion to attending a lecture digitally. Every student has a unique pedagogical approach to learning, by listening, watching, reading, or discussing. I pay attention in class. Perhaps, it&amp;rsquo;s a residue of the &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;be a good boy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> attitude instilled in me by mom and dad. 100% attendance is another one. I reckon I have to begin fighting these habits. I can&amp;rsquo;t focus on a screen because of time lag and the constant jittery noise of microphones. My brain can&amp;rsquo;t perceive the nuances of teaching, like the instructor&amp;rsquo;s body language or tone modulation. A certain class decorum like sitting at a desk and actually taking notes on paper. These things are important to me. Some of them couldn&amp;rsquo;t materialize. Who is to be blamed? No one. I am responsible for fucking up my JEE because &lt;em>it was all my fault&lt;/em> (so does my father say).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>