<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Univs on Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/univ/</link><description>Recent content in Univs on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'>Basil Labib&lt;/a> | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Basic&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 09:28:23 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/univ/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Minority</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-minority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 09:28:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-minority/</guid><description>This post should have come 20 days before, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t gather the peace of mind to actually sit down and write it. But since 20 days have elapsed, let&amp;rsquo;s make it a narration of my experience so far at IITD.
I appeared for my first university minor exams, a new experience. I met seniors and club representatives and got myself involved in a small development project for Rendezvous, our institute&amp;rsquo;s cultural fest.</description></item><item><title>Reaching IIT Delhi</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/univ/reaching-iitd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 19:19:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/univ/reaching-iitd/</guid><description>Abstract This post is a penned down expression of my personal experience. It is considerably less &amp;ldquo;lean&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;unpolished&amp;rdquo;. That is by choice, as I wanted to capture the spontaneity of the moments. What you&amp;rsquo;re about to read is arguably personal so be considerate! Have fun!
Dec 21, 2021 8:17 I look out the scratched glass window out at the receding landscape. it&amp;rsquo;s buildings and bridges. The sun is above my head, looking directly down at me, kissing me gently.</description></item><item><title>The First 15 Days</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-first-15-days/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 13:39:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-first-15-days/</guid><description>I wanted to capture my exact thought processes and emotional turbulence during the first 15 days of &amp;ldquo;housewarming&amp;rdquo; (if so you will) at IITD. This is that post.
One line summary for the TLDR peeps: Overwhelming. Hectic. Slightly intimidating academically and abysmally solitary.
We had our rightful hostel online meet on December 1st. I&amp;rsquo;m from Udaigiri. A serious meetup where our BSW reps laid down the rules and regulations of the hostel.</description></item><item><title>The Accidental IITian</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-accidental-iitian/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 18:43:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-accidental-iitian/</guid><description>There are events and people beyond our control who affect our lives in deeper ways that we can comprehend. 2020 was such an year for me. A most memorable year. I knew it from the moment our honorable PM announced a lockdown in March 2020 that my JEE was going to be a much different ride than how I had envisioned it.
Some people are unfazed by sitting in front of a screen for hours, listening through a headphone clasped around their skull.</description></item></channel></rss>