<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cocteau twins on The Personal Blog of Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/tags/cocteau-twins/</link><description>Recent content in cocteau twins on The Personal Blog of Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'>Basil Labib&lt;/a> | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Basic&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/tags/cocteau-twins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Music Order Arrived</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-music-order-arrived/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-music-order-arrived/</guid><description>A rather crazy self-imposed project which I had the faintest of ideas will become all-devouring and pose countless hurdles for me to dodge. But yeah, did it. Don&amp;rsquo;t blame me for the CT making ethereal noises!
From left to right: Treasure, Stars and Topsoil and Heaven or Las Vegas (all CDs)
Why do I have to buy music? In a nutshell, because I want to. But seriously, why in a world of Spotify and pirated downloadable songs would I have the brilliant idea to buy music?</description></item><item><title>Stuck by Fandom for the First Time in My Life</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/stuck-by-fandom-for-the-first-time-in-my-life/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/stuck-by-fandom-for-the-first-time-in-my-life/</guid><description>Ethereal, heavenly, celestial, opulent, splendid, otherworldly - these adjectives form the regular staple of people who dare to describe the music of the Cocteau Twins (pronounced: cock-tow twins). Honestly, I think it&amp;rsquo;s an effort in vain. Because this band defies all possibilities of being defined by words. Cage them in artificial genres and you will fail. You can only experience their &amp;ldquo;sacred microcosm&amp;rdquo; yourself as Azam Ali so eloquently puts it.</description></item></channel></rss>