<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Personal Blog of Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on The Personal Blog of Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'>Basil Labib&lt;/a> | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Basic&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 13:12:55 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Escapade Into Uttarakhand: A travelogue</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/escapade-into-uttarakhand-a-travelogue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 13:12:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/escapade-into-uttarakhand-a-travelogue/</guid><description>Introduction This travelogue was created based on my journal entries on a daily(ish) basis. I volunteered as a teacher at a remote village in Uttarakhand and helped high school kids prepare for competitive exams (JEE/NEET) for two weeks. This travelogue is presented almost in its entirety with few redacts that I deemed too personal.
Day 1 (30/31 May) I got onto an almost full Traveller van in front of Satpura1 amidst torrential rain and found myself greeted with unknown (and somewhat hostile) faces.</description></item><item><title>Reading Pygmalion: Shaw's criticism of the English language and society</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/reading-pygmalion-shaws-criticism-of-the-english-language-and-society/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 16:45:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/reading-pygmalion-shaws-criticism-of-the-english-language-and-society/</guid><description>There are two central questions at the heart of &amp;ldquo;Pygmalion&amp;rdquo; - the more obvious, is the question of identity and how easy or difficult it is to render a different identity to a person and the second, more subtle question is of the very plausibility of the metrics used for class distinction - namely speech in this case. In fact, phonetics would undoubtedly have been a close affair with the author himself, a Dublin-based clerk with his Irish accent wishing to make his career as a writer in England.</description></item><item><title>A Case for Politics: Carpets, Catharsis, and other Conundrums</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-case-for-politics-carpets-catharsis-and-other-conundrums/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:09:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-case-for-politics-carpets-catharsis-and-other-conundrums/</guid><description>It’s mid-april, that merry time of the year when the campus is released from the noose of tension and treachery. The student elections have just concluded and people are turning back to studying and turning their backs from speculating, amidst scalding Delhi heat. IIT Delhi has five boards - BSW, BRCA, BSP, BSA, and BHM under the aegis of SAC and a different council called CAIC. All these boards have various posts (the description of which can be found by the reader via an internet search) for which students are elected by various electorals.</description></item><item><title>Watchlog</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/watchlog/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 21:26:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/watchlog/</guid><description>This page contains a list of movies/series that I have watched or am watching. I tried doing this before but couldn&amp;rsquo;t maintain and went into an entire &amp;ldquo;phase&amp;rdquo; but anyways, here we go again.
2023 The Lives of Others | Florian Henckel von Donnersmarck | 2006 Annie Hall | Woody Allen | 1977 Gangs of Wasseypur | Anruag Kashyap | 2012 Schindler&amp;rsquo;s List | Steven Spielberg | 1993 V for Vendetta | Every Day | Micheal Suscy | Dead Poets Society | Peter Wier | The Ring | Alfred Hithcock | 1927 The Whale | Darren Aronofsky | 2022 Full Metal Jacket | Stanley Kubrick | The Lodger | Alfred Hithcock | On the Road | Walter Salles | 2012 Hopscotch | Ronald Neame | 1980 Rear Window | Alfred Hithcock | The Story of a Crime | Fyodor Khitruk | 1962 The Snow Queen | | 1957 In the Realm of the Senses | Nagisa Oshima | 1976 A History of Violence | | 2005 The Royal Tenenbaums | Wes Anderson | Buffalo &amp;lsquo;66 | Vincent Gallo | Notting Hill | Roger Mitchell | Masaan | Neeraj Ghaywan | The Brown Bunny | Vincent Gallo | Cold War | Pawei Pawlikowski | 2018 Sunrise: A Song of Two Humans | F.</description></item><item><title>German Expressionism and its influence on Robert Weine</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/german-expressionism-and-its-influence-on-robert-weine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 18:37:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/german-expressionism-and-its-influence-on-robert-weine/</guid><description>Das Kabinett der Dr. Caligari (The Cabinet of Dr. Caligari) is a 1920 German thriller drama directed by Robert Weine and starring Werner Strauss as the eponymous character and Conrad Veidt as Cesare. Caligari is seen as the de facto standard of a peculiar period in German cinema christened German Expressionism. This new direction in German cinema was mostly an expression of a greater intellectual cum social movement called Expressionism - a cry against Impressionism and Naturalism but I’m getting ahead of myself.</description></item><item><title>Playing God: Making sense of CRISPR</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/playing-god-making-sense-of-crispr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 16:29:20 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/playing-god-making-sense-of-crispr/</guid><description>Abstract Imagine standing on a long corridor with closed doors that stretches to infinity on both ends. One keeps walking along and knocking on each door, maybe trying to pick the lock, peeping through the keyhole, or even trying to break in. But the process is tiresome and hopeless. And yet once in a while, someone manages to open a door and view a world they have never imagined. The story of scientific innovation is roughly similar to the story of the endless corridor.</description></item><item><title>Prometheus Unleashed: Making sense of information hazards</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/prometheus-unleashed-making-sense-of-information-hazards/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 11:18:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/prometheus-unleashed-making-sense-of-information-hazards/</guid><description>Intro As part of my research into global existential risks, I came across the conundrum of information hazard which simply refers to the potential misuse of scientific or technological information by bad actors that might turn into a global risk for everyone.
This phenomenon is most aggravated in the field of biotechnological research where misuse of increasingly openly available genomic data or cheaper protein synthesis techniques can easily be used to develop and mass-produce humanity-threatening super-pathogens (“super” referring to immunity against all known forms of human cure).</description></item><item><title>Modern Times: Where are we headed?</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/modern-times-where-are-we-headed/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 13:56:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/modern-times-where-are-we-headed/</guid><description>sidenotes Posting some of my silly drawings here because a good friend said I should so oh well! It&amp;rsquo;s painful to watch his blog go unnourished like this but I&amp;rsquo;m constrained by my physical limitations of being a human and being unable to transcend and/or manipulate the fourth dimension of time.
Enjoy the comic until next time!</description></item><item><title>Year in Books: 2022</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/bs/yib2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:49:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/bs/yib2022/</guid><description>Fierce People | Dirk Wittenhorn A good first read of the year. A thriller, romance, and coming-of-age novel all wrapped in one.
I&amp;rsquo;m glad I read the book before I&amp;rsquo;m going to watch the movie. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t put it down once I started. I wrote an in-depth post so I won&amp;rsquo;t bore you here.
Bright Lights, Big City | Jay McInerney This book presents one of the most elucidated, explicit, and candid portrayals of eighties New York.</description></item><item><title>BUIDL: Hitching a ride on the web3 wagon</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/buidl-hitching-a-ride-on-the-web3-wagon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 09:28:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/buidl-hitching-a-ride-on-the-web3-wagon/</guid><description>ETHIndia 2022&amp;rsquo; @Whitefield, BLR
Infinite Garden: a diverse ecosystem of individuals and organizations that build and grow alongside ethereum. The Ethereum ecosystem, particularly the scaling L2 solutions are witnessing dramatic progress in terms of breakthroughs and innovation. The Infinite Garden is the phrase used to refer to the truly decentralized techno-haven where interaction between online entities are transparent and uncensored. Free from censorship, state control, fraud, and malicious agents, powered by the ecosystem of applications built on blockchains - in short, an information utopia.</description></item><item><title>À bout de souffle: The politics of Godard's debut feature</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/%C3%A0-bout-de-souffle-the-politics-of-godards-debut-feature/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 10:38:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/%C3%A0-bout-de-souffle-the-politics-of-godards-debut-feature/</guid><description>Introduction Art, by its very nature, challenges the status quo. It has the power, and I would argue, responsibility, to sway people to stand up against unjust and authoritarian regimes. It serves as the voice of the marginalised and the voiceless. The twentieth century philosopher Theodore Adorno famously said,
&amp;ldquo;All art is an uncommitted crime&amp;rdquo;.
~Theodore Adorno
The acclaimed Spanish painter, Pablo Picasso painted The Guernica as an expression of protest against war.</description></item><item><title>I am 20: Remembering India's youth</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/i-am-20-remembering-indias-youth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 14:30:10 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/i-am-20-remembering-indias-youth/</guid><description>In 1967, the Films Division of India produced a short documentary under director S.N.S. Sastry. The simple, 18-minute documentary titled &amp;ldquo;I am 20&amp;rdquo; depicts the lives of the Indian youths, their hopes, aspirations, and apprehensions. It captures the true spirit of the Indian mindset of the 60s, the multitude of visions and dreams and ambitions. For an Indian youth watching this documentary, it is very difficult not to be moved by it.</description></item><item><title>The Pillowman: Artistry in a totalitarian regime</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-pillowman-artistry-in-a-totalitarian-regime/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 21:45:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-pillowman-artistry-in-a-totalitarian-regime/</guid><description>The Pillowman, Martin McDonagh, 2003
Introduction Martin McDonagh&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Pillowman&amp;rdquo; is an enquiry into the freedom of an artist in an oppressive totalitarian regime. Katurian, a writer, is interrogated by two brute and somewhat foppish policemen in custody about his role in the recent chain of children murders who were killed in ways elucidated by Katurian in his works. But what eventually unravels is Katurian&amp;rsquo;s own dark past, his dysfunctional family, and the character of his retarded brother whom he loves so much.</description></item><item><title>The Quant Frenzy: A Crude Forecast</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-quant-frenzy-a-crude-forecast/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 17:45:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-quant-frenzy-a-crude-forecast/</guid><description>What motivated this post? Recently, I finished reading Gregory Zuckerman&amp;rsquo;s brilliantly researched book on the pioneering ultra-secretive quantitative investment firm Renaissance Technologies and its founder and mathematics prodigy, Jim Simons. It is an exhaustive and impressive account of a newer, data-driven, non-conservative approach to trading financial instruments. RenTec&amp;rsquo;s flagship hedge fund, Medallion, has averaged a mind-boggling 71.8% annual return, before fees, from 1994 to 2014. Medallion is considered a glaring example of a pioneering experiment that trounced skeptics and traditional investors who were smug about their intuitive abilities as traders and scoffed at the idea of letting computer programs decide the fate of the markets.</description></item><item><title>The Minority</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-minority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 09:28:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-minority/</guid><description>This post should have come 20 days before, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t gather the peace of mind to actually sit down and write it. But since 20 days have elapsed, let&amp;rsquo;s make it a narration of my experience so far at IITD.
I appeared for my first university minor exams, a new experience. I met seniors and club representatives and got myself involved in a small development project for Rendezvous, our institute&amp;rsquo;s cultural fest.</description></item><item><title>Fierce People: A riveting tale of deceit and drama</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/fierce-people-a-riveting-tale-of-deceit-and-drama/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 19:19:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/fierce-people-a-riveting-tale-of-deceit-and-drama/</guid><description>Introduction Although, I have encountered and internalized many teenaged male protagonists, from the meek Charlie from POBAW, to the valiant Tariq, to the quirky Holden Caulfield, Finn Earl, my latest discovery, refuses to be filed amongst them. He is the sixteen-year old protagonist of Dirk Wittenhorn&amp;rsquo;s 2002 novel &amp;ldquo;Fierce People&amp;rdquo; which is a coming-of-age story, a thriller, and a romance all wrapped in one. Although, there is so much going on between these pages and I have met so many memorable characters, it is invariably Finn&amp;rsquo;s transformation that is the central piece that effuses meaning to it all.</description></item><item><title>Year in Books: 2021</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/bs/yib2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 22:18:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/bs/yib2021/</guid><description>Abstract The list of books I have read in 2021 along with thoughts and views on some of them. Enjoy!
Zero to One | Peter Thiel Non-fiction, Startup, Essential, Vision, Principles
Rosemary&amp;rsquo;s baby | Ira Levine
Fiction, Fantasy, Witchcraft, Classic
Vivekananda&amp;rsquo;s Biography | Swami Nikhelananda
Non-fiction, Biography, Monk, Vedanta, Philosophy, Inspiration
The Three Body Problem | Cixin Liu
Fiction, Hard SF (science fiction), Contact, Classic
Transform your Habits | James Clear Non-fiction, Psychology, Self-help, Habits, Short</description></item><item><title>Reaching IIT Delhi</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/univ/reaching-iitd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 19:19:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/univ/reaching-iitd/</guid><description>Abstract This post is a penned down expression of my personal experience. It is considerably less &amp;ldquo;lean&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;unpolished&amp;rdquo;. That is by choice, as I wanted to capture the spontaneity of the moments. What you&amp;rsquo;re about to read is arguably personal so be considerate! Have fun!
Dec 21, 2021 8:17 I look out the scratched glass window out at the receding landscape. it&amp;rsquo;s buildings and bridges. The sun is above my head, looking directly down at me, kissing me gently.</description></item><item><title>The Prince and the Monk: A fictive conversation</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-prince-and-the-monk-a-fictive-conversation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 17:50:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-prince-and-the-monk-a-fictive-conversation/</guid><description>Abstract The following is a short story of an unnamed young prince of an unknown country in an unspecified time. The story involves just one conversation with a monk and how that unravels the personality of the prince and his hazardous life ahead.
To a future me when he feels too broken.
O nce upon a time, a young prince kneeling in the premises of an old monk asked him,</description></item><item><title>The War to end all wars: The First World War</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-war-to-end-all-wars-the-first-world-war/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 09:50:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-war-to-end-all-wars-the-first-world-war/</guid><description>Micheal Howard&amp;rsquo;s treatment of the First World War is a succint description of the horrors, challenges, tactics, politics, and sentiments that paved the way for one of the bloodiest wars the world had ever seen.
Overview of the causes of WW1 Karl von Clausewitz, after the Napoleanic Wars noted that war was a trinity of the government, the activities of the military, and &amp;ldquo;the passions of the people&amp;rdquo;. Howard goes on to unravel in great detail how these came together to become the causes of WW1.</description></item><item><title>The First 15 Days</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-first-15-days/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 13:39:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-first-15-days/</guid><description>I wanted to capture my exact thought processes and emotional turbulence during the first 15 days of &amp;ldquo;housewarming&amp;rdquo; (if so you will) at IITD. This is that post.
One line summary for the TLDR peeps: Overwhelming. Hectic. Slightly intimidating academically and abysmally solitary.
We had our rightful hostel online meet on December 1st. I&amp;rsquo;m from Udaigiri. A serious meetup where our BSW reps laid down the rules and regulations of the hostel.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://basil08.github.io/droplets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 22:00:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/droplets/</guid><description>Droplets 😄 Why? Posts serve as well-researched, well-articulated opinions and thoughts. But I wanted something that could capture tiny little fleeting ideas. I needed microblogging. Oh, you&amp;rsquo;d say, &amp;ldquo;What about Twitter, pal?&amp;rdquo; Nah, not really. So, I hacked a little microblogging server. The code is open and on GitHub. The script is hosted on the incredible Deta platform and the database on Mongo Atlas.</description></item><item><title>Whose glory are we basking in?</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/whose-glory-are-we-basking-in/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 18:09:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/whose-glory-are-we-basking-in/</guid><description>Twitter just got a brand new CEO. An Indian-born American and an alumni of IIT Bombay. A noticeable pattern: Microsoft – Satya Nadella, Alphabet – Sundar Pichai, IBM – Arvind Krishna, and now a welcome addition to the league of US tech companies run by Indian-born IIT graduates. This news has been quite a subject of debate and argument among my friends and being an IITian myself, I felt it my responsibility to clear up few misconceptions and put forth some context.</description></item><item><title>The Accidental IITian</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-accidental-iitian/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 18:43:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-accidental-iitian/</guid><description>There are events and people beyond our control who affect our lives in deeper ways that we can comprehend. 2020 was such an year for me. A most memorable year. I knew it from the moment our honorable PM announced a lockdown in March 2020 that my JEE was going to be a much different ride than how I had envisioned it.
Some people are unfazed by sitting in front of a screen for hours, listening through a headphone clasped around their skull.</description></item><item><title>A deep dive into JSON Web Tokens (JWTs)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-deep-dive-into-json-web-tokens-jwts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 08:03:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-deep-dive-into-json-web-tokens-jwts/</guid><description>Table Of Contents What is JWT? Why use JWT? Why understand it? How do JWTs work? User authentication: Walkthrough Structure of a JWT The header The payload Hash functions HMAC + SHA256 = HS256 RSA + SHA256 = RS256 Other algorithms Common pitfalls and mitigation techniques Unsecured tokens via alg: none Signature stripping Cross Site Resource Forgery (CSRF) Cross Site Scripting (XSS) References License What is JWT? A JSON Web Token or a JWT (pronounced &amp;ldquo;jot&amp;rdquo;) is a plaintext, human readable piece of data that enables authentication and trust between two unknown entities.</description></item><item><title>Notes: How to Win at College by Cal Newport</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-how-to-win-at-college-by-cal-newport/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 09:22:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-how-to-win-at-college-by-cal-newport/</guid><description>Abstract: This is a summary of the main ideas in Cal Newport&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;How to Win at College&amp;rdquo;.
I spent quite sometime trying to come up with a comprehensive yet concise format to summarize this book. I ended up either copying the whole book or noting only generic, fuzzy advices both of which are of little use to a freshman. Rather, what follows is a summary of the general ideas overarching the book.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts: The Psychology of Money (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-psychology-of-money-book/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 08:58:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-psychology-of-money-book/</guid><description>Abstract Morgan Housel&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Psychology of Money&amp;rdquo; is less of a technical book and more of a collection of wisdom and wishful advices. It is N. Taleb&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Bed of Procrustes&amp;rdquo; augmented with real life anecdotes, morsels of history, and a lot of quotations. Although Housel professes a very conservative and frugal approach to managing money, his advice cannot be disputed without a very good counter argument. The cautious models, frameworks, and signposts laid out in the book would prevent an investor from being foolish and that Housel says is too easy to be in the modern financial system.</description></item><item><title>Web 3.0 and The Metaverse Mania</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/web-3.0-and-the-metaverse-mania/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 19:54:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/web-3.0-and-the-metaverse-mania/</guid><description>There is a shot in Steven Spielberg&amp;rsquo;s 2018 science fiction &amp;ldquo;Ready Player One&amp;rdquo; where the protagonist, Wade, sitting in a shack in Columbus puts on a VR headset and is transported to the planet of Incipio where all avatars are born when they enter the OASIS. They can morph into any characters, cartoon, or monster. Customise how they look and sound and smell. Buy virtual assets and fight in hunts on a planet called Doom (Watch the movie if this is lost on you).</description></item><item><title>Hacktoberfest and open source</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/hacktoberfest-and-open-source/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 06:22:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/hacktoberfest-and-open-source/</guid><description>Table Of Contents THE PHILOSOPHY OF OPEN SOURCE PEOPLE WHO WRITE OPEN SOURCE THE PSYCHOLOGY OF A HACKER WHY IS OPEN SOURCE THE FUTURE? WHY GO OPEN? PERSONAL EXPERIENCE LITTLE HISTORY FURTHER READING BIBLIOGRAPHY DigitalOcean, a cloud service provider annually hosts Hacktoberfest, a month-long celebration of open source culture where developers from around the globe contribute to open projects. It is in its 8th iteration this year and has become quite an attraction for programmers, young and experienced.</description></item><item><title>Building a Discord bot: A definitive guide</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/building-a-discord-bot-a-definitive-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 07:56:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/building-a-discord-bot-a-definitive-guide/</guid><description>In this guide, I will be building a Discord bot from scratch using only discord.js and a few open public APIs. I&amp;rsquo;ll also explain each step and discuss the reason for preference of a particular way of implementation over others. Unlike other &amp;ldquo;recipes&amp;rdquo; on the web, this will give you insight into the workflow of building software.
This may seem like a long post because it is. I suggest you to follow along in chunks so you don&amp;rsquo;t get overwhelmed.</description></item><item><title>A tour of the realist world of Edward Hopper</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-tour-of-the-realist-world-of-edward-hopper/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 13:31:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-tour-of-the-realist-world-of-edward-hopper/</guid><description>American artist and painter, Edward Hopper, didn&amp;rsquo;t achieve much recognition in his lifetime. Today, critics laud his work as quintessential &amp;ldquo;American&amp;rdquo; in spirit as he developed a distinctive signature style. His personal life was fraught with toil and resentment as he watched his contemporaries rise to fame and fortune. He was a married man who had no children and his wife stood as a pillar of support, augmenting his intellect, emotion and career.</description></item><item><title>A personal interpretation of 'The Matrix'</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-personal-interpretation-of-the-matrix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 08:59:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-personal-interpretation-of-the-matrix/</guid><description>I first saw The Matrix last year and like every person who has watched it since its release in 1999, it left my auditory and visual senses on overload and a gargantuan heap of information for my brain to process. A second viewing few days back, made me observe relationships and philosophies that escaped me in the first attempt. There are good reasons why The Matrix is discussed by critics even today from as varied perspectives as social, political, scientific, philosophical and of course, technological and has injected such appealing concepts and ideas in the public imagination that they have managed to pass into our vocabulary and lifestyles.</description></item><item><title>Sylvia Plath, The Bell Jar and feminism</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/sylvia-plath-the-bell-jar-and-feminism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 11:27:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/sylvia-plath-the-bell-jar-and-feminism/</guid><description>"What I hate is the thought of being under a man&amp;rsquo;s thumb&amp;quot;, Sylvia fearlessly thundered in her only published novel &amp;ldquo;The Bell Jar&amp;rdquo;. Published in 1963, Jar is one of the prominent texts on feminism and the vocalisation of a woman&amp;rsquo;s apprehensions, rights and freedom. Sylvia&amp;rsquo;s words, like brazen dagger, are used today in protest marches as well as analysed in literary circles.
Sylvia Plath
Jar stands as testimony to the ephemeral skills of Sylvia as a writer.</description></item><item><title>The IIT Dream: Decoding India's lust for engineers</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-iit-dream-decoding-indias-lust-for-engineers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 14:05:39 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-iit-dream-decoding-indias-lust-for-engineers/</guid><description>India suffers from an unusual sort of disease today. Spotted on walls in metropolises and small towns alike, will be colorful posters with portrait sized photos of teenaged students, posing in institute branded t-shirts with big proud smiles on their faces and occasionally V signs made with fingers. Accompanying them will be a number AIR XXXX, decreasing in font size and prominence as the numbers grow larger as if to suggest a decrease in the importance of the student and their aptitude.</description></item><item><title>31 Years of 'Heaven or Las Vegas'</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/31-years-of-heaven-or-las-vegas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 10:18:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/31-years-of-heaven-or-las-vegas/</guid><description>Most CT fans agree (and frankly, there ain&amp;rsquo;t many) that Heaven or Las Vegas is their definitive production: ephemeral and sublime, cocky song titles and discernable vocals, sweet sounds and fragments of bitter lyrics, it is a very Twins album in spirit. Garlands (1982), their debut, was too much on the punk and goth style, a desperate searching phase for their identity which was fulfilled by Treasure (1984), a commendable opus in itself.</description></item><item><title>'Please myself': An interpretation 30 years later</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/please-myself-an-interpretation-30-years-later/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 08:02:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/please-myself-an-interpretation-30-years-later/</guid><description>Polly, a common American girl name, quickly rose to fame as the 6th songtrack on Nirvana&amp;rsquo;s second album, Nevermind, one of the best-selling albums of all time, having sold over 30 million copies since its release in 1991.
Polly became a conversation starter, an ice-breaker, a household catalyst for people everywhere to talk about woman abuse. Polly is a protest song, a song born out of the anguish that Kurt felt for the condition and treatment of woman in the society.</description></item><item><title>Academic Dishonesty</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/academic-dishonesty/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 11:50:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/academic-dishonesty/</guid><description>Today is September 5th which is celebrated as Teacher&amp;rsquo;s Day in India on the birth anniversary of Dr. Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan, an eminent educator, teacher and the first Vice President of India. As Indian students reach out to pay respect to their teachers via various gestures such as feet embracing albeit digitally this year, I wish to take this opportunity to speak about a much graver issue in the Indian education scenario today.</description></item><item><title>Remembering My Teachers</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/remembering-my-teachers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 10:20:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/remembering-my-teachers/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;The right kind of education begins with the educator, who must understand himself and be free from established patterns of thought; for what he is that he imparts. If he has not been rightly educated, what can he teach except the same mechanical knowledge on which he himself has been brought up?&amp;rdquo;
~J Krishnamurti NR Narayan Murthy, the founder of Infosys, recounted three incidents in his life that taught him core human values and left an indelible mark on him.</description></item><item><title>The Sensuality of Rilke's Love Poems</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-sensuality-of-rilkes-love-poems/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 09:04:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-sensuality-of-rilkes-love-poems/</guid><description>I tell you that I have a long way to go before I am – where one begins&amp;hellip; These are Rilke&amp;rsquo;s first words that I read. I had no prior acquaintance with either the man or his writings, save for a curious Google search on a Cocteau Twins&amp;rsquo; song called Rilkean Heart. And yet, I immediately felt a tug towards these words, gyrating around them, twisting and turning them in my head, trying to make sense of it.</description></item><item><title>Love As An Illegitimate Byproduct</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/love-as-an-illegitimate-byproduct/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 10:18:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/love-as-an-illegitimate-byproduct/</guid><description>Evolutionary biology has always fascinated me. I have marveled at the ingenuity of evolutionists drawing up elegant theories, piecing together the most bizarre of observations with a string of sound reasoning. I guess the quality of making logical sense of the alien world we find ourselves in makes evolution appeal to me.
Recently, I read Jared Diamond&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Why Sex is Fun?&amp;rdquo;, a short book (a series of essays really) about human sexuality and how it differs so radically from every other species we know of.</description></item><item><title>How to Take Correct Decisions</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/how-to-take-correct-decisions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 10:33:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/how-to-take-correct-decisions/</guid><description>Prologue The other day, my sister and I were having this rather enlightening and philosophical conversation on how to navigate life. We&amp;rsquo;re almost adults so it&amp;rsquo;s high time we learn things that schools and parents won&amp;rsquo;t teach us.
The Problem A human life is a game of decision making. It is analogous to a video game with opportunities and options at every turn and the chosen options leading to other opportunities, good or bad, but completely alienating us from the opportunities we have missed.</description></item><item><title>To be or not to be: Understanding Hamlet</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/to-be-or-not-to-be-understanding-hamlet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 10:20:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/to-be-or-not-to-be-understanding-hamlet/</guid><description>Volumes have been written on the &amp;ldquo;meaning&amp;rdquo; of Hamlet (the play) by more qualified people than me. I do not seek to compete with them. What follows is my perception of Hamlet, a sketch so if you will, from a modern day perspective.
Hamlet is a complex character. I have strived to deduce Hamlet strictly from the source text and not get influenced by writings elsewhere because I feel external analysis somehow shrouds (glorifies or diminishs, whichever) the essence of what Shakespeare intended.</description></item><item><title>A Closer Look at 'Inside Job'</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-closer-look-at-inside-job/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 16:56:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-closer-look-at-inside-job/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Inside Job&amp;rdquo; is a 2010 documentary written, directed and produced by Charles Ferguson on the 2008 global financial crisis. It won the Oscar in the &amp;ldquo;Best Documentary Feature&amp;rdquo; category in 2011. Notwithstanding, it makes for an enlightening and thrilling watch that every citizen, who cares about where their hard earned money goes, should watch.
This documentary is not an easy watch that one can grab on a lazy afternoon comfortable on their couch.</description></item><item><title>My School Journey</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-school-journey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 23:34:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-school-journey/</guid><description>Few days back, I graduated high school. Which means a journey of 14 years came to an end. I have numerous delights, some regrets and plenty of memories to take with me. I have some to share too.
Teachers First of all, I want to thank every teacher who has taught me. From holding my hand to write an &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo; in nursery to open discussions in Physics classes to painful lectures in Literature – I have taken a part of you all.</description></item><item><title>The Indian Sexual Taboo</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-indian-sexual-taboo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 15:28:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-indian-sexual-taboo/</guid><description>Recent unravelling of the Raj Kundra porn video business on online streaming platforms has raised many tantalizing questions on the effectiveness of the Indian judiciary. It is indeed shameful and comical to know that the judiciary is confused as to the definition of &amp;ldquo;pornography&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;obscene&amp;rdquo; and specific laws under which to prosecute Kundra and Co.
Why do porn industries flourish? Leaving prosecution and dissemination of judgement to more able individuals than me, I would like to raise few points about the other side of the coin: The Indian porn consumer base.</description></item><item><title>Freakonomics: Should you read it?</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/freakonomics-should-you-read-it/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 11:14:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/freakonomics-should-you-read-it/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Why do drug-dealers still live with their mothers?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Are Sumo wrestlers corrupt?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Legalized abortion led to decreasing crime rates&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Are real-estate agents really acting in your best interest?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Does a child&amp;rsquo;s name have any effect on their lives?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Do parents really matter?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Are swimming pools more dangerous for kids than guns?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Why should teachers cheat?&amp;rdquo;
Freakonomics is a study of bizarre, mundane and exceedingly interesting questions. It employs the arsenal of mathematical sophistication to unearth truths and secrets that are hidden from plain sight.</description></item><item><title>Rereading 'A Thousand Splendid Suns'</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/rereading-a-thousand-splendid-suns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 18:37:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/rereading-a-thousand-splendid-suns/</guid><description>There are all these people constantly questioning me about my identity, my aspirations, my worth. What I want to do? What I want to be? So, I am forced to think about these questions. Indeed, what do I wanna do?
I reread the poignant &amp;ldquo;A Thousand Splendid Suns&amp;rdquo; by Khaled Hosseini. So, I have a habit, for better or worse, of poking around the central content to appreciate the big picture.</description></item><item><title>Is Governance Really So Difficult?</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/is-governance-really-so-difficult/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 13:15:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/is-governance-really-so-difficult/</guid><description>Why is taking economic decisions at a national level such a tantalizing task? Why do government policies fail (sometimes miserably)? Why are people still living on the streets under BPL?
You can expose yourself to an array of criticism and theories spun by supposedly thoughtful individuals at any cafe. These folks go on blurting how the present is worse than a decade ago and on and on. I had heard about their side, I wanted to know about the other side too.</description></item><item><title>Friendship</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/friendship/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 11:37:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/friendship/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;How many times had she, Hasina, and Giti said those same three words to each other, Laila wondered, said it without hesitation, after only two or three days of not seeing each other?
I missed you, Hasina. Oh, I missed you too. In Tariq&amp;rsquo;s grimace, Laila learned that boys differed from girls in this regard. They didn&amp;rsquo;t make a show of friendship. They felt no urge, no need, for this sort of talk.</description></item><item><title>My Reading Portfolio</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-reading-portfolio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 12:00:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-reading-portfolio/</guid><description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t met anybody as devoutly fanatic about books as I am in real life. This love of mine can turn aggressive, even generously self-depreciative, which is a source of concern. I maintain a digital library simply because there won&amp;rsquo;t be enough room for all the books if I build for myself a physical library (Now you know how to impress me 😉). I spend literally hours fretting about organization, intensely debating with myself what parameters to organize under, designing programs to maintain a catalog, devising makeshift ways to register progress and so on.</description></item><item><title>Notes: The Millionaire Fastlane by MJ DeMarco</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-millionaire-fastlane-by-mj-demarco/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 21:02:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-millionaire-fastlane-by-mj-demarco/</guid><description>Are you able to successfully leverage the opportunities at your disposal? That is the question that this book tries to answer and provides advice backed by the author&amp;rsquo;s own experiences. The book is written in a comfortable conversational style, including way too many metaphors and analogies.
The author, himself, has a remarkable lifestyle: starting a tech company during the dot-com bubble, growing it, selling it and so on. Below I have aggregated few core ideas from the book.</description></item><item><title>Migrating From Jekyll to Hugo</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/migrating-from-jekyll-to-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 10:34:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/migrating-from-jekyll-to-hugo/</guid><description>This is a quick note for the convenience of the readers.
With a heave of pleasant sigh, I can inform you all that I am migrating from jekyll to hugo. Finally.
The only hindrance (so to speak) was the choice of a decent theme which, as you can see, has been accomplished. Hugo has a ton of features and conveniences that I would be foolish to not take advantage of. Archetypes, built-in shortcodes, KaTeX typesetting, taxonomies beside being so fast!</description></item><item><title>Bookshelf</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/bookshelf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 22:24:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/bookshelf/</guid><description>Abstract Inspired by Patrick Collison&amp;rsquo;s luscious bookshelf, this page is the list of books I have read in the current year (whichever year you are reading it). Most of these are plucked from other people&amp;rsquo;s recommendation lists, popular choices, stuff I find interesting or just a random topic I want to learn about on a Saturday evening. Suggestions? Drop me a line!
I read somewhere (probably in an Umberto Eco article) that one can understand a man by going through his bookshelf.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 22:12:10 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/about/</guid><description>What should you expect from this blog? This is a blog about psychology, philosophy, economics, technology, science, art and design. It is not proper to believe this blog is limited to the handful of subjects listed above because it is not. To understand our lives demands a multidisciplinary stance.
Perhaps, a better explanation is given by ACX which I quote:
Ṛta is a Sanskrit word, so ancient that it brushes up against the origin of Indo-European languages.</description></item><item><title>Most Scarce Resource</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/most-scarce-resource/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/most-scarce-resource/</guid><description>What is the single most scarce resource at the disposal of man?
The present.
It cannot be acquired or earned. It is available to all in equal measure. It cannot be claimed forever unlike knowledge or lost like friends. We may eschew society to do our biddings but all must surrender to this moment.
Anything that you are doing now is a liability and everything else you chose not to do are missed opportunities.</description></item><item><title>The Sun After A Thuderstorm</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-sun-after-a-thuderstorm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-sun-after-a-thuderstorm/</guid><description>There is something magical about the first sunshine after a thunderstorm. The coolness of the still wet ground and the warm sunshine vapourising the dew. The mist hanging low over the floor mixing with the musky smell of freshly spawned algae. The chirping of the songbird as they return to their nests mingling with the chattering of the hawkers and peddlers as they return to the streets below.</description></item><item><title>Notes: I Will Teach You To Be Rich by Ramit Sethi</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-i-will-teach-you-to-be-rich-by-ramit-sethi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-i-will-teach-you-to-be-rich-by-ramit-sethi/</guid><description>Sethi&amp;rsquo;s book, at it&amp;rsquo;s core, is a set of rules and tricks that can be applied by an aware and motivated individual to ensure a life of abundance relative to their current financial standings. Motivated to become rich himself (and hailing from India) at a young age, Sethi learnt from his blunders and noted his successes. He started blogging about his wins which eventually evolved into this book. Needless to say, his advice are well-researched, practical and tested.</description></item><item><title>What Makes You Powerful?</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/what-makes-you-powerful/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/what-makes-you-powerful/</guid><description>Do you want to know what makes one powerful?
It isn&amp;rsquo;t money or weapons or good health. It is the ability to find the weak side of strong things.</description></item><item><title>Notes: The Richest Man in Babylon by George S. Clason</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-richest-man-in-babylon-by-george-s.-clason/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-richest-man-in-babylon-by-george-s.-clason/</guid><description>Notes on &amp;ldquo;The Richest Man in Babylon&amp;rdquo; by George S. Clason.
What is wealth? Wealth is a power. With wealth, many things are possible.
Essential Habits A man&amp;rsquo;s wealth is not in the purse he carries. A fat purse quickly empties if there be no golden stream to refill it.
Fate is unpredictable hence untrustworthy. It makes wanton spenders and misers alike.
Every surplus can earn for you. And every revenue on that can earn for you.</description></item><item><title>Turn Down The Music</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/turn-down-the-music/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/turn-down-the-music/</guid><description>Yes, turn down the music
Throw away the booze and
Tell them the party&amp;rsquo;s over for
she isn&amp;rsquo;t here.
Rip the sky bleed,
crush every skull I find,
burn every fucking flower that blooms coz I want her. Yes, turn down the music
Throw away the booze and
Tell them the party&amp;rsquo;s over for
she isn&amp;rsquo;t here.
Was it so much to ask for your love?
I dreamt too much about us</description></item><item><title>Think, Wait and Fast</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/think-wait-and-fast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/think-wait-and-fast/</guid><description>In the book &amp;ldquo;Siddhartha&amp;rdquo; by Herman Hesse – the protagonist, who is a Samana (a homeless hermit), is enchanted by the beauty of a woman named Kamala. On their first discourse, Kamala asks him what is he capable of doing that he can trade for money, pretty clothes, shoes, sweet perfumes and gifts for her. To which Siddhartha replies,
&amp;ldquo;I can think. I can wait. I can fast.&amp;rdquo;
I think that is a very profound answer and it will do ignorant fools like us much good if we make an attempt to comprehend it.</description></item><item><title>Going Public</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/going-public/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/going-public/</guid><description>Circumstances have forced me to mull over unprecedented actions. However, given the situation of the country and the world in general, I hardly think that is an exceptional decision.
The question stands, should I make my blog public? As rationality dictates, I would like to put forward few thoughts both pro- and anti-, some personal, some acquired.
It is not unknown to you that this is this blog&amp;rsquo;s new home on the Web.</description></item><item><title>My First Guitar</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-first-guitar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-first-guitar/</guid><description>I admit I have become lazy. I have not written about myself for a long time. And I apologize for polluting this space with movie and book thoughts. A lot of things have been happening (or should I say, the lack thereof?). But surely, the coolest things to happen is my guitar. Yes, ladies and gentlemen! My first guitar.
At this point, I am not clear whether the pandemic screwed me or I screwed myself.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts: UNIX - History and Memoir (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-unix-history-and-memoir-book/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-unix-history-and-memoir-book/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s always good to know about the things you love the most. It somehow makes you love them even more. I am glad non-living things are not stupidly self-conscious and self-doubting like us and I can understand them more deeply than I can understand other humans.
Some mind(ful|less) blabberings With that said, I enjoyed this book. In Brian&amp;rsquo;s succint prose, he recollects the history of the mother of all operating systems: UNIX.</description></item><item><title>Dual Boot</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/dual-boot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/dual-boot/</guid><description>I experienced something profound and I want to share.
my experience with dual booting For three years, I have borne the pain of Windows. I hate it for being a black box. I love it for being a convenience. But I knew I wanted to get out. I was fearful. I have only one laptop and I have heard (oh lord, this word &amp;ldquo;heard&amp;rdquo;) very bad stories of entire hard disks getting purged.</description></item><item><title>Notes: Design for Hackers by David Kadavy</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-design-for-hackers-by-david-kadavy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-design-for-hackers-by-david-kadavy/</guid><description>Why Design? Your biggest asset - &amp;ldquo;Learn whatever you want to achieve your vision&amp;rdquo;. Good designs are timeless. They can awe people of any era. Fundamental soul of a human creation that expresses itself in successive outer layers of the product. Designing of a system comes before building it not after. Affect emotion, build credibility, earn trust. Don&amp;rsquo;t draw ponies. First visual interaction thus heuristic shortcut to judge credibility. Purpose | Medium and Technology | Aesthetics Good design choices are a set of ideas that must mature in the mind.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts: Design for Hackers (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-design-for-hackers-book/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-design-for-hackers-book/</guid><description>Design. An idea which I admit rather shamefully to not have paid any serious attention to (until now).
Design of a system happens before building not after.
This, it seems, is a general attitude towards design by builders and engineers or people who work on the guts or so called backend of a system as was coyly pointed out by the author himself.
Unfortunately, it is true. Design is something I have always thought of as an after thought in my projects at least uptil now.</description></item><item><title>Notes: Habits by James Clear</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-habits-by-james-clear/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-habits-by-james-clear/</guid><description>My Notes Introduction Majority fail in making habits because they try to make changes the wrong way.
It is easy to get obssessed with the result.
Never overestimate the importance of one defining moment and underestimate the value of making better decisions on a daily basis.
Don&amp;rsquo;t focus on the destination. Focus on the path.
Habits Pattern of every habit:
Reminder ( trigger ) Routine ( the action itself ) Reward ( the benefit ) A good reminder makes it easier for you to start your habit by encoding your new behavior in something that you already do, rather than relying on getting motivated.</description></item><item><title>Gemini Protocol</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/gemini-protocol/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/gemini-protocol/</guid><description>Gemini is a minimal application layer request-response protocol that aims to make a Geminispace of information to be accessible to anyone even with slow/intermittent internet connection. Think HTTP 0.9 or a less restraining Gopher.
TLDR If you haven&amp;rsquo;t checked out Gemini yet, you totally should. This is a HTTP proxy to the actual gemini site.
Why Gemini? I really value your time and understand you have better things to do. So, I&amp;rsquo;ll cut down on formalities and introductions and preludes and yada yada.</description></item><item><title>Specialisation</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/specialisation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/specialisation/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-this-about">What is this about?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>So, here&amp;rsquo;s the thing, imagine the following situation:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Living in the Present or the Future</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/living-in-the-present-or-the-future/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/living-in-the-present-or-the-future/</guid><description>A concave disposition I figured.
Living in the now, the present versus living for the future. This is not a mutually exclusive choice. One must possess both qualities and be able to switch back and forth effortlessly between them.
Living for the future is stressful in the present but generally blissful for the future. You might argue that this must be the optimum choice but the conflict is you are preparing for something non existent and moreover, expending your present to do so and effective using what you can only ever experience, the present.</description></item><item><title>Systems and Everything Else</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/systems-and-everything-else/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/systems-and-everything-else/</guid><description>This is probably the best life skill I have come across in a while that I wish to talk about.
What is this post about? Have you struggled to find a bearing in the world? With so much information and activity to process, does it make your mind feel despaired? Have you endeavored (tried?) to find a list of fundamental principles to live by? Everyone has a core belief through which stems (either consciously or unconsciouly) all of their thoughts and actions.</description></item><item><title>Year in Books: 2020</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/bs/yib2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/bs/yib2020/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s Get Started The Rosie Project | Graeme Simsion
My first read this year (2020). I started just after taking the last of my annuals and I remember laughing hard. It&amp;rsquo;s a romcom about a genetic professor suffering from Asperger&amp;rsquo;s trying to find a wife. The Wife Project still gives me giggles. Oh and I remember picking this up after seeing it on Bill Gate&amp;rsquo;s to-read list.
Daemon | Daniel Suarez A dystopian fiction where a computer program takes &amp;ldquo;control&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts: The Selfish Gene (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-selfish-gene-book/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-selfish-gene-book/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My favourite non-fiction read of 2020.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Music Order Arrived</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-music-order-arrived/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-music-order-arrived/</guid><description>A rather crazy self-imposed project which I had the faintest of ideas will become all-devouring and pose countless hurdles for me to dodge. But yeah, did it. Don&amp;rsquo;t blame me for the CT making ethereal noises!
From left to right: Treasure, Stars and Topsoil and Heaven or Las Vegas (all CDs)
Why do I have to buy music? In a nutshell, because I want to. But seriously, why in a world of Spotify and pirated downloadable songs would I have the brilliant idea to buy music?</description></item><item><title>My First Open Source Excursion</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-first-open-source-excursion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-first-open-source-excursion/</guid><description>Granted that I have atleast a dozen projects hanging in midair (figuratively) on my hard disk (literally). And I have a couple of repos on github in near stasis but today I had my first whiff of open source. Open source doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean much without collaboration and today I dabbled in real time. Contributing code to a public repo, getting feedback and watching it getting approved. Oh! I felt rewarded.</description></item><item><title>Stuck by Fandom for the First Time in My Life</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/stuck-by-fandom-for-the-first-time-in-my-life/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/stuck-by-fandom-for-the-first-time-in-my-life/</guid><description>Ethereal, heavenly, celestial, opulent, splendid, otherworldly - these adjectives form the regular staple of people who dare to describe the music of the Cocteau Twins (pronounced: cock-tow twins). Honestly, I think it&amp;rsquo;s an effort in vain. Because this band defies all possibilities of being defined by words. Cage them in artificial genres and you will fail. You can only experience their &amp;ldquo;sacred microcosm&amp;rdquo; yourself as Azam Ali so eloquently puts it.</description></item></channel></rss>