<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'>Basil Labib&lt;/a> | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Basic&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 05:05:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TODO</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/todo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 05:05:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/todo/</guid><description>&lt;aside style="border: 1px gray solid; padding: 1em; margin: 1em;">
 &lt;h4>Table Of Contents&lt;/h4>
 &lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#introduction">Introduction&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-bit-of-history">A bit of history&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-bit-of-analysis">A bit of analysis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-stages-of-the-complaint">The Stages of the Complaint&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#stage-1-desperation">Stage 1: Desperation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#stage-2-arrogance">Stage 2: Arrogance&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#stage-3-distress-and-loss">Stage 3: Distress and Loss&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#stage-4-contemplation">Stage 4: Contemplation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#stage-5-resignation-and-plea">Stage 5: Resignation and Plea&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-answers-to-the-complaint">The Answers to the Complaint&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#an-answer-to-the-arrogance">An Answer to the Arrogance&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#where-is-the-unity-among-muslims-today">Where is the Unity Among Muslims Today?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-muslim-way-is-forgotten">The Muslim way is forgotten&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#where-is-the-truthful-believer">Where is the truthful believer?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#your-downfall-is-your-own-doing">Your downfall is your own doing&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-last-stanza-of-jawab-e-shikwa">The Last Stanza of Jawab-e-Shikwa&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#personal-notes">Personal Notes&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#footnotes">Footnotes&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;/aside>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Disclaimer&lt;/strong>: You will notice that I have used &amp;ldquo;Allah SWT says&amp;rdquo; or similar sentence construction in the following text. This must NOT be interpreted as the Word of God which is final and contained in the Holy Quran. This is a literary license I have exercised to present the two poems which would not have the same effect if I changed their intended person/point of view. Both poems are the work of a human being and should be interpreted as such.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Trip To The Paradise On Earth: Part 2</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-trip-to-the-paradise-on-earth-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 22:44:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-trip-to-the-paradise-on-earth-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This is the second part of my travelogue to Kashmir. You may read the first part &lt;a href="https://basil08.github.io/post/a-trip-to-the-paradise-on-earth-part-1/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-5---a-day-of-many-songs-and-many-silences">Day 5 - A day of many songs and many silences&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/kashmir-2/17.png"
 alt="Route for the intracity tour within Srinagar" width="400px">&lt;figcaption>
 &lt;p>Route for the intracity tour within Srinagar&lt;/p>
 &lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>

&lt;p>I went for my usual walk around 7:30 am. It was still relatively cold, and most of the city was still asleep. It was mutually decided the night before that we would take a break from long trips and explore the city itself. That was the plan.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Trip To The Paradise On Earth: Part 1</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-trip-to-the-paradise-on-earth-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 20:05:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-trip-to-the-paradise-on-earth-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This travelogue and the next one narrates my experiences of spending a week in Kashmir with my family. As always, I have tried to combine my personal ruminations with more useful information if you&amp;rsquo;re a fellow traveller.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Disclaimer: This post might contains expletives.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/kashmir/4.jpg"
 alt="On the trek path to Thajivas Glacier, Sonamarg. October 2024">&lt;figcaption>
 &lt;p>On the trek path to Thajivas Glacier, Sonamarg. October 2024&lt;/p>
 &lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>

&lt;h2 id="day-0-sunday---leaving-delhi">Day 0 (Sunday) - Leaving Delhi&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After a punishing mid-semester, the onslaught of RDV was setting a lighter and more exciting tone for campus peeps. Being a part of RDV for the past three years, one gains the wisdom that it isn’t much of a big deal for final year students if they are not in the organising team. Basically, I didn’t give a fuck about the fact that it was RDV time on campus. My weekend was spent in the library studying. However, I was looking forward to the Qawwali night slated for Sunday evening. I was also looking forward to catching a train just after that which will take me to Jammu and then to the magical land of Kashmir.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>London Diaries! Part 1</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/london-diaries-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 06:39:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/london-diaries-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the second time I’m trying to write this post. It shouldn’t be this hard to write a travelogue, right? RIGHT?! But it is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some part of that blame goes to all the rich and many, many experiences that I have had on this trip. Each of them fought for space in this post, and inadvertently, I had to let go of some. In any case, what follows is my travelogue for my trip to London from 16th August to 27th August 2024 - reproduced to the best of my abilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implementing Kerberos Authentication System from Scratch</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/implementing-kerberos-authentication-system-from-scratch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 06:58:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/implementing-kerberos-authentication-system-from-scratch/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Sometime back, I started exploring network security systems and stumbled across &lt;a href="https://www.cse.iitd.ernet.in/%7Esiy107537/sil765/readings.html">this nice course page&lt;/a>&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup> from my institute. I thought it would be a nice complement to the introductory computer networks course I am taking this semester. I started reading this fascinating &lt;a href="https://web.mit.edu/Kerberos/dialogue.html">short design principles article&lt;/a> on the Kerberos system. It was so encapsulating that I spent an entire afternoon drawing pictures in my notebook. I decided to implement the ideas given in the article from scratch. In other words, I decided to build my own Kerberos authentication system.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Poems for the Lonely Hearts</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/poems-for-the-lonely-hearts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 20:07:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/poems-for-the-lonely-hearts/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have decided to publish whatever little I was able to write through the summer. I assure you this is neither exhaustive nor sufficient but what meager words I could muster through immense writer&amp;rsquo;s block and a certain dilapidated and diseased heart, I have put them in here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re still interested in reading, here is the &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1EL9-iLbhXhVLd4EgZW5vyL_EHvh2hXPX/view?usp=sharing">collection&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The One Where I Was Almost Jailed!</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-one-where-i-was-almost-jailed/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 08:51:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-one-where-i-was-almost-jailed/</guid><description>&lt;p>Reflections on a personal incident that happened a few days back. Due to the nature and peculiarity of the event, I was terrified and confused whether I should publish it or not, hence I have decided to do so.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="what-happened">What Happened&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I was added to a Whatsapp group of current and past IITD graduates with the title “General Elections 2024” couple of days before June 4 (the day when the 2024 Lok Sabha Elections results were announced). The purpose of the group was to discuss matters of political and national importance including but not limited to policy efficacy, government criticism, and so on. I knew some people in the group who were my seniors but not everyone. The group gradually grew to a strength of around 100 people.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Distillation of "A Circuit for Indirect Object Identification in GPT-2"</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/distillation-of-a-circuit-for-indirect-object-identification-in-gpt-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 21:23:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/distillation-of-a-circuit-for-indirect-object-identification-in-gpt-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a &lt;a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/tag/distillation-and-pedagogy">distillation&lt;/a> of the paper “Interpretability in the Wild: A Circuit for Indirect Object Identification in GPT-2 Small” by Wang. et. al. &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00593">Paper&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As LLMs continue to prove themselves capable as a general problem solver, they are increasingly being deployed to critical application settings. Thus, it is paramount to understand the algorithms that are implemented by the model in order to reason about the output of a model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mechanistic interpretability seeks to discover these algorithms by looking at the constituents of a model and trying to reverse-engineer the functionality of each component based on the observed behaviour of the model.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A personal take on Gan’s "The positive functions of poverty"</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-personal-take-on-gans-the-positive-functions-of-poverty/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 22:28:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-personal-take-on-gans-the-positive-functions-of-poverty/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span style="display: inline-block; font-size: 30px; font-weight: 600;">Sometime back, &lt;/span> a friend shared a paper with me which had an interesting title &lt;a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/2776496">“The positive functions of poverty”&lt;/a> by Herbert J Gans, a German-born American sociologist. I got the time to read it yesterday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Broadly speaking, this paper takes a functional approach of justifying that poverty exists because it serves certain functions in a society and to eliminate poverty would prove disastrous to the society as a whole unless other functionally equivalent processes are created to fill in the gaps.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Every IIT Boy Needs To Know: Building Emotional Intelligence</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/what-every-iit-boy-needs-to-know-building-emotional-intelligence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 07:45:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/what-every-iit-boy-needs-to-know-building-emotional-intelligence/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Open fire!&lt;br>
On my burning heart&lt;br>
I&amp;rsquo;ve never been lucky in love&lt;br>
My defences are down &lt;br>
A kiss or a frown&lt;br>
I can&amp;rsquo;t survive on my own&lt;br>
~&lt;em>Send Me An Angel, Real Life&lt;/em>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Disclaimer: I am not a misogynist or a misandrist. All arguments presented in this article are either based on personal experiences or communicated by someone else.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prologue">Prologue&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="display: inline-block; font-size: 30px; font-weight: 600;">This boy was &lt;/span> friends with a girl and spent time together - doing assignments, that kind of thing. Then he went on to narrate this peculiar incident one evening when he texted her to meet up for a chat as he was feeling under the weather. She texted back that she couldn’t because she had to study. Later that night, he spotted her along with other boys at a club while scrolling through Instagram.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Do Good Students Get Poor Marks</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/why-do-good-students-get-poor-marks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 23:38:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/why-do-good-students-get-poor-marks/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span style="display: inline-block; font-size: 30px; font-weight: 600;">Sometime back,&lt;/span> in one of the professor-student meetings, I raised the issue of rampant cheating during exams only to be frowned upon by my peers who let out a disinterested sigh of disgust. Surely one would expect students to support the issue of cheating? It turned out that students who perceived cheating to be a problem were in a minority. That is because the number of good students, by definition, is small.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Year in Books: 2023</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/bs/yib2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:49:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/bs/yib2023/</guid><description>&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;details>
 &lt;summary style="
 display: block;
 transition: .3s;
 ">
 &lt;span>
 &lt;strong>On The Road | Jack Kerouac&lt;/strong>
 &lt;/span>
 &lt;/summary>
 &lt;div style="
 display: flex;
 flex-wrap: wrap;
 overflow: auto;
 height: 100%;
 padding: 0 20px;
 line-height: 1.5;
 ">
 &lt;p>Publishing of Jack Kerouac’s “On the Road” is a pivotal moment in the recognition and propagation of the so-called American Beat generation of 1940s. The Beats are difficult to define but loosely refer to the bad body of hobos, bums, and con men who were a product of the Depression of the 30s. Young, promising, and full of dreams but without a penny in pocket. As Jack so eloquently puts it, “All he needed was one wheel on his hand and four wheels on the road”. And that is a lovely definition of what this book is all about. It is rich and rich with experiences and stories that will never make a conversation go boring at dinner time and so full of sadness and melancholy at the same time. Told from the perspective of Jack’s alter ego, Sal Paradise, a wannabe writer from New York who befriends a rapturous Beat of the generation, Dean Moriarty, modelled after his friend, Neal Cassidy, the book is a wild account of what it means to be Beat and lost and still somehow find a way. They escape on daring adventures and hitchhike around the American wilderness from coast to coast, meeting old friends, making new ones, conning people, and making sure to make the most of their limited lives that are going by. Kerouac holds back nothing and there’s everything from whores and sex to drugs, and parties, and arrests and the law and brilliant descriptions of America that would make any lacklustre soul quiver with curiosity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Passing The Baton: Experiences of an Editor</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/passing-the-baton-experiences-of-an-editor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 01:29:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/passing-the-baton-experiences-of-an-editor/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Journalism without a moral position is impossible. Every journalist is a moralist. It’s absolutely unavoidable. A journalist is someone who looks at the world and the way it works, someone who takes a close look at things every day and reports what she sees, someone who represents the world, the event, for others. She cannot do her work without judging what she sees.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>~Marguerite Duras, 1997.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="display: inline-block; font-size: 30px; font-weight: 600;"> After I became &lt;/span> one of the &lt;a href="https://www.bspiitd.com/about">chief editors&lt;/a> at &lt;a href="https://www.bspiitd.com/">BSP&lt;/a> a year ago, I wrote a private blogpost on my impression of it. The idea was to write another post at the end of the tenure and see what changed after serving it for another year to the best of my abilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Wild Madness of Shaheen Bagh</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-wild-madness-of-shaheen-bagh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 20:40:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-wild-madness-of-shaheen-bagh/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>The following is a personal account of taking a stroll through the markets of Shaheen Bagh on the fifth day of the month of Ramadan with a friend. We went looking for new shoes just after breaking our fast.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>After observing the duality of poverty and granduer exist so harmoniously at the same place, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but note my emotions. Here, I have attempted to reproduce them to the best of my abilities.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stories from the Underground: Part 2</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/stories-from-the-underground-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 20:50:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/stories-from-the-underground-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>As promised, this is part 2 of &lt;a href="https://basil08.github.io/post/stories-from-the-underground-part-1/">Stories from the Underground&lt;/a>, my travelogue on the GCP workshop at Oxford and beyond.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Disclaimer: This post might contains expletives.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="day-3-21st-december">Day 3 (21st December)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I woke up and stretched like a cat on my double bed. Having a room for two all for myself was a welcome change from long hours of sitting and waiting around at airports. I glanced at my clock, 6ish. &lt;em>Perfect&lt;/em>, I thought. Wrapped up some BSP work, made one of those instant hot chocolate thingie and went for my walk — a considerably longer one because the workshop was over and we were scheduled to depart for Oxford at 10. Video called my folks. I forced myself to take unchartered paths through the woods. It was fascinating to observe a biome so biologically different from one back in the tropics – mosses and lichens were aplenty and so were ferns and temperate-ish flora. The wetness had turned the dirt into mud and my shoes were making squishy noises all along the way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>In the Name of: IIT Delhi and the Age of Unenlightenment</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/in-the-name-of-iit-delhi-and-the-age-of-unenlightenment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 05:05:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/in-the-name-of-iit-delhi-and-the-age-of-unenlightenment/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It was a bright cold day in April, and the clocks were striking thirteen.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>~George Orwell, &lt;em>1984&lt;/em>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="display: inline-block; font-size: 30px; font-weight: 600;"> Global &lt;/span> news channels are keenly monitoring, with much bated breath, the development in the Indian subcontinent and the rise of fascist right-wing Hindutva in the country; the germ of discord and intolerance that were sown with the demolition of the Babri Masjid back in 1992. Rarely has the prime minister of any country made such a dramatic show of their support towards one particular religion. It is evident that the Modi government has piggybanked on the identity-based politics for its third run at the general elections later this year.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stories from the Underground: Part 1</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/stories-from-the-underground-part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 09:50:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/stories-from-the-underground-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Disclaimer: This post might contain expletives.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="prologue">Prologue&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I am waiting at the airport bound to New Delhi right now on NYE. It&amp;rsquo;s been around 10 days since I came back from my first international trip and subsequently go on to represent my institute at Inter IIT Cultural Meet at IIT Kharagpur. I have classes from 8 am tomorrow morning. When did my life got so fast?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>What is this life if, full of care,&lt;br>
We have no time to stand and stare. &lt;br>
~Leisure, William Henry Davies&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hacking Wordle Blitz</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/hacking-wordle-blitz/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 04:36:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/hacking-wordle-blitz/</guid><description>&lt;p>Apologies for not blogging in &lt;em>like forever&lt;/em>. Funny things have been happening in my life lately, perhaps the most funny is the concentration of all trips and &amp;ldquo;vacations&amp;rdquo; in my end-semester holidays. You might call that lucky but I quickly learnt that vacations are supposed to be evenly distributed, atleast from the actually-destressing-and-not-getting-tired-as-hell-from-travelling-and-not-being-able-to-catch-a-breath perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During my entire end-sem holidays, my itinerary allowed me 5 days of staying at home. &lt;em>Just 5&lt;/em>. Before you hasten to the conclusion that 5 days is a lot of time to chill and relax, you must understand that there are relatives and friends to meet to maintain &amp;ldquo;diplomatic relations&amp;rdquo;. There goes my chill and relax.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Are we not safe on campus anymore?</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/are-we-not-safe-on-campus-anymore/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 11:24:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/are-we-not-safe-on-campus-anymore/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="a-commentary-on-the-systems-that-safeguard-us">&lt;em>A commentary on the systems that safeguard us&lt;/em>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A 21 year-old female student was &lt;a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/varanasi/iit-bhu-girl-alleges-molestation-on-campus-massive-protests-break-out/articleshow/104925615.cms">molested&lt;/a> on IIT-BHU campus on Thursday morning. Around 2000 students boycotted academic activities and staged a protest demanding arrest of the perpetrators, enhanced security on campus, and resignation of the institute’s director. As per preliminary report, authorities have taken action and increased security on campus.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="crime-against-women-in-a-society">Crime against women in a society&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Crime in society is seen as an indicator of the general conscience and aspiration of the people. There is an established negative correlation between the prosperity and welfare of a society and crime rates in that society. Although it is not possible to reduce crime rates to zero, the kind of crimes committed gives us a window into the value system of the inhabitants. Women crime is one of the lowest and most demeaning forms of atrocities that a society has to face, perhaps only above war crimes and totalitarian compromise of human rights. When one woman’s safety is compromised, fingers are not only raised on the perpetrator but on the society as a whole. And to imagine the crime committed inside an educational institution often touted as an “Institute of Eminence” is not just a compromise of human rights but an attack on our fundamental values.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What If Zeus Was Right?</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/what-if-zeus-was-right/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 21:06:11 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/what-if-zeus-was-right/</guid><description>&lt;p>The myth of &lt;a href="https://www.britannica.com/topic/Prometheus-Greek-god">Prometheus&lt;/a> is a famous story that talks about the titular demigod who stole fire from Zeus and gave it as a gift to humans. Zeus got pissed and as a punishment, chained him and directed an eagle to eat his liver every day which would grow back the next day &lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>. But what is the point of this story? What should we learn from it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am in my junior year at a premier engineering school and am supposed to make a few critical life decisions by the end of this year. Although, it might not strike as obvious but as I think about what I want to do post university, I increasingly find myself in the shoes of my dear Prometheus.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Common Fallacies in Human Reasoning</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/common-fallacies-in-human-reasoning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 10:23:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/common-fallacies-in-human-reasoning/</guid><description>&lt;p>The human mind is a wonderful example of emergent behaviour. A certain number of neurons fire together in coordination to give rise to conscious optimisers that are able to take independent decisions. And yet, the human mind is a morally and rationally flawed apparatus. One constantly encounters situations in day-to-day life when they are faced with a moral crisis - a dead-end in the decision making process if one is assumed to be guided by a set of principles.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Office: Learnings from the American sitcom</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-office-learnings-from-the-american-sitcom/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 01:56:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-office-learnings-from-the-american-sitcom/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="i-wish-there-was-a-way-to-know-youre-in-the-good-old-days-before-youve-actually-left-them">&amp;ldquo;I wish there was a way to know you&amp;rsquo;re in the good old days before you&amp;rsquo;ve actually left them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h3>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>— Andy Bernard, S9E25 (&lt;em>Finale&lt;/em>)&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I recently finished watching &lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0386676/">The Office&lt;/a>, often lauded as one of the most successful of American sitcoms. Running over 9 seasons&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>, it chronicles the tale of a small American paper company and its employees in the form of a mockumentary - a scripted show shot as a documentary. The cut shots of characters clarifying or putting down their internal thoughts imbues the show with freshness and excitement. Of course, I loved the show (what’s there not to like?); the characters and their stories and how everything falls into place eventually. However, this post is about analysing the Office from a pragmatic psychological viewpoint. I intend to present what I learnt from the Office.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Textile@IITD: Through the eyes of a UG junior student</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/textile@iitd-through-the-eyes-of-a-ug-junior-student/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 20:38:11 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/textile@iitd-through-the-eyes-of-a-ug-junior-student/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I have spent a year in the Textile and Fibre Engineering department of IIT Delhi pursuing a Bachelor of Technology and a minor from the Computer Science department. My designation qualifies me to write this highly opinionated post which is a collection of my experiences and my interpretations for some of them. The value comes from the fact that I make an unbiased review of the department with no filters. This document can serve as a guide for aspiring Textile students at IIT Delhi, current students to guide them in their education, and even professors, administration, and educationists to guide their pedagogical approach.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Murky Mempool: Making sense of {M|B}EV</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-murky-mempool-making-sense-of-mbev/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 23:30:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-murky-mempool-making-sense-of-mbev/</guid><description>&lt;p>It is human tendency to become unconditionally enchanted by something popular regardless of its intrinsic value. Known by many names like &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_effect">network effect&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Herd_mentality">herd mentality&lt;/a>, etc., this psychological effect has a diabolic effect on information dissemination. This is especially true when there is high variance in the educational distribution of the population. Take the &lt;a href="https://phys.org/news/2023-07-korean-team-room-temperature-ambient-pressure-superconductor.html">room temperature semi-conductor craze&lt;/a> for example. Or the plethora of medical news during the 2020 pandemic. Or the invention of the web. You get the point. It&amp;rsquo;s everywhere.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Updates to the blog</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/updates-to-the-blog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 11:22:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/updates-to-the-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p>It has been &lt;a href="https://basil08.github.io/post/migrating-from-jekyll-to-hugo/">quite sometime&lt;/a> since I turned my attention to this blog. Not in terms of content but in terms of features and upgrades. It has served its purpose well, that is, helping a lazy blogger like me keep up with his habit :P. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t intruding too much in terms of maintainence, silently complementing my content, and giving me the peace of mind to blog while keeping it aesthetic for you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>One More Light: Why Can't We Normalise Failing?</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/one-more-light-why-cant-we-normalise-failing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 18:52:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/one-more-light-why-cant-we-normalise-failing/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a student, I want to put my head in a pillow and scream my heart out. As a writer, I am doomed to write words that not many will read and even fewer will understand. As a journalist, I am required to piece together what happened and inform the community of the cold chain of events of last night. But I choose to write this article as a human being, one who is confused and terrified and angry.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Purpose, Passion, and Politics: The Craft of Writing</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/purpose-passion-and-politics-the-craft-of-writing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 10:32:06 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/purpose-passion-and-politics-the-craft-of-writing/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span style="display: inline-block; font-size: 30px; font-weight: 600;"> The &lt;/span> other day, I overheard a conversation between two professors when one cheekily quipped that he had set the next exam paper using &lt;a href="https://chat.openai.com">ChatGPT&lt;/a>. Obviously shocked, the other professor asked, &amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo; Our gallant hero coolly replied, &amp;ldquo;Well, tit for tat.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It seems that with an increase in the number of generative text services, there has been a proportional decrease in the creativity and imagination of people. And I fear that the problem will only aggravate overtime. GPTs will continue to narrow down the gap between expertise and acquired affluence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Bonding Curves Are Crucial to DeFi Protocols</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/how-bonding-curves-are-crucial-to-defi-protocols/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 14:26:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/how-bonding-curves-are-crucial-to-defi-protocols/</guid><description>&lt;div style="text-align: center">
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/bc/0.jpg"
 alt="Source: Google images" height="200px">&lt;figcaption>
 &lt;p>Source: Google images&lt;/p>
 &lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>

&lt;/div>
&lt;p>After the initial excitement, the current state of DeFi rests with the spawning of a number of speculation and lending markets (such as &lt;a href="https://compound.finance">Compound&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://aave.com">AAVE&lt;/a>), complementing their traditional counterparts. For a comprehensive bird-eye view of the history of DeFi, I strongly recommend &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@njess/defi-101-some-basic-primitives-where-they-came-from-and-why-it-matters-35f8c0cf8557">this post&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/njess">@njess&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speculation markets work by providing a platform for traders to bet on the value of any digital asset over time. DeFi is experimenting with devising financial instruments like futures and options for digital assets as evident by a number of perpetual futures protocols like &lt;a href="https://perp.com">Perpetual&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://dydx.exchange">dYdX&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://mycelium.xyz">Mycelium&lt;/a>, etc.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spirited Away: Of Monsters and Men</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/spirited-away-of-monsters-and-men/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:01:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/spirited-away-of-monsters-and-men/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="im-not-a-storyteller-im-a-man-who-draws-pictures">“I’m not a storyteller. I’m a man who draws pictures”.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>~Hayao Miyazaki&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Studio Ghibli’s most acclaimed production &lt;strong>Spirited Away&lt;/strong> is shy of a few days to its twenty-second anniversary and is often regarded as the Best Animation Film ever made. This 125-minute anime, directed by Hayao Miyazaki&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>, follows a 10-year old girl, Chihiro, as she adventures in a magical land of witches, demons, and a slew of other creatures and masterfully combines storytelling with strong elements of magical realism. Let us dive deep and understand why Spirited Away or &lt;em>Sen to Chihiro no Kamikakushi&lt;/em> — translated as &amp;ldquo;Sen and Chihiro&amp;rsquo;s Spiriting Away&amp;rdquo;, is such a big deal.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Escapade Into Uttarakhand: A travelogue</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/escapade-into-uttarakhand-a-travelogue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 13:12:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/escapade-into-uttarakhand-a-travelogue/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This travelogue was created based on my journal entries on a daily(ish) basis. I volunteered as a teacher at a remote village in Uttarakhand and helped high school kids prepare for competitive exams (JEE/NEET) for two weeks. This travelogue is presented almost in its entirety with few redacts that I deemed too personal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="day-1-3031-may">Day 1 (30/31 May)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I got onto an almost full Traveller van in front of Satpura&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup> amidst torrential rain and found myself greeted with unknown (and somewhat hostile) faces. I got into a corner and crumpled myself somehow into that little space. And we rolled around 7:30pm. After sometime I realised, to my horror, that I wanted to puke. It was then that it dawned on me that perhaps I&amp;rsquo;m also one of those people who cannot stand travelling in cars although I was surprised because it had never happened before (also maybe because I have never been on a trip like this). Anyhow, because of a sheer stroke of good luck, someone shifted and I got a window seat and I got better because of the cool Delhi air.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reading Pygmalion: Shaw's criticism of the English language and society</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/reading-pygmalion-shaws-criticism-of-the-english-language-and-society/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 16:45:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/reading-pygmalion-shaws-criticism-of-the-english-language-and-society/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span style="display: inline-block; font-size: 30px; font-weight: 600;"> There &lt;/span> are two central questions at the heart of &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Pygmalion&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> - the more obvious, is the question of identity and how easy or difficult it is to render a different identity to a person and the second, more subtle question is of the very plausibility of the metrics used for class distinction - namely speech in this case. In fact, phonetics would undoubtedly have been a close affair with the author himself, a Dublin-based clerk with his Irish accent wishing to make his career as a writer in England. Classified as a &amp;ldquo;romance comedy&amp;rdquo;, &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Pygmalion&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> is a scatching satire on class distinctions in nineteenth-century England. It is, also, a tantalizing reworking of the ancient Ovidian myth in a modern feminist light. And, a cheeky commentary on the English language itself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Case for Politics: Carpets, Catharsis, and other Conundrums</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-case-for-politics-carpets-catharsis-and-other-conundrums/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:09:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-case-for-politics-carpets-catharsis-and-other-conundrums/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>It’s mid-april, that merry time of the year when the campus is released from the noose of tension and treachery. The student elections have just concluded and people are turning back to studying and turning their backs from speculating, amidst scalding Delhi heat. IIT Delhi has five boards - BSW, BRCA, BSP, BSA, and BHM under the aegis of SAC and a different council called CAIC. All these boards have various posts (the description of which can be found by the reader via an internet search) for which students are elected by various electorals.&lt;/em> [3]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Watchlog</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/watchlog/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 21:26:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/watchlog/</guid><description>&lt;p>This page contains a list of movies/series that I have watched or am watching. I tried doing this before but couldn&amp;rsquo;t maintain and went into an entire &amp;ldquo;phase&amp;rdquo; but anyways, here we go again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I have moved on to Letterboxd for my movie reviews. Please check me out &lt;a href="https://letterboxd.com/itbwtsh/">here&lt;/a>! &lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="2025">2025&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;details>
 &lt;summary style="
 display: block;
 transition: .3s;
 ">
 &lt;span>
 Nosferatu | Robert Eggers | 2024
 &lt;/span>
 &lt;/summary>
 &lt;div style="
 display: flex;
 flex-wrap: wrap;
 overflow: auto;
 height: 100%;
 padding: 0 20px;
 line-height: 1.5;
 ">
 
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/details>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;details>
 &lt;summary style="
 display: block;
 transition: .3s;
 ">
 &lt;span>
 Submarine | Richard Ayoade | 2010
 &lt;/span>
 &lt;/summary>
 &lt;div style="
 display: flex;
 flex-wrap: wrap;
 overflow: auto;
 height: 100%;
 padding: 0 20px;
 line-height: 1.5;
 ">
 
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/details>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;details>
 &lt;summary style="
 display: block;
 transition: .3s;
 ">
 &lt;span>
 The Elephant Man | David Lynch | 1980
 &lt;/span>
 &lt;/summary>
 &lt;div style="
 display: flex;
 flex-wrap: wrap;
 overflow: auto;
 height: 100%;
 padding: 0 20px;
 line-height: 1.5;
 ">
 &lt;p>Since I was already conditioned into the &lt;em>Lynchian&lt;/em> aesthetics via Mulholland Drive and Blue Velvet (which IMO distinctly define Lynch&amp;rsquo;s movies), watching &lt;em>The Elephant Man&lt;/em> was a welcome change. It was nothing like other Lynchian horrors (treats?) - it retains all surrealistic horrific setting and yet at its core, it&amp;rsquo;s a tale of humanity and I think that just increases my respect for Lynch manifold.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>German Expressionism and its influence on Robert Weine</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/german-expressionism-and-its-influence-on-robert-weine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 18:37:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/german-expressionism-and-its-influence-on-robert-weine/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Das Kabinett der Dr. Caligari&lt;/em> (The Cabinet of Dr. Caligari) is a 1920 German thriller drama directed by Robert Weine and starring Werner Strauss as the eponymous character and Conrad Veidt as Cesare. Caligari is seen as the de facto standard of a peculiar period in German cinema christened German Expressionism. This new direction in German cinema was mostly an expression of a greater intellectual cum social movement called Expressionism - a cry against Impressionism and Naturalism but I’m getting ahead of myself. This post aims to investigate (to a considerable degree) the reasons for the emergence of Expressionism, its influence on German cinema with an emphasis on Caligari, and its legacy. In short, to figure out the big deal about it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Playing God: Making sense of CRISPR</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/playing-god-making-sense-of-crispr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 16:29:20 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/playing-god-making-sense-of-crispr/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Imagine standing on a long corridor with closed doors that stretches to infinity on both ends. One keeps walking along and knocking on each door, maybe trying to pick the lock, peeping through the keyhole, or even trying to break in. But the process is tiresome and hopeless. And yet once in a while, someone manages to open a door and view a world they have never imagined. The story of scientific innovation is roughly similar to the story of the endless corridor.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prometheus Unleashed: Making sense of information hazards</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/prometheus-unleashed-making-sense-of-information-hazards/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 11:18:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/prometheus-unleashed-making-sense-of-information-hazards/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>As part of my research into global existential risks, I came across the conundrum of information hazard which simply refers to the potential misuse of scientific or technological information by bad actors that might turn into a global risk for everyone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This phenomenon is most aggravated in the field of biotechnological research where misuse of increasingly openly available genomic data or cheaper protein synthesis techniques can easily be used to develop and mass-produce humanity-threatening super-pathogens (“super” referring to immunity against all known forms of human cure). This is a particularly interesting conundrum as the fine line between openness and secrecy governs the difference between better scientific research and global catastrophe.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modern Times: Where are we headed?</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/modern-times-where-are-we-headed/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 13:56:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/modern-times-where-are-we-headed/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/modern-times-comic/0.png">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/modern-times-comic/1.png">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/modern-times-comic/2.png">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/modern-times-comic/3.png">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/modern-times-comic/4.png">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/modern-times-comic/5.png">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/modern-times-comic/6.png">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/modern-times-comic/7.png">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/modern-times-comic/8.png">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/modern-times-comic/9.png">
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="sidenotes">sidenotes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Posting some of my silly drawings here because &lt;a href="https://aniruddhadeb.com">a good friend&lt;/a> said I should so oh well! It&amp;rsquo;s painful to watch his blog go unnourished like this but I&amp;rsquo;m constrained by my physical limitations of being a human and being unable to transcend and/or manipulate the fourth dimension of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enjoy the comic until next time!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Year in Books: 2022</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/bs/yib2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:49:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/bs/yib2022/</guid><description>&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;details>
 &lt;summary style="
 display: block;
 transition: .3s;
 ">
 &lt;span>
 &lt;strong>Fierce People | Dirk Wittenhorn&lt;/strong>
 &lt;/span>
 &lt;/summary>
 &lt;div style="
 display: flex;
 flex-wrap: wrap;
 overflow: auto;
 height: 100%;
 padding: 0 20px;
 line-height: 1.5;
 ">
 &lt;p>A good first read of the year. A thriller, romance, and coming-of-age novel all wrapped in one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m glad I read the book before I&amp;rsquo;m going to watch the movie. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t put it down once I started. I wrote an in-depth &lt;a href="https://basil08.github.io/post/fierce-people/">post&lt;/a> so I won&amp;rsquo;t bore you here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BUIDL: Hitching a ride on the web3 wagon</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/buidl-hitching-a-ride-on-the-web3-wagon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 09:28:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/buidl-hitching-a-ride-on-the-web3-wagon/</guid><description>&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/ethindia22/18.jpeg"
 alt="ETHIndia 2022&amp;rsquo; @Whitefield, BLR" width="400px">&lt;figcaption>
 &lt;p>ETHIndia 2022&amp;rsquo; @Whitefield, BLR&lt;/p>
 &lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>


&lt;div style="display: flex;">
 &lt;div class="white" style="padding: 5px; border-radius: 4px; margin: 0.2em;">
 &lt;blockquote>
 &lt;strong>Infinite Garden&lt;/strong>: a diverse ecosystem of individuals and organizations that build and grow alongside ethereum.
 &lt;/blockquote>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The Ethereum ecosystem, particularly the scaling L2 solutions are witnessing dramatic progress in terms of breakthroughs and innovation. The &lt;code>Infinite Garden&lt;/code> is the phrase used to refer to the truly decentralized techno-haven where interaction between online entities are transparent and uncensored. Free from censorship, state control, fraud, and malicious agents, powered by the ecosystem of applications built on blockchains - in short, an information utopia. Personally, the idea seems enticing and inviting. But transitioning from web2 to web3 is a long way and the vision I outlined, although the shared vision of the people on the frontier of this revolution, is still a long, long way into the future.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>À bout de souffle: The politics of Godard's debut feature</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/%C3%A0-bout-de-souffle-the-politics-of-godards-debut-feature/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 10:38:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/%C3%A0-bout-de-souffle-the-politics-of-godards-debut-feature/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="display: inline-block; font-size: 30px; font-weight: 600;">Art&lt;/span>, by its very nature, challenges the status quo. It has the power, and I would argue, responsibility, to sway people to stand up against unjust and authoritarian regimes. It serves as the voice of the marginalised and the voiceless. The twentieth century philosopher Theodore Adorno famously said,&lt;/p>

&lt;div style="display: flex;">
 &lt;div class="white" style="padding: 5px; border-radius: 4px; margin: 0.2em;">
 &lt;blockquote>
 &lt;p>&amp;ldquo;All art is an uncommitted crime&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~Theodore Adorno&lt;/p>

 &lt;/blockquote>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The acclaimed Spanish painter, Pablo Picasso painted &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qJLH7JAsBHA">The Guernica&lt;/a> as an expression of protest against war. Its explicit and ghastly imagery has been used in anti-war protests ever since. Or, take contemporary artist Banksy&amp;rsquo;s protest poster for &lt;em>Black Lives Matter&lt;/em> which shows an American flag catching a fire by a vigil candle beside a framed photograph of an unknown person.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I am 20: Remembering India's youth</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/i-am-20-remembering-indias-youth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 14:30:10 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/i-am-20-remembering-indias-youth/</guid><description>&lt;p>In 1967, the Films Division of India produced a short documentary under director S.N.S. Sastry. The simple, 18-minute documentary titled &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fA8h74ZW8Ok">&amp;ldquo;I am 20&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> depicts the lives of the Indian youths, their hopes, aspirations, and apprehensions. It captures the true spirit of the Indian mindset of the 60s, the multitude of visions and dreams and ambitions. For an Indian youth watching this documentary, it is very difficult not to be moved by it. It is this timeless quality engrained in this film that has garnered it the iconic status that it truly deserves.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Pillowman: Artistry in a totalitarian regime</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-pillowman-artistry-in-a-totalitarian-regime/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 21:45:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-pillowman-artistry-in-a-totalitarian-regime/</guid><description>&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/pillowman/0.jpg"
 alt="The Pillowman, Martin McDonagh, 2003" width="400px">&lt;figcaption>
 &lt;p>The Pillowman, Martin McDonagh, 2003&lt;/p>
 &lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>

&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Martin McDonagh&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Pillowman&amp;rdquo; is an enquiry into the freedom of an artist in an oppressive totalitarian regime. Katurian, a writer, is interrogated by two brute and somewhat foppish policemen in custody about his role in the recent chain of children murders who were killed in ways elucidated by Katurian in his works. But what eventually unravels is Katurian&amp;rsquo;s own dark past, his dysfunctional family, and the character of his retarded brother whom he loves so much. Martin&amp;rsquo;s comment on the state of freedom of artistic expression is central piece as he sketches the life of a distressed writer whose sole outlet of chaos and insanity is through his pen, and who is prosecuted by the state for his artistic creativity. There are multiple thorny questions such as: Where should we draw the line for artistic expression and capital crime? How even to describe artistic expression? Is it okay for songwriters to openly use profanity or filmmakers to increasingly include explicit scenes of violence, brutality, and sexuality? What is reasonable and what isn&amp;rsquo;t?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Quant Frenzy: A Crude Forecast</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-quant-frenzy-a-crude-forecast/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 17:45:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-quant-frenzy-a-crude-forecast/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-motivated-this-post">What motivated this post?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Recently, I finished reading &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43889703-the-man-who-solved-the-market">Gregory Zuckerman&amp;rsquo;s brilliantly researched book&lt;/a> on the pioneering ultra-secretive quantitative investment firm &lt;a href="https://www.renfund.com/Home.action?index=true">Renaissance Technologies&lt;/a> and its founder and mathematics prodigy, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jim_Simons_(mathematician)">Jim Simons&lt;/a>. It is an exhaustive and impressive account of a newer, data-driven, non-conservative approach to trading financial instruments. RenTec&amp;rsquo;s flagship hedge fund, Medallion, has averaged a mind-boggling 71.8% annual return, before fees, from 1994 to 2014. Medallion is considered a glaring example of a pioneering experiment that trounced skeptics and traditional investors who were smug about their intuitive abilities as traders and scoffed at the idea of letting computer programs decide the fate of the markets. Jim Simons has a net worth of 24+ billion USD today (Yes, you read that right).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Minority</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-minority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 09:28:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-minority/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post should have come 20 days before, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t gather the peace of mind to actually sit down and write it. But since 20 days &lt;em>have&lt;/em> elapsed, let&amp;rsquo;s make it a narration of my experience so far at IITD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I appeared for my first university minor exams, a new experience. I met seniors and club representatives and got myself involved in a small development project for Rendezvous, our institute&amp;rsquo;s cultural fest. I arranged for a bicycle from a senior and got it repaired from the shop yesterday. The Omicron variant is out at large, and the management is apprehensive of keeping students on campus. Most of my wingmates and friends have returned home. I just don&amp;rsquo;t feel like going home, that 24-hour journey, all the packing, I hate that. Besides, the Delhi cold is suiting my skin in a way (Although it&amp;rsquo;s too dry than I want it to be). As a result, I&amp;rsquo;m alone in my wing with few other boys, typing away at my laptop, looking out the window, and strumming the guitar I borrowed until mine arrives. No, but really, I like not having to make small talk with people, being disrupted doing something important, putting my thought into behaving.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fierce People: A riveting tale of deceit and drama</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/fierce-people-a-riveting-tale-of-deceit-and-drama/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 19:19:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/fierce-people-a-riveting-tale-of-deceit-and-drama/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Although, I have encountered and internalized many teenaged male protagonists, from the meek Charlie from POBAW, to the valiant Tariq, to the quirky Holden Caulfield, &lt;em>Finn Earl&lt;/em>, my latest discovery, refuses to be filed amongst them. He is the sixteen-year old protagonist of Dirk Wittenhorn&amp;rsquo;s 2002 novel &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Fierce People&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> which is a coming-of-age story, a thriller, and a romance all wrapped in one. Although, there is &lt;em>so&lt;/em> much going on between these pages and I have met so many memorable characters, it is invariably Finn&amp;rsquo;s transformation that is the central piece that effuses meaning to it all.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Year in Books: 2021</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/bs/yib2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 22:18:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/bs/yib2021/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The list of books I have read in 2021 along with thoughts and views on some of them. Enjoy!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Zero to One | Peter Thiel&lt;/strong> &lt;br>
Non-fiction, Startup, Essential, Vision, Principles&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Rosemary&amp;rsquo;s baby | Ira Levine&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Fiction, Fantasy, Witchcraft, Classic&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vivekananda&amp;rsquo;s Biography | Swami Nikhelananda&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Non-fiction, Biography, Monk, Vedanta, Philosophy, Inspiration&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Three Body Problem | Cixin Liu&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Fiction, Hard SF (science fiction), Contact, Classic&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Transform your Habits | James Clear&lt;/strong> &lt;br>
Non-fiction, Psychology, Self-help, Habits, Short&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reaching IIT Delhi</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/univ/reaching-iitd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 19:19:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/univ/reaching-iitd/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This post is a penned down expression of my personal experience. It is considerably less &amp;ldquo;lean&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;unpolished&amp;rdquo;. That is by choice, as I wanted to capture the spontaneity of the moments. What you&amp;rsquo;re about to read is arguably personal so be considerate! Have fun!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="dec-21-2021-817">Dec 21, 2021 8:17&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I look out the scratched glass window out at the receding landscape. it&amp;rsquo;s buildings and bridges. The sun is above my head, looking directly down at me, kissing me gently. And the railway tracks meander and merge like serpents and timelines, streaks of solid steel gleaming in the sun, hypnotizing the wry traveler like the sirens of Messina.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Prince and the Monk: A fictive conversation</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-prince-and-the-monk-a-fictive-conversation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 17:50:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-prince-and-the-monk-a-fictive-conversation/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The following is a short story of an unnamed young prince of an unknown country in an unspecified time. The story involves just one conversation with a monk and how that unravels the personality of the prince and his hazardous life ahead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>To a future me when he feels too broken.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="display: inline-block; font-size: 30px; font-weight: 600;"> O &lt;/span> nce upon a time, a young prince kneeling in the premises of an old monk asked him,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The War to end all wars: The First World War</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-war-to-end-all-wars-the-first-world-war/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 09:50:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-war-to-end-all-wars-the-first-world-war/</guid><description>&lt;p>Micheal Howard&amp;rsquo;s treatment of the &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25858.The_First_World_War">First World War&lt;/a> is a succint description of the horrors, challenges, tactics, politics, and sentiments that paved the way for one of the bloodiest wars the world had ever seen.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="overview-of-the-causes-of-ww1">Overview of the causes of WW1&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Karl von Clausewitz, after the Napoleanic Wars noted that war was a trinity of the government, the activities of the military, and &amp;ldquo;the passions of the people&amp;rdquo;. Howard goes on to unravel in great detail how these came together to become the causes of WW1. Now, to pinpoint any single event as the cause of WW1 is a risky business as is any such ordeal in history.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The First 15 Days</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-first-15-days/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 13:39:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-first-15-days/</guid><description>&lt;p>I wanted to capture my exact thought processes and emotional turbulence during the first 15 days of &amp;ldquo;housewarming&amp;rdquo; (if so you will) at IITD. This is that post.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One line summary for the TLDR peeps: Overwhelming. Hectic. Slightly intimidating academically and abysmally solitary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We had our rightful hostel online meet on December 1st. I&amp;rsquo;m from Udaigiri. A serious meetup where our BSW reps laid down the rules and regulations of the hostel. Things like the disciplinary committee (DisCo), abuses, tolerance, offensive views, and so on. I would, obviously, respect other people and uphold the integity and sanctity of the university. And yet, one never knows when one crosses a line, either consciously or unconsciously, which is something that I must admit I&amp;rsquo;m a bit apprehensive about. It was also slightly uncomfortable &lt;em>being told&lt;/em> to follow rules that should be given for a freshman. I mean, respecting girls, tolerance towards diverse views etc., ain&amp;rsquo;t these basic ideals of a civilized individual? Yet, as I was about to learn, IITD isn&amp;rsquo;t as safe and glorious as I had thought (Will come back to it later).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://basil08.github.io/droplets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 22:00:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/droplets/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="droplets-smile">Droplets &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="why">Why?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Posts serve as well-researched, well-articulated opinions and thoughts. But I wanted something that could capture tiny little fleeting ideas. I needed microblogging. Oh, you&amp;rsquo;d say, &amp;ldquo;What about Twitter, pal?&amp;rdquo; Nah, not really. So, I hacked a little microblogging server. The code is open and on &lt;a href="https://github.com/basil08/vera">GitHub&lt;/a>. The script is hosted on the incredible &lt;a href="https://deta.dev">Deta&lt;/a> platform and the database on Mongo Atlas.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>Whose glory are we basking in?</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/whose-glory-are-we-basking-in/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 18:09:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/whose-glory-are-we-basking-in/</guid><description>&lt;p>Twitter just got a brand new CEO. An Indian-born American and an alumni of IIT Bombay. A noticeable pattern: Microsoft – Satya Nadella, Alphabet – Sundar Pichai, IBM – Arvind Krishna, and now a welcome addition to the league of US tech companies run by Indian-born IIT graduates. This news has been quite a subject of debate and argument among my friends and being an IITian myself, I felt it my responsibility to clear up few misconceptions and put forth some context.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Accidental IITian</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-accidental-iitian/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 18:43:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/univ/the-accidental-iitian/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are events and people beyond our control who affect our lives in deeper ways that we can comprehend. 2020 was such an year for me. A most memorable year. I knew it from the moment our honorable PM announced &lt;em>a&lt;/em> lockdown in March 2020 that my JEE was going to be a &lt;em>much&lt;/em> different ride than how I had envisioned it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some people are unfazed by sitting in front of a screen for hours, listening through a headphone clasped around their skull. I feel suffocated. Pandemic time was memorable as school teachers and coaching tried to make sense of online education, setting standards, and establishing SOPs. They failed of course but anyway, that&amp;rsquo;s not the point. I analysed why my body has such a drastic physical aversion to attending a lecture digitally. Every student has a unique pedagogical approach to learning, by listening, watching, reading, or discussing. I pay attention in class. Perhaps, it&amp;rsquo;s a residue of the &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;be a good boy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> attitude instilled in me by mom and dad. 100% attendance is another one. I reckon I have to begin fighting these habits. I can&amp;rsquo;t focus on a screen because of time lag and the constant jittery noise of microphones. My brain can&amp;rsquo;t perceive the nuances of teaching, like the instructor&amp;rsquo;s body language or tone modulation. A certain class decorum like sitting at a desk and actually taking notes on paper. These things are important to me. Some of them couldn&amp;rsquo;t materialize. Who is to be blamed? No one. I am responsible for fucking up my JEE because &lt;em>it was all my fault&lt;/em> (so does my father say).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A deep dive into JSON Web Tokens (JWTs)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-deep-dive-into-json-web-tokens-jwts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 08:03:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-deep-dive-into-json-web-tokens-jwts/</guid><description>&lt;aside style="border: 1px gray solid; padding: 1em; margin: 1em;">
 &lt;h4>Table Of Contents&lt;/h4>
 &lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#what-is-jwt">What is JWT?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#why-use-jwt">Why use JWT?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#why-understand-it">Why understand it?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#how-do-jwts-work">How do JWTs work?&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#user-authentication-walkthrough">User authentication: Walkthrough&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#structure-of-a-jwt">Structure of a JWT&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-header">The header&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-payload">The payload&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#hash-functions">Hash functions&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#hmac--sha256--hs256">HMAC + SHA256 = HS256&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#rsa--sha256--rs256">RSA + SHA256 = RS256&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#other-algorithms">Other algorithms&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#common-pitfalls-and-mitigation-techniques">Common pitfalls and mitigation techniques&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#unsecured-tokens-via-alg-none">Unsecured tokens via &lt;code>alg: none&lt;/code>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#signature-stripping">Signature stripping&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cross-site-resource-forgery-csrf">&lt;a href="https://owasp.org/www-community/attacks/csrf">Cross Site Resource Forgery (CSRF)&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cross-site-scripting-xss">&lt;a href="https://owasp.org/www-community/attacks/xss/">Cross Site Scripting (XSS)&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#license">License&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;/aside>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-jwt">What is JWT?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A JSON Web Token or a JWT (pronounced &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;jot&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>) is a plaintext, human readable piece of data that enables authentication and trust between two unknown entities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Notes: How to Win at College by Cal Newport</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-how-to-win-at-college-by-cal-newport/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 09:22:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-how-to-win-at-college-by-cal-newport/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;em>Abstract&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>: This is a summary of the main ideas in &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/253197.How_to_Win_at_College">Cal Newport&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;How to Win at College&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I spent quite sometime trying to come up with a comprehensive yet concise format to summarize this book. I ended up either copying the whole book or noting only generic, fuzzy advices both of which are of little use to a freshman. Rather, what follows is a summary of the general ideas overarching the book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts: The Psychology of Money (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-psychology-of-money-book/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 08:58:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-psychology-of-money-book/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Morgan Housel&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;The Psychology of Money&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> is less of a technical book and more of a collection of wisdom and wishful advices. It is N. Taleb&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Bed of Procrustes&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> augmented with real life anecdotes, morsels of history, and a lot of quotations. Although Housel professes a very conservative and frugal approach to managing money, his advice cannot be disputed without a very good counter argument. The cautious models, frameworks, and signposts laid out in the book would prevent an investor from being foolish and that Housel says is too easy to be in the modern financial system.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Web 3.0 and The Metaverse Mania</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/web-3.0-and-the-metaverse-mania/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 19:54:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/web-3.0-and-the-metaverse-mania/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is a shot in Steven Spielberg&amp;rsquo;s 2018 science fiction &lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1677720/">&amp;ldquo;Ready Player One&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> where the protagonist, Wade, sitting in a shack in Columbus puts on a VR headset and is transported to the planet of Incipio where all avatars are born when they enter the OASIS. They can morph into any characters, cartoon, or monster. Customise how they look and sound and smell. Buy virtual assets and fight in hunts on a planet called Doom (Watch the movie if this is lost on you). Although these are mere imagination spewed from the mind of a 80s culture maniac, how would you feel if I tell you this is exactly the place we are headed?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hacktoberfest and open source</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/hacktoberfest-and-open-source/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 06:22:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/hacktoberfest-and-open-source/</guid><description>&lt;aside style="border: 1px gray solid; padding: 1em; margin: 1em;">
 &lt;h4>Table Of Contents&lt;/h4>
 &lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-philosophy-of-open-source">THE PHILOSOPHY OF OPEN SOURCE&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#people-who-write-open-source">PEOPLE WHO WRITE OPEN SOURCE&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-psychology-of-a-hacker">THE PSYCHOLOGY OF A HACKER&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#why-is-open-source-the-future">WHY IS OPEN SOURCE THE FUTURE?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#why-go-open">WHY GO OPEN?&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#personal-experience">PERSONAL EXPERIENCE&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#little-history">LITTLE HISTORY&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#further-reading">FURTHER READING&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bibliography">BIBLIOGRAPHY&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;/aside>
&lt;p>DigitalOcean, a cloud service provider annually hosts &lt;a href="https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com">Hacktoberfest&lt;/a>, a month-long celebration of open source culture where developers from around the globe contribute to open projects. It is in its 8th iteration this year and has become quite an attraction for programmers, young and experienced.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Discord bot: A definitive guide</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/building-a-discord-bot-a-definitive-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 07:56:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/building-a-discord-bot-a-definitive-guide/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this guide, I will be building a Discord bot from scratch using only &lt;a href="https://discord.js.org">discord.js&lt;/a> and a few open public APIs. I&amp;rsquo;ll also explain each step and discuss the reason for preference of a particular way of implementation over others. Unlike other &amp;ldquo;recipes&amp;rdquo; on the web, this will give you insight into the workflow of building software.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This may seem like a long post because it is. I suggest you to follow along in chunks so you don&amp;rsquo;t get overwhelmed. The tutorial is divided into chapters. So, let&amp;rsquo;s get started.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A tour of the realist world of Edward Hopper</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-tour-of-the-realist-world-of-edward-hopper/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 13:31:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-tour-of-the-realist-world-of-edward-hopper/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span style="display: inline-block; font-size: 30px; font-weight: 600;"> American artist &lt;/span> and painter, Edward Hopper, didn&amp;rsquo;t achieve much recognition in his lifetime. Today, critics laud his work as quintessential &amp;ldquo;American&amp;rdquo; in spirit as he developed a distinctive signature style. His personal life was fraught with toil and resentment as he watched his contemporaries rise to fame and fortune. He was a married man who had no children and his wife stood as a pillar of support, augmenting his intellect, emotion and career. He was a shy, quiet, somewhat reclusive artist who was appalled by abstract modernism and its advent in the American art landscape. He was cynical of critics who failed to share his viewpoint that art is an expression of an artist&amp;rsquo;s emotional conscience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A personal interpretation of 'The Matrix'</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-personal-interpretation-of-the-matrix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 08:59:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-personal-interpretation-of-the-matrix/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span style="display: inline-block; font-size: 30px; font-weight: 600;">I first saw &lt;/span> &lt;em>The Matrix&lt;/em> last year and like every person who has watched it since its release in 1999, it left my auditory and visual senses on overload and a gargantuan heap of information for my brain to process. A second viewing few days back, made me observe relationships and philosophies that escaped me in the first attempt. There are good reasons why &lt;em>The Matrix&lt;/em> is discussed by critics even today from as varied perspectives as social, political, scientific, philosophical and of course, technological and has injected such appealing concepts and ideas in the public imagination that they have managed to pass into our vocabulary and lifestyles.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sylvia Plath, The Bell Jar and feminism</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/sylvia-plath-the-bell-jar-and-feminism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 11:27:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/sylvia-plath-the-bell-jar-and-feminism/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span style="display: inline-block; font-size: 30px; font-weight: 600;">"What I hate &lt;/span> &lt;em>is the thought of being under a man&amp;rsquo;s thumb&amp;quot;&lt;/em>, Sylvia fearlessly thundered in her only published novel &amp;ldquo;The Bell Jar&amp;rdquo;. Published in 1963, &lt;em>Jar&lt;/em> is one of the prominent texts on feminism and the vocalisation of a woman&amp;rsquo;s apprehensions, rights and freedom. Sylvia&amp;rsquo;s words, like brazen dagger, are used today in protest marches as well as analysed in literary circles.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/belljar/0.jpg"
 alt="Sylvia Plath">&lt;figcaption>
 &lt;p>Sylvia Plath&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The IIT Dream: Decoding India's lust for engineers</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-iit-dream-decoding-indias-lust-for-engineers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 14:05:39 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-iit-dream-decoding-indias-lust-for-engineers/</guid><description>&lt;p>India suffers from an unusual sort of disease today. Spotted on walls in metropolises and small towns alike, will be colorful posters with portrait sized photos of teenaged students, posing in institute branded t-shirts with big proud smiles on their faces and occasionally V signs made with fingers. Accompanying them will be a number AIR XXXX, decreasing in font size and prominence as the numbers grow larger as if to suggest a decrease in the importance of the student and their aptitude. This is the description of a typical Indian coaching institute advertisement, a booming billion dollar industry, used to lure students and sell them the IIT dream.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>31 Years of 'Heaven or Las Vegas'</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/31-years-of-heaven-or-las-vegas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 10:18:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/31-years-of-heaven-or-las-vegas/</guid><description>&lt;p>Most CT fans agree (and frankly, there ain&amp;rsquo;t many) that Heaven or Las Vegas is their definitive production: ephemeral and sublime, cocky song titles and discernable vocals, sweet sounds and fragments of bitter lyrics, it is a very Twins album in spirit. Garlands (1982), their debut, was too much on the punk and goth style, a desperate searching phase for their identity which was fulfilled by Treasure (1984), a commendable opus in itself. But it is Heaven or Las Vegas or a song therein, that the CT are most remembered for.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>'Please myself': An interpretation 30 years later</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/please-myself-an-interpretation-30-years-later/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 08:02:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/please-myself-an-interpretation-30-years-later/</guid><description>&lt;p>Polly, a common American girl name, quickly rose to fame as the 6th songtrack on Nirvana&amp;rsquo;s second album, Nevermind, one of the best-selling albums of all time, having sold over 30 million copies since its release in 1991.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Polly became a conversation starter, an ice-breaker, a household catalyst for people everywhere to talk about woman abuse. Polly is a protest song, a song born out of the anguish that Kurt felt for the condition and treatment of woman in the society. It has often been dubbed as Nirvana&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;darkest&amp;rdquo; song – which, in my opinion, is a fairly glorified sobriquet because most of Nirvana&amp;rsquo;s songs are dark and ghastly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Academic Dishonesty</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/academic-dishonesty/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 11:50:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/academic-dishonesty/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today is September 5th which is celebrated as Teacher&amp;rsquo;s Day in India on the birth anniversary of Dr. Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan, an eminent educator, teacher and the first Vice President of India. As Indian students reach out to pay respect to their teachers via various gestures such as feet embracing albeit digitally this year, I wish to take this opportunity to speak about a much graver issue in the Indian education scenario today.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Remembering My Teachers</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/remembering-my-teachers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 10:20:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/remembering-my-teachers/</guid><description>&lt;div style="display: flex;">
 &lt;div class="white" style="padding: 5px; border-radius: 4px; margin: 0.2em;">
 &lt;blockquote>
 &amp;ldquo;The right kind of education begins with the educator, who must understand himself and be free from established patterns of thought; for what he is that he imparts. If he has not been rightly educated, what can he teach except the same mechanical knowledge on which he himself has been brought up?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&lt;cite>~J Krishnamurti&lt;/cite>
 &lt;/blockquote>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>NR Narayan Murthy, the founder of Infosys, recounted three incidents in his life that taught him core human values and left an indelible mark on him. The first was when his senior school Chemistry teacher taught him the &lt;em>difference between community and personal property and how to treat each of them&lt;/em>. Second was the &lt;em>quest for global excellence&lt;/em> in whatever one chooses to do by his meticulous and obssessed engineering prof and finally the &lt;em>importance of starting any transaction on a zero base&lt;/em> by his boss at IIM-A. These are incredible life lessons and as I sat pondering how my tryst with teachers have played out, I found myself reaching for my diary. I am privileged to write that I have learned many things from them – both inside the textbook and outside.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Sensuality of Rilke's Love Poems</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-sensuality-of-rilkes-love-poems/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 09:04:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-sensuality-of-rilkes-love-poems/</guid><description>&lt;div style="display: flex;">
 &lt;div class="white" style="padding: 5px; border-radius: 4px; margin: 0.2em;">
 &lt;blockquote>
 I tell you that I have a long way to go before I am – where one begins&amp;hellip;
 &lt;/blockquote>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>These are Rilke&amp;rsquo;s first words that I read. I had no prior acquaintance with either the man or his writings, save for a curious Google search on a Cocteau Twins&amp;rsquo; song called &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lkvmjniEW0E">Rilkean Heart&lt;/a>. And yet, I immediately felt a tug towards these words, gyrating around them, twisting and turning them in my head, trying to make sense of it. Perhaps, just perhaps, Rilke would know the storm that was raging in me?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Love As An Illegitimate Byproduct</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/love-as-an-illegitimate-byproduct/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 10:18:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/love-as-an-illegitimate-byproduct/</guid><description>&lt;p>Evolutionary biology has always fascinated me. I have marveled at the ingenuity of evolutionists drawing up elegant theories, piecing together the most bizarre of observations with a string of sound reasoning. I guess the quality of making logical sense of the alien world we find ourselves in makes evolution appeal to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, I read Jared Diamond&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Why Sex is Fun?&amp;rdquo;, a short book (a series of essays really) about human sexuality and how it differs so radically from every other species we know of. His words and reasoning reminded me of Dawkins&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;The Selfish Gene&amp;rdquo; – particularly nostalgic where the spermatozoa and oocyte structural discrepency and Zahavis&amp;rsquo; principle of handicap signals; however, the prose was much easier to read than Selfish. Evolution is much like astronomy / cosmology in a certain way – both instills humility in a manner no other subject can.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Take Correct Decisions</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/how-to-take-correct-decisions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 10:33:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/how-to-take-correct-decisions/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="prologue">Prologue&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The other day, my sister and I were having this rather enlightening and philosophical conversation on how to navigate life. We&amp;rsquo;re almost adults so it&amp;rsquo;s high time we learn things that schools and parents won&amp;rsquo;t teach us.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-problem">The Problem&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A human life is a game of decision making. It is analogous to a video game with opportunities and options at every turn and the chosen options leading to other opportunities, good or bad, &lt;em>but completely alienating us from the opportunities we have missed.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>To be or not to be: Understanding Hamlet</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/to-be-or-not-to-be-understanding-hamlet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 10:20:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/to-be-or-not-to-be-understanding-hamlet/</guid><description>&lt;p>Volumes have been written on the &amp;ldquo;meaning&amp;rdquo; of Hamlet (the play) by more qualified people than me. I do not seek to compete with them. What follows is my perception of Hamlet, a sketch so if you will, from a modern day perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hamlet is a complex character. I have strived to deduce Hamlet strictly from the source text and not get influenced by writings elsewhere because I feel external analysis somehow shrouds (glorifies or diminishs, whichever) the essence of what Shakespeare intended. I also acknowledge there are passages and portions that are still unclear to me. I take them as deficiencies on my part and the excellence of the play.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Closer Look at 'Inside Job'</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-closer-look-at-inside-job/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 16:56:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-closer-look-at-inside-job/</guid><description>&lt;!-- 


&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/4XVLECplZwd2OrHFkfy6Te"
 width="100%"
 height="380"
 frameborder="0"
 allowtransparency="true"
 allow="encrypted-media">&lt;/iframe>
 -->
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Inside Job&amp;rdquo; is a 2010 documentary written, directed and produced by Charles Ferguson on the 2008 global financial crisis. It won the Oscar in the &amp;ldquo;Best Documentary Feature&amp;rdquo; category in 2011. Notwithstanding, it makes for an enlightening and thrilling watch that every citizen, who cares about where their hard earned money goes, should watch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This documentary is not an easy watch that one can grab on a lazy afternoon comfortable on their couch. It has complex sounding terms and concepts that should keep one on the edge of their seat. As those financial experts makes the layman believe, &amp;ldquo;What we do is far more complicated for you to understand so you better leave us alone as we do it.&amp;rdquo; They are soft-headed people who will make one feel witless and run away with their money. That is exactly what happened in 2008.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My School Journey</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-school-journey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 23:34:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-school-journey/</guid><description>&lt;p>Few days back, I graduated high school. Which means a journey of 14 years came to an end. I have numerous delights, some regrets and plenty of memories to take with me. I have some to share too.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="teachers">Teachers&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>First of all, I want to thank &lt;em>every&lt;/em> teacher who has taught me. From holding my hand to write an &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo; in nursery to open discussions in Physics classes to painful lectures in Literature – I have taken a part of you all. And though, I may become whatever I will, I have irrevocably become the sum of those pieces that you all have gladly given me. I am grateful to all of you, in the truest sense of the word. Moreover, coming from an indigent family, the love and support that some of you have shown me has been something I still can&amp;rsquo;t imagine. I still remember when Mrs. Bannerjee (my 10th English teacher) borrowed a dictionary on her name from the school library for me so that I could prepare for my board exams the following day. I remember Mrs. Ali and Mrs. Khan who waived my school fees for an entire year at a time when my family was going through great turmoil. Frankly, I would had to drop-out otherwise. Mrs. Kalam, who treated me as her own son, extended every possible help she could. I always felt so at home around her given the fact that I don&amp;rsquo;t like people a lot. Mrs. Sinha, who taught me Chemistry from practically the beginning. I still have the pen you gave me after I scored a 100 in boards by your guidance and blessings. And surely many, many others I cannot recall. I am a self-motivated student and all I need is a little encouragement. I am glad I got that and a lot more from all of you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Indian Sexual Taboo</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-indian-sexual-taboo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 15:28:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-indian-sexual-taboo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recent unravelling of the Raj Kundra porn video business on online streaming platforms has raised many tantalizing questions on the effectiveness of the Indian judiciary. It is indeed shameful and comical to know that the judiciary is confused as to the definition of &amp;ldquo;pornography&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;obscene&amp;rdquo; and specific laws under which to prosecute Kundra and Co.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-do-porn-industries-flourish">Why do porn industries flourish?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Leaving prosecution and dissemination of judgement to more able individuals than me, I would like to raise few points about the other side of the coin: &lt;em>The Indian porn consumer base&lt;/em>. If Raj Kundra was able to lure financially compromised girls into creating obscene content and sell them for millions, then why did he succeed? &lt;strong>Markets thrive where there is demand&lt;/strong> - indeed, the fundamental basis of capitalism. Pornhub yearly statistics reveal Indian consumers on the site has been on a consistent rise. And that is just one provider.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Freakonomics: Should you read it?</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/freakonomics-should-you-read-it/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 11:14:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/freakonomics-should-you-read-it/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Why do drug-dealers still live with their mothers?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Are Sumo wrestlers corrupt?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Legalized abortion led to decreasing crime rates&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Are real-estate agents really acting in &lt;em>your&lt;/em> best interest?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Does a child&amp;rsquo;s name have any effect on their lives?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Do parents really matter?&amp;rdquo; &lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Are swimming pools more dangerous for kids than guns?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Why should teachers cheat?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Freakonomics is a study of bizarre, mundane and exceedingly interesting questions. It employs the arsenal of mathematical sophistication to unearth truths and secrets that are hidden from plain sight. Written by an uncanny duo, Steven D. Levitt (the economist) and Stephen J. Dubner (the journalist) as part of an unexpected collaboration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rereading 'A Thousand Splendid Suns'</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/rereading-a-thousand-splendid-suns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 18:37:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/rereading-a-thousand-splendid-suns/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are all these people constantly questioning me about my identity, my aspirations, &lt;em>my worth&lt;/em>. What I want to do? &lt;em>What I want to be?&lt;/em> So, I am forced to think about these questions. Indeed, what do I wanna do?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I reread the poignant &amp;ldquo;A Thousand Splendid Suns&amp;rdquo; by Khaled Hosseini. So, I have a habit, for better or worse, of poking around the central content to appreciate the big picture. I read a Wikipedia article on Afghanistan&amp;rsquo;s history. I found it interesting. And included 3 books on Afghan history in my library – looking forward to &amp;ldquo;A Brief History of Afghanistan&amp;rdquo; by Shaista Wahab et. al.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is Governance Really So Difficult?</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/is-governance-really-so-difficult/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 13:15:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/is-governance-really-so-difficult/</guid><description>&lt;p>Why is taking economic decisions at a national level such a tantalizing task? Why do government policies fail (sometimes miserably)? Why are people still living on the streets under BPL?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can expose yourself to an array of criticism and theories spun by supposedly thoughtful individuals at any cafe. These folks go on blurting how the present is worse than a decade ago and on and on. I had heard about their side, I wanted to know about the other side too.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Friendship</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/friendship/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 11:37:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/friendship/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;How many times had she, Hasina, and Giti said those same three words to each other,
Laila wondered, said it without hesitation, after only two or three days of not seeing
each other?&lt;br>
&lt;em>I missed you, Hasina.&lt;/em> &lt;em>Oh, I missed you too&lt;/em>. In Tariq&amp;rsquo;s grimace, Laila learned
that boys differed from girls in this regard. They didn&amp;rsquo;t make a show of friendship. They
felt no urge, no need, for this sort of talk. Laila imagined it had been this way for her
brothers too. Boys, Laila came to see, treated friendship the way they treated the sun: its
existence undisputed; its radiance best enjoyed, not beheld directly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Reading Portfolio</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-reading-portfolio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 12:00:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-reading-portfolio/</guid><description>&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t met anybody as devoutly fanatic about books as I am in real life. This love of mine can turn aggressive, even generously self-depreciative, which is a source of concern. I maintain a digital library simply because &lt;em>there won&amp;rsquo;t be enough room&lt;/em> for all the books if I build for myself a physical library (Now you know how to impress me :winking_face:). I spend literally hours fretting about organization, intensely debating with myself what parameters to organize under, designing programs to maintain a catalog, devising makeshift ways to register progress and so on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Notes: The Millionaire Fastlane by MJ DeMarco</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-millionaire-fastlane-by-mj-demarco/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 21:02:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-millionaire-fastlane-by-mj-demarco/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you able to successfully leverage the opportunities at your disposal? That is the question that this book tries to answer and provides advice backed by the author&amp;rsquo;s own experiences. The book is written in a comfortable conversational style, including &lt;em>way too many&lt;/em> metaphors and analogies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The author, himself, has a remarkable lifestyle: starting a tech company during the dot-com bubble, growing it, selling it and so on. Below I have aggregated few core ideas from the book. Enjoy!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Migrating From Jekyll to Hugo</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/migrating-from-jekyll-to-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 10:34:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/migrating-from-jekyll-to-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This is a quick note for the convenience of the readers.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With a heave of pleasant sigh, I can inform you all that &lt;strong>I am migrating from &lt;a href="https://jekyllrb.com">jekyll&lt;/a> to &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io">hugo&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>. Finally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only hindrance (so to speak) was the choice of a decent theme which, as you can see, has been accomplished. Hugo has a ton of features and conveniences that I would be foolish to not take advantage of. Archetypes, built-in shortcodes, KaTeX typesetting, taxonomies beside being so fast! I love Hugo. &amp;#x1f49c;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bookshelf</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/bookshelf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 22:24:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/bookshelf/</guid><description>&lt;p>Inspired by Patrick Collison&amp;rsquo;s luscious &lt;a href="https://patrickcollison.com/bookshelf">bookshelf&lt;/a>, this page is the list of books I have read in the current year (whichever year you are reading it). Most of these are plucked from other people&amp;rsquo;s recommendation lists, popular choices, stuff I find interesting or just a random topic I want to learn about on a Saturday evening. Suggestions? Drop me a &lt;a href="mailto:gs454236@gmail.com">line&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I read somewhere (probably in an Umberto Eco article) that one can understand a man by going through his bookshelf. In any case, this is my bookshelf and I leave you to judge me at my worth. Happy browsing!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 22:12:10 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/about/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-should-you-expect-from-this-blog">What should you expect from this blog?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is a blog about psychology, philosophy, economics, technology, science, art and design. It is not proper to believe this blog is limited to the handful of subjects listed above because it is not. To understand our lives demands a multidisciplinary stance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perhaps, a better explanation is given by ACX which I quote:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ṛta is a Sanskrit word, so ancient that it brushes up against the origin of Indo-European languages. It&amp;rsquo;s related to English &amp;ldquo;rationality&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;arithmetic&amp;rdquo;, but also &amp;ldquo;art&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;harmony&amp;rdquo;. And &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo;, both in the senses of &amp;ldquo;natural rights&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;the right answer&amp;rdquo;. And &amp;ldquo;order&amp;rdquo;. And &amp;ldquo;arete&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;aristos&amp;rdquo; and all those other Greek words about morality. And &amp;ldquo;artificial&amp;rdquo;, as in eg artificial intelligence. More speculatively &amp;ldquo;reign&amp;rdquo; and related words about rulership, and &amp;ldquo;rich&amp;rdquo; and related words about money.
&lt;cite>– Astral Codex Ten&amp;rsquo;s about&lt;/cite>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Most Scarce Resource</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/most-scarce-resource/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/most-scarce-resource/</guid><description>&lt;p>What is the single most scarce resource at the disposal of man?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The present.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It cannot be acquired or earned. It is available to all in equal measure. It cannot be claimed forever unlike knowledge or lost like friends. We may eschew society to do our biddings but all must surrender to this moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anything that you are doing now is a liability and everything else you chose not to do are &lt;em>missed opportunities&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Sun After A Thuderstorm</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-sun-after-a-thuderstorm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-sun-after-a-thuderstorm/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is something magical about the first sunshine after a thunderstorm. The coolness of the still wet ground and the warm sunshine vapourising the dew. The mist hanging low over the floor mixing with the musky smell of freshly spawned algae. The chirping of the songbird as they return to their nests mingling with the chattering of the hawkers and peddlers as they return to the streets below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Notes: I Will Teach You To Be Rich by Ramit Sethi</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-i-will-teach-you-to-be-rich-by-ramit-sethi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-i-will-teach-you-to-be-rich-by-ramit-sethi/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sethi&amp;rsquo;s book, at it&amp;rsquo;s core, is a set of rules and tricks that can be applied by an aware and motivated individual to ensure a life of abundance relative to their current financial standings. Motivated to become rich himself (and hailing from India) at a young age, Sethi learnt from his blunders and noted his successes. He started blogging about his wins which eventually evolved into this book. Needless to say, his advice are well-researched, practical and tested. Do they work? It seems to.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Makes You Powerful?</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/what-makes-you-powerful/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/what-makes-you-powerful/</guid><description>&lt;p>Do you want to know what makes one powerful?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It isn&amp;rsquo;t money or weapons or good health. It is the &lt;em>ability to find the weak side of strong things.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Notes: The Richest Man in Babylon by George S. Clason</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-richest-man-in-babylon-by-george-s.-clason/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-richest-man-in-babylon-by-george-s.-clason/</guid><description>&lt;p>Notes on &lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;The Richest Man in Babylon&amp;rdquo; by George S. Clason.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-wealth">What is wealth?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Wealth is a power. &lt;strong>With wealth, many things are possible.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="essential-habits">Essential Habits&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A man&amp;rsquo;s wealth is not in the purse he carries. &lt;strong>A fat purse quickly empties if there be no golden stream to refill it.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fate is unpredictable hence untrustworthy.&lt;/strong> It makes wanton spenders and misers alike.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Every surplus can earn for you. And every revenue on that can earn for you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Turn Down The Music</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/turn-down-the-music/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/turn-down-the-music/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Yes, turn down the music&lt;br>
Throw away the booze and&lt;br>
Tell them the party&amp;rsquo;s over for&lt;br>
she isn&amp;rsquo;t here.&lt;br>
Rip the sky bleed,&lt;br>
crush every skull I find,&lt;br>
burn every fucking flower &lt;br>
that blooms coz I want her. &lt;br>
Yes, turn down the music&lt;br>
Throw away the booze and&lt;br>
Tell them the party&amp;rsquo;s over for&lt;br>
she isn&amp;rsquo;t here.&lt;br>
Was it so much to ask for your love?&lt;br>
I dreamt too much about us&lt;br>
But you were too conceited. Now,&lt;br>
Switch off the lights &lt;br>
And, turn down the music&lt;br>
Throw away the booze and&lt;br>
Tell them the party&amp;rsquo;s over for&lt;br>
she isn&amp;rsquo;t here. &lt;br>
— b.l.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Think, Wait and Fast</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/think-wait-and-fast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/think-wait-and-fast/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the book &amp;ldquo;Siddhartha&amp;rdquo; by Herman Hesse – the protagonist, who is a Samana (a homeless hermit), is enchanted by the beauty of a woman named Kamala. On their first discourse, Kamala asks him what is he capable of doing that he can trade for money, pretty clothes, shoes, sweet perfumes and gifts for her. To which Siddhartha replies,&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I can think. I can wait. I can fast.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I think that is a very profound answer and it will do ignorant fools like us much good if we make an attempt to comprehend it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Going Public</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/going-public/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/going-public/</guid><description>&lt;p>Circumstances have forced me to mull over unprecedented actions. However, given the situation of the country and the world in general, I hardly think that is an exceptional decision.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The question stands, &lt;em>should I make my blog public?&lt;/em> As rationality dictates, I would like to put forward few thoughts both pro- and anti-, some personal, some acquired.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is not unknown to you that this is this blog&amp;rsquo;s new home on the Web. I took down its previous home simply because a friend of mine discovered it. That maybe happened in March. Am I insecure? Yes, maybe. But who am I to judge myself, whether I&amp;rsquo;m intelligent or insecure? How can an observer infer anything about an experiment of which she herself is a part? I&amp;rsquo;ll let you all to decide.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My First Guitar</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-first-guitar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-first-guitar/</guid><description>&lt;p>I admit I have become lazy. I have not written about myself for a long time. And I apologize for polluting this space with movie and book thoughts. A lot of things have been happening (or should I say, the lack thereof?). But surely, the coolest things to happen is my guitar. Yes, ladies and gentlemen! My first guitar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point, I am not clear whether the pandemic screwed me or I screwed myself. But I am certain, I feel depressed and terribly alone. When your mind is idle, it has these &lt;em>thoughts&lt;/em>, interesting thoughts. Let me share one of mine: So, people say there are introverted and so on and so forth. But they are lying. Because if they were, then they certainly wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be telling you. The point is we don&amp;rsquo;t really know any introverts. And by definition, we can never. For instance, I &lt;em>decided&lt;/em> to write about myself and my life. If I hadn&amp;rsquo;t, you would have never known anything. Now, apply this to &lt;em>every&lt;/em> person you know and let them apply it to their knowns. Those whose laughs are the most joyous are the ones truly crying.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts: UNIX - History and Memoir (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-unix-history-and-memoir-book/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-unix-history-and-memoir-book/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s always good to know about the things you love the most. It somehow makes you love them even more. I am glad non-living things are not stupidly self-conscious and self-doubting like us and I can understand them more deeply than I can understand other humans.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="some-mindfulless-blabberings">Some mind(ful|less) blabberings&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With that said, I enjoyed this book. In Brian&amp;rsquo;s succint prose, he recollects the history of &lt;em>the mother of all operating systems&lt;/em>: UNIX. And along the way, describes the sideways development that it encouraged such as the development of C (the “lingua franca of computing”), various timeless tools like &lt;code>grep&lt;/code>, &lt;code>awk&lt;/code>, &lt;code>sed&lt;/code>, &lt;code>yacc&lt;/code>, &lt;code>lex&lt;/code>, &lt;code>make&lt;/code>, document formatters and so on. He talks about what lead to the development of UNIX and ruminates on the kind of environment contagious to such breakthroughs. Unfettered management, fun atmosphere, great minds, stable funding and the freedom and willingness to solve real-world problems. He also points out and clear a lot of the admittedly confusing history that is the legacy of Unix as the (licensed) source code of Unix reached Berkeley. As he correctly pointed out, AT&amp;amp;T tried to &amp;ldquo;lock the barn door after the crown jewels had flown the coop&amp;rdquo;. And then we had BSD, Minix, Linux, Xenix and yada yada.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dual Boot</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/dual-boot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/dual-boot/</guid><description>&lt;p>I experienced something profound and I want to share.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="my-experience-with-dual-booting">my experience with dual booting&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For three years, I have borne the pain of Windows. I hate it for being a black box. I love it for being a convenience. But I knew I wanted to get out. I was fearful. I have only one laptop and I have heard (oh lord, this word &amp;ldquo;heard&amp;rdquo;) very bad stories of entire hard disks getting purged. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t take the leap.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Notes: Design for Hackers by David Kadavy</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-design-for-hackers-by-david-kadavy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-design-for-hackers-by-david-kadavy/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-design">Why Design?&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Your biggest asset - &amp;ldquo;Learn whatever you want to achieve your vision&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Good designs are timeless. They can awe people of &lt;em>any&lt;/em> era.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fundamental soul of a human creation that expresses itself in successive outer layers of the product.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Designing of a system comes before building it not after.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Affect emotion, build credibility, earn trust.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Don&amp;rsquo;t draw ponies.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>First visual interaction thus heuristic shortcut to judge credibility.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Purpose | Medium and Technology | Aesthetics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Good design choices are a set of ideas that must mature in the mind.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use user persona to wireframe and prototype.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Memorable and usability.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="typography">Typography&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Where does that typeface come from? What medium and technology influenced it?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Typeface is what you use. Font is the file which contains the typeface (Am I being pedantic?).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Understand the forces that brought the style into existence.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SEO is design.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="proportions">Proportions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>How size and magnitude relate to each other.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Important and unimportant elements.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Common ones:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>√2 : 1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 : 4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 : 3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>φ : 1&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="composition">Composition&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Arrangement of elements.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reading direction, guiding the eye.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="principles">Principles&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Dominance - pulls you in&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Similarity&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rhythm&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Texture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Direction&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contrast&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Application to MailChimp logo&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="visual-hierarchy">Visual Hierarchy&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>White space&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Type weight&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Type size - 3:4 relationship - 5, 7, 9, 12, 16, 21, 28, 37, 50, 67&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Color&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ornamentation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Different blog designs and explanation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Application to website&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cluttering design in HTML tables&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="color-science">Color Science&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Color in physics
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>EMR&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Human visual limitations
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Color constancy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>metamerism&lt;/li>
&lt;li>afterimages&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Human visual system (biology)
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Rod, cones (3 types), ganglion etc&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Trichromatic theory, color opponent theory&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Color blindness&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Color models
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Munsell&lt;/li>
&lt;li>HSB&lt;/li>
&lt;li>LAB&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data driven graphics
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Converging palettes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Diverging palletes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RGB model
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Color mixing, additive model&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hexadecimal mental model&lt;/li>
&lt;li>navigating color without using a picker&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cross media color representation
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>RGB (computers), CMYK (print)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CMYK a subtractive model&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gamuts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ICC profile&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Approximate screen color on print (previewing color shifts, proofing etc)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spot colors&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="color-theory">Color Theory&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Color association with events for our ancestors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Effect of red on prefrontal cortex
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>prefrontal cortex and rational thought&lt;/li>
&lt;li>eg of Target (retailer chain)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>use cases for red&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Color and culture
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>questions to ask when designing for a foreign culture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>do research&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Color Wheel&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Expected usage of few colors in culture
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>White - backgrounds, trustworthy etc&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Off white - natural feel, not for high traffic site&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dark - sophistication, exclusivity&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bright - less content&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Green - success, mark of progress&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Yellow - info&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Red - error, warning, urgent&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Blue - links (generally)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Accent colors&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Interaction between colors
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>warm colors pop, cool colors recede&lt;/li>
&lt;li>tint pops, shade recedes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>why monet never used black (explanation of his poplar painting)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>application to typography color, element design&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Color schemes
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>monochromatic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>analogous&lt;/li>
&lt;li>complementary&lt;/li>
&lt;li>split complementary&lt;/li>
&lt;li>triadic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>tetradic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>variations&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Creating mood with colors
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>mysterious (exclusive)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>active (youths, zeal etc)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>muted (solemn etc)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>natural&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tools for creating color schemes
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="www.colorschemer.com">Color Schemer&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://colorschemedesigner.com">Color Scheme Designer&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://kuler.adobe.com">Kuler&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h1 id="appendix-a">appendix A&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Consult for table of pairable typefaces to use for different purposes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h1 id="appendix-b---typographical-etiquette">appendix B - typographical etiquette&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fake bold/italic/small caps&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stretch types&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Outline types&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Impose background images or textures&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>Avoid Widows and orphans&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use drop caps&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Avoid indenting and leaving a line. Redundant.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use smart quotes (&lt;code>&amp;amp;rdquo; &amp;amp;ldquo; &amp;amp;rdquo; &amp;amp;ldquo; &amp;amp;prime; &amp;amp;Prime;&lt;/code> )&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>&amp;amp;hyphen;&lt;/code> (‐), &lt;code>&amp;amp;ndash;&lt;/code> (–) and &lt;code>&amp;amp;mdash;&lt;/code> (—)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ligatures but not widely supported.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Thoughts: Design for Hackers (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-design-for-hackers-book/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-design-for-hackers-book/</guid><description>&lt;p>Design. An idea which I admit rather shamefully to not have paid any serious attention to (until now).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Design of a system happens before building not after.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This, it seems, is a general attitude towards design by builders and engineers or people who work on the guts or so called backend of a system as was coyly pointed out by the author himself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, it is true. Design is something I have always thought of as an after thought in my projects at least uptil now. But no more!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Notes: Habits by James Clear</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-habits-by-james-clear/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-habits-by-james-clear/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="my-notes">My Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Majority fail in making habits because they try to make changes the wrong way.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It is easy to get obssessed with the result.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Never overestimate the importance of one defining moment and underestimate the value of making better decisions on a daily basis.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Don&amp;rsquo;t focus on the destination. Focus on the path.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="habits">Habits&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Pattern of every habit:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Reminder ( trigger )&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Routine ( the action itself )&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reward ( the benefit )&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A good reminder makes it easier for you to start your habit by encoding your new behavior in something that you already do, rather than relying on getting motivated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gemini Protocol</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/gemini-protocol/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/gemini-protocol/</guid><description>&lt;p>Gemini is a minimal &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_layer">application layer&lt;/a> request-response protocol that aims to make a &lt;em>Geminispace&lt;/em> of information to be accessible to anyone even with slow/intermittent internet connection. Think HTTP 0.9 or a less restraining Gopher.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="tldr">TLDR&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t checked out Gemini yet, you &lt;a href="https://gemini.circumlunar.space">totally should&lt;/a>. This is a HTTP proxy to the actual gemini site.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-gemini">Why Gemini?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I really value your time and understand you have better things to do. So, I&amp;rsquo;ll cut down on formalities and introductions and preludes and yada yada. My format might be quirky but my motive is always to be efficient and effective and non-conformant.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Specialisation</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/specialisation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/specialisation/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-this-about">What is this about?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>So, here&amp;rsquo;s the thing, imagine the following situation:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Living in the Present or the Future</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/living-in-the-present-or-the-future/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/living-in-the-present-or-the-future/</guid><description>&lt;p>A concave disposition I figured.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Living in the now, the present versus living for the future. This is &lt;strong>not&lt;/strong> a mutually exclusive choice. One must possess both qualities and be able to switch back and forth effortlessly between them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Living for the future is stressful in the present but generally blissful for the future. You might argue that this must be the optimum choice but the conflict is you are preparing for something non existent and moreover, expending your &lt;em>present&lt;/em> to do so and effective using what you can only ever experience, the present.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Systems and Everything Else</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/systems-and-everything-else/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/systems-and-everything-else/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is probably the best life skill I have come across in a while that I wish to talk about.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-this-post-about">What is this post about?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Have you struggled to find a bearing in the world? With &lt;strong>so&lt;/strong> much information and activity to process, does it make your mind feel despaired? Have you endeavored (tried?) to find a list of &lt;em>fundamental principles&lt;/em> to live by? Everyone has a core belief through which stems (either consciously or unconsciouly) all of their thoughts and actions. But I disgress, this is for another time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Year in Books: 2020</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/bs/yib2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/bs/yib2020/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="lets-get-started">Let&amp;rsquo;s Get Started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Rosie Project | Graeme Simsion&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
My first read this year (2020). I started just after taking the last of my annuals and I remember laughing hard. It&amp;rsquo;s a romcom about a genetic professor suffering from Asperger&amp;rsquo;s trying to find a wife. The &lt;code>Wife Project&lt;/code> still gives me giggles. Oh and I remember picking this up after seeing it on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/a47dqygseGo">Bill Gate&amp;rsquo;s to-read list&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Daemon | Daniel Suarez&lt;/strong> &lt;br>
A dystopian fiction where a computer program takes &amp;ldquo;control&amp;rdquo;. This was on my list for a long time. I read it in our public library and enjoyed the nerd talk. By the way, it also has a sequel &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8488830-freedom">Freedom (TM)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts: The Selfish Gene (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-selfish-gene-book/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-selfish-gene-book/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My favourite non-fiction read of 2020.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Music Order Arrived</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-music-order-arrived/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-music-order-arrived/</guid><description>&lt;p>A rather crazy self-imposed project which I had the faintest of ideas will become all-devouring and pose countless hurdles for me to dodge. But yeah, did it. Don&amp;rsquo;t blame me for the CT making ethereal noises!&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/ctcd1.jpg"
 alt="From left to right: Treasure, Stars and Topsoil and Heaven or Las Vegas (all CDs)">&lt;figcaption>
 &lt;p>From left to right: Treasure, Stars and Topsoil and Heaven or Las Vegas (all CDs)&lt;/p>
 &lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>

&lt;h2 id="why-do-i-have-to-buy-music">Why do I have to buy music?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, because I want to. But seriously, why in a world of Spotify and pirated downloadable songs would I have the brilliant idea to &lt;em>buy&lt;/em> music?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My First Open Source Excursion</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-first-open-source-excursion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-first-open-source-excursion/</guid><description>&lt;p>Granted that I have atleast a dozen projects hanging in midair (figuratively) on my hard disk (literally).
And I have a couple of repos on github in near stasis but today I had my first whiff of open source. Open source doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean much without collaboration and today I dabbled in real time. Contributing code to a public repo, getting feedback and watching it getting approved. Oh! I felt rewarded.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stuck by Fandom for the First Time in My Life</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/stuck-by-fandom-for-the-first-time-in-my-life/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/stuck-by-fandom-for-the-first-time-in-my-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ethereal, heavenly, celestial, opulent, splendid, otherworldly - these adjectives form the regular staple of people who dare to describe the music of the Cocteau Twins (pronounced: cock-tow twins). Honestly, I think it&amp;rsquo;s an effort in vain. Because this band defies all possibilities of being defined by words. Cage them in artificial genres and you will fail. You can only &lt;em>experience&lt;/em> their &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;sacred microcosm&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> yourself as Azam Ali so eloquently puts &lt;a href="https://www.talkhouse.com/the-sacred-microcosm-of-the-cocteau-twins">it&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>