<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Travel on Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/series/travel/</link><description>Recent content in Travel on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'&gt;Basil Labib&lt;/a&gt; | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'&gt;Basic&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 22:44:01 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/series/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Trip To The Paradise On Earth: Part 2</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-trip-to-the-paradise-on-earth-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 22:44:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-trip-to-the-paradise-on-earth-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the second part of my travelogue to Kashmir. You may read the first part &lt;a href="https://basil08.github.io/post/a-trip-to-the-paradise-on-earth-part-1/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="day-5---a-day-of-many-songs-and-many-silences"&gt;Day 5 - A day of many songs and many silences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/kashmir-2/17.png"
 alt="Route for the intracity tour within Srinagar" width="400px"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Route for the intracity tour within Srinagar&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went for my usual walk around 7:30 am. It was still relatively cold, and most of the city was still asleep. It was mutually decided the night before that we would take a break from long trips and explore the city itself. That was the plan.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Trip To The Paradise On Earth: Part 1</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-trip-to-the-paradise-on-earth-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 20:05:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-trip-to-the-paradise-on-earth-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This travelogue and the next one narrates my experiences of spending a week in Kashmir with my family. As always, I have tried to combine my personal ruminations with more useful information if you&amp;rsquo;re a fellow traveller.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: This post might contains expletives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/kashmir/4.jpg"
 alt="On the trek path to Thajivas Glacier, Sonamarg. October 2024"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;On the trek path to Thajivas Glacier, Sonamarg. October 2024&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id="day-0-sunday---leaving-delhi"&gt;Day 0 (Sunday) - Leaving Delhi&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a punishing mid-semester, the onslaught of RDV was setting a lighter and more exciting tone for campus peeps. Being a part of RDV for the past three years, one gains the wisdom that it isn’t much of a big deal for final year students if they are not in the organising team. Basically, I didn’t give a fuck about the fact that it was RDV time on campus. My weekend was spent in the library studying. However, I was looking forward to the Qawwali night slated for Sunday evening. I was also looking forward to catching a train just after that which will take me to Jammu and then to the magical land of Kashmir.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>London Diaries! Part 1</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/london-diaries-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 06:39:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/london-diaries-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is the second time I’m trying to write this post. It shouldn’t be this hard to write a travelogue, right? RIGHT?! But it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some part of that blame goes to all the rich and many, many experiences that I have had on this trip. Each of them fought for space in this post, and inadvertently, I had to let go of some. In any case, what follows is my travelogue for my trip to London from 16th August to 27th August 2024 - reproduced to the best of my abilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stories from the Underground: Part 2</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/stories-from-the-underground-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 20:50:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/stories-from-the-underground-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As promised, this is part 2 of &lt;a href="https://basil08.github.io/post/stories-from-the-underground-part-1/"&gt;Stories from the Underground&lt;/a&gt;, my travelogue on the GCP workshop at Oxford and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: This post might contains expletives.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="day-3-21st-december"&gt;Day 3 (21st December)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up and stretched like a cat on my double bed. Having a room for two all for myself was a welcome change from long hours of sitting and waiting around at airports. I glanced at my clock, 6ish. &lt;em&gt;Perfect&lt;/em&gt;, I thought. Wrapped up some BSP work, made one of those instant hot chocolate thingie and went for my walk — a considerably longer one because the workshop was over and we were scheduled to depart for Oxford at 10. Video called my folks. I forced myself to take unchartered paths through the woods. It was fascinating to observe a biome so biologically different from one back in the tropics – mosses and lichens were aplenty and so were ferns and temperate-ish flora. The wetness had turned the dirt into mud and my shoes were making squishy noises all along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stories from the Underground: Part 1</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/stories-from-the-underground-part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 09:50:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/stories-from-the-underground-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: This post might contain expletives.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="prologue"&gt;Prologue&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am waiting at the airport bound to New Delhi right now on NYE. It&amp;rsquo;s been around 10 days since I came back from my first international trip and subsequently go on to represent my institute at Inter IIT Cultural Meet at IIT Kharagpur. I have classes from 8 am tomorrow morning. When did my life got so fast?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is this life if, full of care,&lt;br&gt;
We have no time to stand and stare. &lt;br&gt;
~Leisure, William Henry Davies&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Escapade Into Uttarakhand: A travelogue</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/escapade-into-uttarakhand-a-travelogue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 13:12:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/escapade-into-uttarakhand-a-travelogue/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This travelogue was created based on my journal entries on a daily(ish) basis. I volunteered as a teacher at a remote village in Uttarakhand and helped high school kids prepare for competitive exams (JEE/NEET) for two weeks. This travelogue is presented almost in its entirety with few redacts that I deemed too personal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="day-1-3031-may"&gt;Day 1 (30/31 May)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got onto an almost full Traveller van in front of Satpura&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; amidst torrential rain and found myself greeted with unknown (and somewhat hostile) faces. I got into a corner and crumpled myself somehow into that little space. And we rolled around 7:30pm. After sometime I realised, to my horror, that I wanted to puke. It was then that it dawned on me that perhaps I&amp;rsquo;m also one of those people who cannot stand travelling in cars although I was surprised because it had never happened before (also maybe because I have never been on a trip like this). Anyhow, because of a sheer stroke of good luck, someone shifted and I got a window seat and I got better because of the cool Delhi air.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>BUIDL: Hitching a ride on the web3 wagon</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/buidl-hitching-a-ride-on-the-web3-wagon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 09:28:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/buidl-hitching-a-ride-on-the-web3-wagon/</guid><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/ethindia22/18.jpeg"
 alt="ETHIndia 2022&amp;rsquo; @Whitefield, BLR" width="400px"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;ETHIndia 2022&amp;rsquo; @Whitefield, BLR&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;div style="display: flex;"&gt;
 &lt;div class="white" style="padding: 5px; border-radius: 4px; margin: 0.2em;"&gt;
 &lt;blockquote&gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;Infinite Garden&lt;/strong&gt;: a diverse ecosystem of individuals and organizations that build and grow alongside ethereum.
 &lt;/blockquote&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ethereum ecosystem, particularly the scaling L2 solutions are witnessing dramatic progress in terms of breakthroughs and innovation. The &lt;code&gt;Infinite Garden&lt;/code&gt; is the phrase used to refer to the truly decentralized techno-haven where interaction between online entities are transparent and uncensored. Free from censorship, state control, fraud, and malicious agents, powered by the ecosystem of applications built on blockchains - in short, an information utopia. Personally, the idea seems enticing and inviting. But transitioning from web2 to web3 is a long way and the vision I outlined, although the shared vision of the people on the frontier of this revolution, is still a long, long way into the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>