<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Travel on Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/series/travel/</link><description>Recent content in Travel on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'>Basil Labib&lt;/a> | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Basic&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 20:50:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/series/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Stories from the Underground: Part 2</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/stories-from-the-underground-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 20:50:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/stories-from-the-underground-part-2/</guid><description>As promised, this is part 2 of Stories from the Underground, my travelogue on the GCP workshop at Oxford and beyond.
Disclaimer: This post might contains expletives.
Day 3 (21st December) I woke up and stretched like a cat on my double bed. Having a room for two all for myself was a welcome change from long hours of sitting and waiting around at airports. I glanced at my clock, 6ish.</description></item><item><title>Stories from the Underground: Part 1</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/stories-from-the-underground-part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 09:50:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/stories-from-the-underground-part-1/</guid><description>Disclaimer: This post might contain expletives.
Prologue I am waiting at the airport bound to New Delhi right now on NYE. It&amp;rsquo;s been around 10 days since I came back from my first international trip and subsequently go on to represent my institute at Inter IIT Cultural Meet at IIT Kharagpur. I have classes from 8 am tomorrow morning. When did my life got so fast?
What is this life if, full of care,</description></item><item><title>Escapade Into Uttarakhand: A travelogue</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/escapade-into-uttarakhand-a-travelogue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 13:12:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/escapade-into-uttarakhand-a-travelogue/</guid><description>Introduction This travelogue was created based on my journal entries on a daily(ish) basis. I volunteered as a teacher at a remote village in Uttarakhand and helped high school kids prepare for competitive exams (JEE/NEET) for two weeks. This travelogue is presented almost in its entirety with few redacts that I deemed too personal.
Day 1 (30/31 May) I got onto an almost full Traveller van in front of Satpura1 amidst torrential rain and found myself greeted with unknown (and somewhat hostile) faces.</description></item><item><title>BUIDL: Hitching a ride on the web3 wagon</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/buidl-hitching-a-ride-on-the-web3-wagon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 09:28:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/buidl-hitching-a-ride-on-the-web3-wagon/</guid><description>ETHIndia 2022&amp;rsquo; @Whitefield, BLR
Infinite Garden: a diverse ecosystem of individuals and organizations that build and grow alongside ethereum. The Ethereum ecosystem, particularly the scaling L2 solutions are witnessing dramatic progress in terms of breakthroughs and innovation. The Infinite Garden is the phrase used to refer to the truly decentralized techno-haven where interaction between online entities are transparent and uncensored. Free from censorship, state control, fraud, and malicious agents, powered by the ecosystem of applications built on blockchains - in short, an information utopia.</description></item></channel></rss>