<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>thoughts on The Personal Blog of Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/tags/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in thoughts on The Personal Blog of Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'>Basil Labib&lt;/a> | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Basic&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 08:58:30 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thoughts: The Psychology of Money (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-psychology-of-money-book/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 08:58:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-psychology-of-money-book/</guid><description>Abstract Morgan Housel&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Psychology of Money&amp;rdquo; is less of a technical book and more of a collection of wisdom and wishful advices. It is N. Taleb&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Bed of Procrustes&amp;rdquo; augmented with real life anecdotes, morsels of history, and a lot of quotations. Although Housel professes a very conservative and frugal approach to managing money, his advice cannot be disputed without a very good counter argument. The cautious models, frameworks, and signposts laid out in the book would prevent an investor from being foolish and that Housel says is too easy to be in the modern financial system.</description></item><item><title>Web 3.0 and The Metaverse Mania</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/web-3.0-and-the-metaverse-mania/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 19:54:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/web-3.0-and-the-metaverse-mania/</guid><description>There is a shot in Steven Spielberg&amp;rsquo;s 2018 science fiction &amp;ldquo;Ready Player One&amp;rdquo; where the protagonist, Wade, sitting in a shack in Columbus puts on a VR headset and is transported to the planet of Incipio where all avatars are born when they enter the OASIS. They can morph into any characters, cartoon, or monster. Customise how they look and sound and smell. Buy virtual assets and fight in hunts on a planet called Doom (Watch the movie if this is lost on you).</description></item><item><title>Sylvia Plath, The Bell Jar and feminism</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/sylvia-plath-the-bell-jar-and-feminism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 11:27:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/sylvia-plath-the-bell-jar-and-feminism/</guid><description>"What I hate is the thought of being under a man&amp;rsquo;s thumb&amp;quot;, Sylvia fearlessly thundered in her only published novel &amp;ldquo;The Bell Jar&amp;rdquo;. Published in 1963, Jar is one of the prominent texts on feminism and the vocalisation of a woman&amp;rsquo;s apprehensions, rights and freedom. Sylvia&amp;rsquo;s words, like brazen dagger, are used today in protest marches as well as analysed in literary circles.
Sylvia Plath
Jar stands as testimony to the ephemeral skills of Sylvia as a writer.</description></item><item><title>31 Years of 'Heaven or Las Vegas'</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/31-years-of-heaven-or-las-vegas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 10:18:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/31-years-of-heaven-or-las-vegas/</guid><description>Most CT fans agree (and frankly, there ain&amp;rsquo;t many) that Heaven or Las Vegas is their definitive production: ephemeral and sublime, cocky song titles and discernable vocals, sweet sounds and fragments of bitter lyrics, it is a very Twins album in spirit. Garlands (1982), their debut, was too much on the punk and goth style, a desperate searching phase for their identity which was fulfilled by Treasure (1984), a commendable opus in itself.</description></item><item><title>'Please myself': An interpretation 30 years later</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/please-myself-an-interpretation-30-years-later/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 08:02:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/please-myself-an-interpretation-30-years-later/</guid><description>Polly, a common American girl name, quickly rose to fame as the 6th songtrack on Nirvana&amp;rsquo;s second album, Nevermind, one of the best-selling albums of all time, having sold over 30 million copies since its release in 1991.
Polly became a conversation starter, an ice-breaker, a household catalyst for people everywhere to talk about woman abuse. Polly is a protest song, a song born out of the anguish that Kurt felt for the condition and treatment of woman in the society.</description></item><item><title>To be or not to be: Understanding Hamlet</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/to-be-or-not-to-be-understanding-hamlet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 10:20:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/to-be-or-not-to-be-understanding-hamlet/</guid><description>Volumes have been written on the &amp;ldquo;meaning&amp;rdquo; of Hamlet (the play) by more qualified people than me. I do not seek to compete with them. What follows is my perception of Hamlet, a sketch so if you will, from a modern day perspective.
Hamlet is a complex character. I have strived to deduce Hamlet strictly from the source text and not get influenced by writings elsewhere because I feel external analysis somehow shrouds (glorifies or diminishs, whichever) the essence of what Shakespeare intended.</description></item><item><title>A Closer Look at 'Inside Job'</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-closer-look-at-inside-job/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 16:56:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-closer-look-at-inside-job/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Inside Job&amp;rdquo; is a 2010 documentary written, directed and produced by Charles Ferguson on the 2008 global financial crisis. It won the Oscar in the &amp;ldquo;Best Documentary Feature&amp;rdquo; category in 2011. Notwithstanding, it makes for an enlightening and thrilling watch that every citizen, who cares about where their hard earned money goes, should watch.
This documentary is not an easy watch that one can grab on a lazy afternoon comfortable on their couch.</description></item><item><title>Rereading 'A Thousand Splendid Suns'</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/rereading-a-thousand-splendid-suns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 18:37:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/rereading-a-thousand-splendid-suns/</guid><description>There are all these people constantly questioning me about my identity, my aspirations, my worth. What I want to do? What I want to be? So, I am forced to think about these questions. Indeed, what do I wanna do?
I reread the poignant &amp;ldquo;A Thousand Splendid Suns&amp;rdquo; by Khaled Hosseini. So, I have a habit, for better or worse, of poking around the central content to appreciate the big picture.</description></item><item><title>Is Governance Really So Difficult?</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/is-governance-really-so-difficult/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 13:15:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/is-governance-really-so-difficult/</guid><description>Why is taking economic decisions at a national level such a tantalizing task? Why do government policies fail (sometimes miserably)? Why are people still living on the streets under BPL?
You can expose yourself to an array of criticism and theories spun by supposedly thoughtful individuals at any cafe. These folks go on blurting how the present is worse than a decade ago and on and on. I had heard about their side, I wanted to know about the other side too.</description></item><item><title>Notes: The Millionaire Fastlane by MJ DeMarco</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-millionaire-fastlane-by-mj-demarco/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 21:02:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-millionaire-fastlane-by-mj-demarco/</guid><description>Are you able to successfully leverage the opportunities at your disposal? That is the question that this book tries to answer and provides advice backed by the author&amp;rsquo;s own experiences. The book is written in a comfortable conversational style, including way too many metaphors and analogies.
The author, himself, has a remarkable lifestyle: starting a tech company during the dot-com bubble, growing it, selling it and so on. Below I have aggregated few core ideas from the book.</description></item><item><title>The Sun After A Thuderstorm</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-sun-after-a-thuderstorm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-sun-after-a-thuderstorm/</guid><description>There is something magical about the first sunshine after a thunderstorm. The coolness of the still wet ground and the warm sunshine vapourising the dew. The mist hanging low over the floor mixing with the musky smell of freshly spawned algae. The chirping of the songbird as they return to their nests mingling with the chattering of the hawkers and peddlers as they return to the streets below.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts: UNIX - History and Memoir (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-unix-history-and-memoir-book/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-unix-history-and-memoir-book/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s always good to know about the things you love the most. It somehow makes you love them even more. I am glad non-living things are not stupidly self-conscious and self-doubting like us and I can understand them more deeply than I can understand other humans.
Some mind(ful|less) blabberings With that said, I enjoyed this book. In Brian&amp;rsquo;s succint prose, he recollects the history of the mother of all operating systems: UNIX.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts: The Selfish Gene (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-selfish-gene-book/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-selfish-gene-book/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My favourite non-fiction read of 2020.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>