<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Interpretations on Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/tags/interpretations/</link><description>Recent content in Interpretations on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'>Basil Labib&lt;/a> | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Basic&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 08:02:53 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/tags/interpretations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>'Please myself': An interpretation 30 years later</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/please-myself-an-interpretation-30-years-later/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 08:02:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/please-myself-an-interpretation-30-years-later/</guid><description>&lt;p>Polly, a common American girl name, quickly rose to fame as the 6th songtrack on Nirvana&amp;rsquo;s second album, Nevermind, one of the best-selling albums of all time, having sold over 30 million copies since its release in 1991.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Polly became a conversation starter, an ice-breaker, a household catalyst for people everywhere to talk about woman abuse. Polly is a protest song, a song born out of the anguish that Kurt felt for the condition and treatment of woman in the society. It has often been dubbed as Nirvana&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;darkest&amp;rdquo; song – which, in my opinion, is a fairly glorified sobriquet because most of Nirvana&amp;rsquo;s songs are dark and ghastly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>To be or not to be: Understanding Hamlet</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/to-be-or-not-to-be-understanding-hamlet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 10:20:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/to-be-or-not-to-be-understanding-hamlet/</guid><description>&lt;p>Volumes have been written on the &amp;ldquo;meaning&amp;rdquo; of Hamlet (the play) by more qualified people than me. I do not seek to compete with them. What follows is my perception of Hamlet, a sketch so if you will, from a modern day perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hamlet is a complex character. I have strived to deduce Hamlet strictly from the source text and not get influenced by writings elsewhere because I feel external analysis somehow shrouds (glorifies or diminishs, whichever) the essence of what Shakespeare intended. I also acknowledge there are passages and portions that are still unclear to me. I take them as deficiencies on my part and the excellence of the play.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is Governance Really So Difficult?</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/is-governance-really-so-difficult/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 13:15:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/is-governance-really-so-difficult/</guid><description>&lt;p>Why is taking economic decisions at a national level such a tantalizing task? Why do government policies fail (sometimes miserably)? Why are people still living on the streets under BPL?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can expose yourself to an array of criticism and theories spun by supposedly thoughtful individuals at any cafe. These folks go on blurting how the present is worse than a decade ago and on and on. I had heard about their side, I wanted to know about the other side too.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Think, Wait and Fast</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/think-wait-and-fast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/think-wait-and-fast/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the book &amp;ldquo;Siddhartha&amp;rdquo; by Herman Hesse – the protagonist, who is a Samana (a homeless hermit), is enchanted by the beauty of a woman named Kamala. On their first discourse, Kamala asks him what is he capable of doing that he can trade for money, pretty clothes, shoes, sweet perfumes and gifts for her. To which Siddhartha replies,&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I can think. I can wait. I can fast.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts: UNIX - History and Memoir (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-unix-history-and-memoir-book/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-unix-history-and-memoir-book/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s always good to know about the things you love the most. It somehow makes you love them even more. I am glad non-living things are not stupidly self-conscious and self-doubting like us and I can understand them more deeply than I can understand other humans.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="some-mindfulless-blabberings">Some mind(ful|less) blabberings&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With that said, I enjoyed this book. In Brian&amp;rsquo;s succint prose, he recollects the history of &lt;em>the mother of all operating systems&lt;/em>: UNIX. And along the way, describes the sideways development that it encouraged such as the development of C (the “lingua franca of computing”), various timeless tools like &lt;code>grep&lt;/code>, &lt;code>awk&lt;/code>, &lt;code>sed&lt;/code>, &lt;code>yacc&lt;/code>, &lt;code>lex&lt;/code>, &lt;code>make&lt;/code>, document formatters and so on. He talks about what lead to the development of UNIX and ruminates on the kind of environment contagious to such breakthroughs. Unfettered management, fun atmosphere, great minds, stable funding and the freedom and willingness to solve real-world problems. He also points out and clear a lot of the admittedly confusing history that is the legacy of Unix as the (licensed) source code of Unix reached Berkeley. As he correctly pointed out, AT&amp;amp;T tried to &amp;ldquo;lock the barn door after the crown jewels had flown the coop&amp;rdquo;. And then we had BSD, Minix, Linux, Xenix and yada yada.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts: The Selfish Gene (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-selfish-gene-book/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-selfish-gene-book/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My favourite non-fiction read of 2020.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>