<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Music on Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/tags/music/</link><description>Recent content in Music on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'>Basil Labib&lt;/a> | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Basic&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 10:18:49 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>31 Years of 'Heaven or Las Vegas'</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/31-years-of-heaven-or-las-vegas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 10:18:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/31-years-of-heaven-or-las-vegas/</guid><description>&lt;p>Most CT fans agree (and frankly, there ain&amp;rsquo;t many) that Heaven or Las Vegas is their definitive production: ephemeral and sublime, cocky song titles and discernable vocals, sweet sounds and fragments of bitter lyrics, it is a very Twins album in spirit. Garlands (1982), their debut, was too much on the punk and goth style, a desperate searching phase for their identity which was fulfilled by Treasure (1984), a commendable opus in itself. But it is Heaven or Las Vegas or a song therein, that the CT are most remembered for.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>'Please myself': An interpretation 30 years later</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/please-myself-an-interpretation-30-years-later/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 08:02:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/please-myself-an-interpretation-30-years-later/</guid><description>&lt;p>Polly, a common American girl name, quickly rose to fame as the 6th songtrack on Nirvana&amp;rsquo;s second album, Nevermind, one of the best-selling albums of all time, having sold over 30 million copies since its release in 1991.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Polly became a conversation starter, an ice-breaker, a household catalyst for people everywhere to talk about woman abuse. Polly is a protest song, a song born out of the anguish that Kurt felt for the condition and treatment of woman in the society. It has often been dubbed as Nirvana&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;darkest&amp;rdquo; song – which, in my opinion, is a fairly glorified sobriquet because most of Nirvana&amp;rsquo;s songs are dark and ghastly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Music Order Arrived</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-music-order-arrived/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-music-order-arrived/</guid><description>&lt;p>A rather crazy self-imposed project which I had the faintest of ideas will become all-devouring and pose countless hurdles for me to dodge. But yeah, did it. Don&amp;rsquo;t blame me for the CT making ethereal noises!&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/ctcd1.jpg"
 alt="From left to right: Treasure, Stars and Topsoil and Heaven or Las Vegas (all CDs)">&lt;figcaption>
 &lt;p>From left to right: Treasure, Stars and Topsoil and Heaven or Las Vegas (all CDs)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>