<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Love on Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/tags/love/</link><description>Recent content in Love on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'&gt;Basil Labib&lt;/a&gt; | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'&gt;Basic&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 09:04:40 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/tags/love/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Sensuality of Rilke's Love Poems</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-sensuality-of-rilkes-love-poems/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 09:04:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-sensuality-of-rilkes-love-poems/</guid><description>&lt;div style="display: flex;"&gt;
 &lt;div class="white" style="padding: 5px; border-radius: 4px; margin: 0.2em;"&gt;
 &lt;blockquote&gt;
 I tell you that I have a long way to go before I am – where one begins&amp;hellip;
 &lt;/blockquote&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are Rilke&amp;rsquo;s first words that I read. I had no prior acquaintance with either the man or his writings, save for a curious Google search on a Cocteau Twins&amp;rsquo; song called &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lkvmjniEW0E"&gt;Rilkean Heart&lt;/a&gt;. And yet, I immediately felt a tug towards these words, gyrating around them, twisting and turning them in my head, trying to make sense of it. Perhaps, just perhaps, Rilke would know the storm that was raging in me?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Love As An Illegitimate Byproduct</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/love-as-an-illegitimate-byproduct/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 10:18:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/love-as-an-illegitimate-byproduct/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Evolutionary biology has always fascinated me. I have marveled at the ingenuity of evolutionists drawing up elegant theories, piecing together the most bizarre of observations with a string of sound reasoning. I guess the quality of making logical sense of the alien world we find ourselves in makes evolution appeal to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I read Jared Diamond&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Why Sex is Fun?&amp;rdquo;, a short book (a series of essays really) about human sexuality and how it differs so radically from every other species we know of. His words and reasoning reminded me of Dawkins&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;The Selfish Gene&amp;rdquo; – particularly nostalgic where the spermatozoa and oocyte structural discrepency and Zahavis&amp;rsquo; principle of handicap signals; however, the prose was much easier to read than Selfish. Evolution is much like astronomy / cosmology in a certain way – both instills humility in a manner no other subject can.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>