<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Movie on Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/tags/movie/</link><description>Recent content in Movie on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'&gt;Basil Labib&lt;/a&gt; | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'&gt;Basic&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 08:59:33 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/tags/movie/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A personal interpretation of 'The Matrix'</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-personal-interpretation-of-the-matrix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 08:59:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-personal-interpretation-of-the-matrix/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="display: inline-block; font-size: 30px; font-weight: 600;"&gt;I first saw &lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Matrix&lt;/em&gt; last year and like every person who has watched it since its release in 1999, it left my auditory and visual senses on overload and a gargantuan heap of information for my brain to process. A second viewing few days back, made me observe relationships and philosophies that escaped me in the first attempt. There are good reasons why &lt;em&gt;The Matrix&lt;/em&gt; is discussed by critics even today from as varied perspectives as social, political, scientific, philosophical and of course, technological and has injected such appealing concepts and ideas in the public imagination that they have managed to pass into our vocabulary and lifestyles.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Closer Look at 'Inside Job'</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-closer-look-at-inside-job/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 16:56:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-closer-look-at-inside-job/</guid><description>&lt;!-- 


&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/4XVLECplZwd2OrHFkfy6Te"
 width="100%"
 height="380"
 frameborder="0"
 allowtransparency="true"
 allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Inside Job&amp;rdquo; is a 2010 documentary written, directed and produced by Charles Ferguson on the 2008 global financial crisis. It won the Oscar in the &amp;ldquo;Best Documentary Feature&amp;rdquo; category in 2011. Notwithstanding, it makes for an enlightening and thrilling watch that every citizen, who cares about where their hard earned money goes, should watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This documentary is not an easy watch that one can grab on a lazy afternoon comfortable on their couch. It has complex sounding terms and concepts that should keep one on the edge of their seat. As those financial experts makes the layman believe, &amp;ldquo;What we do is far more complicated for you to understand so you better leave us alone as we do it.&amp;rdquo; They are soft-headed people who will make one feel witless and run away with their money. That is exactly what happened in 2008.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>