<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>UNIX on Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/tags/unix/</link><description>Recent content in UNIX on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'&gt;Basil Labib&lt;/a&gt; | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'&gt;Basic&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/tags/unix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thoughts: UNIX - History and Memoir (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-unix-history-and-memoir-book/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-unix-history-and-memoir-book/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s always good to know about the things you love the most. It somehow makes you love them even more. I am glad non-living things are not stupidly self-conscious and self-doubting like us and I can understand them more deeply than I can understand other humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="some-mindfulless-blabberings"&gt;Some mind(ful|less) blabberings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that said, I enjoyed this book. In Brian&amp;rsquo;s succint prose, he recollects the history of &lt;em&gt;the mother of all operating systems&lt;/em&gt;: UNIX. And along the way, describes the sideways development that it encouraged such as the development of C (the “lingua franca of computing”), various timeless tools like &lt;code&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;awk&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;sed&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;yacc&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;lex&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt;, document formatters and so on. He talks about what lead to the development of UNIX and ruminates on the kind of environment contagious to such breakthroughs. Unfettered management, fun atmosphere, great minds, stable funding and the freedom and willingness to solve real-world problems. He also points out and clear a lot of the admittedly confusing history that is the legacy of Unix as the (licensed) source code of Unix reached Berkeley. As he correctly pointed out, AT&amp;amp;T tried to &amp;ldquo;lock the barn door after the crown jewels had flown the coop&amp;rdquo;. And then we had BSD, Minix, Linux, Xenix and yada yada.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>