<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>India on Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/tags/india/</link><description>Recent content in India on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'&gt;Basil Labib&lt;/a&gt; | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'&gt;Basic&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 11:50:44 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/tags/india/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Academic Dishonesty</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/academic-dishonesty/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 11:50:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/academic-dishonesty/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today is September 5th which is celebrated as Teacher&amp;rsquo;s Day in India on the birth anniversary of Dr. Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan, an eminent educator, teacher and the first Vice President of India. As Indian students reach out to pay respect to their teachers via various gestures such as feet embracing albeit digitally this year, I wish to take this opportunity to speak about a much graver issue in the Indian education scenario today.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Indian Sexual Taboo</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-indian-sexual-taboo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 15:28:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-indian-sexual-taboo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Recent unravelling of the Raj Kundra porn video business on online streaming platforms has raised many tantalizing questions on the effectiveness of the Indian judiciary. It is indeed shameful and comical to know that the judiciary is confused as to the definition of &amp;ldquo;pornography&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;obscene&amp;rdquo; and specific laws under which to prosecute Kundra and Co.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-do-porn-industries-flourish"&gt;Why do porn industries flourish?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaving prosecution and dissemination of judgement to more able individuals than me, I would like to raise few points about the other side of the coin: &lt;em&gt;The Indian porn consumer base&lt;/em&gt;. If Raj Kundra was able to lure financially compromised girls into creating obscene content and sell them for millions, then why did he succeed? &lt;strong&gt;Markets thrive where there is demand&lt;/strong&gt; - indeed, the fundamental basis of capitalism. Pornhub yearly statistics reveal Indian consumers on the site has been on a consistent rise. And that is just one provider.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>