<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Guitar on Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/tags/guitar/</link><description>Recent content in Guitar on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'>Basil Labib&lt;/a> | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Basic&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/tags/guitar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My First Guitar</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-first-guitar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-first-guitar/</guid><description>&lt;p>I admit I have become lazy. I have not written about myself for a long time. And I apologize for polluting this space with movie and book thoughts. A lot of things have been happening (or should I say, the lack thereof?). But surely, the coolest things to happen is my guitar. Yes, ladies and gentlemen! My first guitar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point, I am not clear whether the pandemic screwed me or I screwed myself. But I am certain, I feel depressed and terribly alone. When your mind is idle, it has these &lt;em>thoughts&lt;/em>, interesting thoughts. Let me share one of mine: So, people say there are introverted and so on and so forth. But they are lying. Because if they were, then they certainly wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be telling you. The point is we don&amp;rsquo;t really know any introverts. And by definition, we can never. For instance, I &lt;em>decided&lt;/em> to write about myself and my life. If I hadn&amp;rsquo;t, you would have never known anything. Now, apply this to &lt;em>every&lt;/em> person you know and let them apply it to their knowns. Those whose laughs are the most joyous are the ones truly crying.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>