<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/tags/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'>Basil Labib&lt;/a> | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Basic&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Notes: I Will Teach You To Be Rich by Ramit Sethi</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-i-will-teach-you-to-be-rich-by-ramit-sethi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-i-will-teach-you-to-be-rich-by-ramit-sethi/</guid><description>Sethi&amp;rsquo;s book, at it&amp;rsquo;s core, is a set of rules and tricks that can be applied by an aware and motivated individual to ensure a life of abundance relative to their current financial standings. Motivated to become rich himself (and hailing from India) at a young age, Sethi learnt from his blunders and noted his successes. He started blogging about his wins which eventually evolved into this book. Needless to say, his advice are well-researched, practical and tested.</description></item><item><title>Notes: The Richest Man in Babylon by George S. Clason</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-richest-man-in-babylon-by-george-s.-clason/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-richest-man-in-babylon-by-george-s.-clason/</guid><description>Notes on &amp;ldquo;The Richest Man in Babylon&amp;rdquo; by George S. Clason.
What is wealth? Wealth is a power. With wealth, many things are possible.
Essential Habits A man&amp;rsquo;s wealth is not in the purse he carries. A fat purse quickly empties if there be no golden stream to refill it.
Fate is unpredictable hence untrustworthy. It makes wanton spenders and misers alike.
Every surplus can earn for you. And every revenue on that can earn for you.</description></item><item><title>Notes: Design for Hackers by David Kadavy</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-design-for-hackers-by-david-kadavy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-design-for-hackers-by-david-kadavy/</guid><description>Why Design? Your biggest asset - &amp;ldquo;Learn whatever you want to achieve your vision&amp;rdquo;. Good designs are timeless. They can awe people of any era. Fundamental soul of a human creation that expresses itself in successive outer layers of the product. Designing of a system comes before building it not after. Affect emotion, build credibility, earn trust. Don&amp;rsquo;t draw ponies. First visual interaction thus heuristic shortcut to judge credibility. Purpose | Medium and Technology | Aesthetics Good design choices are a set of ideas that must mature in the mind.</description></item><item><title>Notes: Habits by James Clear</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-habits-by-james-clear/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-habits-by-james-clear/</guid><description>My Notes Introduction Majority fail in making habits because they try to make changes the wrong way.
It is easy to get obssessed with the result.
Never overestimate the importance of one defining moment and underestimate the value of making better decisions on a daily basis.
Don&amp;rsquo;t focus on the destination. Focus on the path.
Habits Pattern of every habit:
Reminder ( trigger ) Routine ( the action itself ) Reward ( the benefit ) A good reminder makes it easier for you to start your habit by encoding your new behavior in something that you already do, rather than relying on getting motivated.</description></item></channel></rss>