<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>book on The Personal Blog of Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/tags/book/</link><description>Recent content in book on The Personal Blog of Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/BasilLabib'>Basil Labib&lt;/a> | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Basic&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 21:02:21 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/tags/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Notes: The Millionaire Fastlane by MJ DeMarco</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-millionaire-fastlane-by-mj-demarco/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 21:02:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-millionaire-fastlane-by-mj-demarco/</guid><description>Are you able to successfully leverage the opportunities at your disposal? That is the question that this book tries to answer and provides advice backed by the author&amp;rsquo;s own experiences. The book is written in a comfortable conversational style, including way too many metaphors and analogies.
The author, himself, has a remarkable lifestyle: starting a tech company during the dot-com bubble, growing it, selling it and so on. Below I have aggregated few core ideas from the book.</description></item><item><title>Think, Wait and Fast</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/think-wait-and-fast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/think-wait-and-fast/</guid><description>In the book &amp;ldquo;Siddhartha&amp;rdquo; by Herman Hesse – the protagonist, who is a Samana (a homeless hermit), is enchanted by the beauty of a woman named Kamala. On their first discourse, Kamala asks him what is he capable of doing that he can trade for money, pretty clothes, shoes, sweet perfumes and gifts for her. To which Siddhartha replies,
&amp;ldquo;I can think. I can wait. I can fast.&amp;rdquo;
I think that is a very profound answer and it will do ignorant fools like us much good if we make an attempt to comprehend it.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts: Ready Player Two (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-ready-player-two-book/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-ready-player-two-book/</guid><description>WARNING: Literally the entire story is told. Proceed at your own risk.
TLDR If you plan to read it, you should look somewhere else.
I will keep it somewhere deep in my &amp;ldquo;Never to Read Again&amp;rdquo; stack and hope it disintegrated that way.
Yucks References! Apparently, we humans think that if something works for once than by extension more of it, no wait way more of it must be somehow better.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts: UNIX - History and Memoir (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-unix-history-and-memoir-book/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-unix-history-and-memoir-book/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s always good to know about the things you love the most. It somehow makes you love them even more. I am glad non-living things are not stupidly self-conscious and self-doubting like us and I can understand them more deeply than I can understand other humans.
Some mind(ful|less) blabberings With that said, I enjoyed this book. In Brian&amp;rsquo;s succint prose, he recollects the history of the mother of all operating systems: UNIX.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts: The Selfish Gene (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-selfish-gene-book/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-selfish-gene-book/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My favourite non-fiction read of 2020.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>