<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Book on Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/tags/book/</link><description>Recent content in Book on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'&gt;Basil Labib&lt;/a&gt; | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'&gt;Basic&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 08:58:30 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/tags/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thoughts: The Psychology of Money (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-psychology-of-money-book/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 08:58:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-psychology-of-money-book/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract"&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morgan Housel&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Psychology of Money&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; is less of a technical book and more of a collection of wisdom and wishful advices. It is N. Taleb&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bed of Procrustes&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; augmented with real life anecdotes, morsels of history, and a lot of quotations. Although Housel professes a very conservative and frugal approach to managing money, his advice cannot be disputed without a very good counter argument. The cautious models, frameworks, and signposts laid out in the book would prevent an investor from being foolish and that Housel says is too easy to be in the modern financial system.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sylvia Plath, The Bell Jar and feminism</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/sylvia-plath-the-bell-jar-and-feminism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 11:27:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/sylvia-plath-the-bell-jar-and-feminism/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="display: inline-block; font-size: 30px; font-weight: 600;"&gt;"What I hate &lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;is the thought of being under a man&amp;rsquo;s thumb&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;, Sylvia fearlessly thundered in her only published novel &amp;ldquo;The Bell Jar&amp;rdquo;. Published in 1963, &lt;em&gt;Jar&lt;/em&gt; is one of the prominent texts on feminism and the vocalisation of a woman&amp;rsquo;s apprehensions, rights and freedom. Sylvia&amp;rsquo;s words, like brazen dagger, are used today in protest marches as well as analysed in literary circles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/belljar/0.jpg"
 alt="Sylvia Plath"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sylvia Plath&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Love As An Illegitimate Byproduct</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/love-as-an-illegitimate-byproduct/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 10:18:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/love-as-an-illegitimate-byproduct/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Evolutionary biology has always fascinated me. I have marveled at the ingenuity of evolutionists drawing up elegant theories, piecing together the most bizarre of observations with a string of sound reasoning. I guess the quality of making logical sense of the alien world we find ourselves in makes evolution appeal to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I read Jared Diamond&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Why Sex is Fun?&amp;rdquo;, a short book (a series of essays really) about human sexuality and how it differs so radically from every other species we know of. His words and reasoning reminded me of Dawkins&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;The Selfish Gene&amp;rdquo; – particularly nostalgic where the spermatozoa and oocyte structural discrepency and Zahavis&amp;rsquo; principle of handicap signals; however, the prose was much easier to read than Selfish. Evolution is much like astronomy / cosmology in a certain way – both instills humility in a manner no other subject can.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Freakonomics: Should you read it?</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/freakonomics-should-you-read-it/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 11:14:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/freakonomics-should-you-read-it/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why do drug-dealers still live with their mothers?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Are Sumo wrestlers corrupt?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Legalized abortion led to decreasing crime rates&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Are real-estate agents really acting in &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; best interest?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Does a child&amp;rsquo;s name have any effect on their lives?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Do parents really matter?&amp;rdquo; &lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Are swimming pools more dangerous for kids than guns?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Why should teachers cheat?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freakonomics is a study of bizarre, mundane and exceedingly interesting questions. It employs the arsenal of mathematical sophistication to unearth truths and secrets that are hidden from plain sight. Written by an uncanny duo, Steven D. Levitt (the economist) and Stephen J. Dubner (the journalist) as part of an unexpected collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rereading 'A Thousand Splendid Suns'</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/rereading-a-thousand-splendid-suns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 18:37:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/rereading-a-thousand-splendid-suns/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;There are all these people constantly questioning me about my identity, my aspirations, &lt;em&gt;my worth&lt;/em&gt;. What I want to do? &lt;em&gt;What I want to be?&lt;/em&gt; So, I am forced to think about these questions. Indeed, what do I wanna do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reread the poignant &amp;ldquo;A Thousand Splendid Suns&amp;rdquo; by Khaled Hosseini. So, I have a habit, for better or worse, of poking around the central content to appreciate the big picture. I read a Wikipedia article on Afghanistan&amp;rsquo;s history. I found it interesting. And included 3 books on Afghan history in my library – looking forward to &amp;ldquo;A Brief History of Afghanistan&amp;rdquo; by Shaista Wahab et. al.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My Reading Portfolio</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-reading-portfolio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 12:00:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-reading-portfolio/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t met anybody as devoutly fanatic about books as I am in real life. This love of mine can turn aggressive, even generously self-depreciative, which is a source of concern. I maintain a digital library simply because &lt;em&gt;there won&amp;rsquo;t be enough room&lt;/em&gt; for all the books if I build for myself a physical library (Now you know how to impress me :winking_face:). I spend literally hours fretting about organization, intensely debating with myself what parameters to organize under, designing programs to maintain a catalog, devising makeshift ways to register progress and so on.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Notes: The Millionaire Fastlane by MJ DeMarco</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-millionaire-fastlane-by-mj-demarco/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 21:02:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-millionaire-fastlane-by-mj-demarco/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Are you able to successfully leverage the opportunities at your disposal? That is the question that this book tries to answer and provides advice backed by the author&amp;rsquo;s own experiences. The book is written in a comfortable conversational style, including &lt;em&gt;way too many&lt;/em&gt; metaphors and analogies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author, himself, has a remarkable lifestyle: starting a tech company during the dot-com bubble, growing it, selling it and so on. Below I have aggregated few core ideas from the book. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Think, Wait and Fast</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/think-wait-and-fast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/think-wait-and-fast/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the book &amp;ldquo;Siddhartha&amp;rdquo; by Herman Hesse – the protagonist, who is a Samana (a homeless hermit), is enchanted by the beauty of a woman named Kamala. On their first discourse, Kamala asks him what is he capable of doing that he can trade for money, pretty clothes, shoes, sweet perfumes and gifts for her. To which Siddhartha replies,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I can think. I can wait. I can fast.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that is a very profound answer and it will do ignorant fools like us much good if we make an attempt to comprehend it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Thoughts: UNIX - History and Memoir (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-unix-history-and-memoir-book/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-unix-history-and-memoir-book/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s always good to know about the things you love the most. It somehow makes you love them even more. I am glad non-living things are not stupidly self-conscious and self-doubting like us and I can understand them more deeply than I can understand other humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="some-mindfulless-blabberings"&gt;Some mind(ful|less) blabberings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that said, I enjoyed this book. In Brian&amp;rsquo;s succint prose, he recollects the history of &lt;em&gt;the mother of all operating systems&lt;/em&gt;: UNIX. And along the way, describes the sideways development that it encouraged such as the development of C (the “lingua franca of computing”), various timeless tools like &lt;code&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;awk&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;sed&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;yacc&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;lex&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt;, document formatters and so on. He talks about what lead to the development of UNIX and ruminates on the kind of environment contagious to such breakthroughs. Unfettered management, fun atmosphere, great minds, stable funding and the freedom and willingness to solve real-world problems. He also points out and clear a lot of the admittedly confusing history that is the legacy of Unix as the (licensed) source code of Unix reached Berkeley. As he correctly pointed out, AT&amp;amp;T tried to &amp;ldquo;lock the barn door after the crown jewels had flown the coop&amp;rdquo;. And then we had BSD, Minix, Linux, Xenix and yada yada.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Thoughts: The Selfish Gene (Book)</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-selfish-gene-book/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/thoughts-the-selfish-gene-book/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract"&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourite non-fiction read of 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>