<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nostalgia on Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/tags/nostalgia/</link><description>Recent content in Nostalgia on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'>Basil Labib&lt;/a> | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Basic&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 10:20:28 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/tags/nostalgia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Remembering My Teachers</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/remembering-my-teachers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 10:20:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/remembering-my-teachers/</guid><description>&lt;div style="display: flex;">
 &lt;div class="white" style="padding: 5px; border-radius: 4px; margin: 0.2em;">
 &lt;blockquote>
 &amp;ldquo;The right kind of education begins with the educator, who must understand himself and be free from established patterns of thought; for what he is that he imparts. If he has not been rightly educated, what can he teach except the same mechanical knowledge on which he himself has been brought up?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&lt;cite>~J Krishnamurti&lt;/cite>
 &lt;/blockquote>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>NR Narayan Murthy, the founder of Infosys, recounted three incidents in his life that taught him core human values and left an indelible mark on him. The first was when his senior school Chemistry teacher taught him the &lt;em>difference between community and personal property and how to treat each of them&lt;/em>. Second was the &lt;em>quest for global excellence&lt;/em> in whatever one chooses to do by his meticulous and obssessed engineering prof and finally the &lt;em>importance of starting any transaction on a zero base&lt;/em> by his boss at IIM-A. These are incredible life lessons and as I sat pondering how my tryst with teachers have played out, I found myself reaching for my diary. I am privileged to write that I have learned many things from them – both inside the textbook and outside.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>