<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>School on Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/tags/school/</link><description>Recent content in School on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'>Basil Labib&lt;/a> | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Basic&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 23:34:27 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/tags/school/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My School Journey</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-school-journey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 23:34:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-school-journey/</guid><description>&lt;p>Few days back, I graduated high school. Which means a journey of 14 years came to an end. I have numerous delights, some regrets and plenty of memories to take with me. I have some to share too.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="teachers">Teachers&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>First of all, I want to thank &lt;em>every&lt;/em> teacher who has taught me. From holding my hand to write an &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo; in nursery to open discussions in Physics classes to painful lectures in Literature – I have taken a part of you all. And though, I may become whatever I will, I have irrevocably become the sum of those pieces that you all have gladly given me. I am grateful to all of you, in the truest sense of the word. Moreover, coming from an indigent family, the love and support that some of you have shown me has been something I still can&amp;rsquo;t imagine. I still remember when Mrs. Bannerjee (my 10th English teacher) borrowed a dictionary on her name from the school library for me so that I could prepare for my board exams the following day. I remember Mrs. Ali and Mrs. Khan who waived my school fees for an entire year at a time when my family was going through great turmoil. Frankly, I would had to drop-out otherwise. Mrs. Kalam, who treated me as her own son, extended every possible help she could. I always felt so at home around her given the fact that I don&amp;rsquo;t like people a lot. Mrs. Sinha, who taught me Chemistry from practically the beginning. I still have the pen you gave me after I scored a 100 in boards by your guidance and blessings. And surely many, many others I cannot recall. I am a self-motivated student and all I need is a little encouragement. I am glad I got that and a lot more from all of you.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>