<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal on Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/tags/personal/</link><description>Recent content in Personal on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'>Basil Labib&lt;/a> | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Basic&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 23:34:27 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My School Journey</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-school-journey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 23:34:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-school-journey/</guid><description>Few days back, I graduated high school. Which means a journey of 14 years came to an end. I have numerous delights, some regrets and plenty of memories to take with me. I have some to share too.
Teachers First of all, I want to thank every teacher who has taught me. From holding my hand to write an &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo; in nursery to open discussions in Physics classes to painful lectures in Literature – I have taken a part of you all.</description></item><item><title>Rereading 'A Thousand Splendid Suns'</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/rereading-a-thousand-splendid-suns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 18:37:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/rereading-a-thousand-splendid-suns/</guid><description>There are all these people constantly questioning me about my identity, my aspirations, my worth. What I want to do? What I want to be? So, I am forced to think about these questions. Indeed, what do I wanna do?
I reread the poignant &amp;ldquo;A Thousand Splendid Suns&amp;rdquo; by Khaled Hosseini. So, I have a habit, for better or worse, of poking around the central content to appreciate the big picture.</description></item><item><title>Friendship</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/friendship/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 11:37:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/friendship/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;How many times had she, Hasina, and Giti said those same three words to each other, Laila wondered, said it without hesitation, after only two or three days of not seeing each other?
I missed you, Hasina. Oh, I missed you too. In Tariq&amp;rsquo;s grimace, Laila learned that boys differed from girls in this regard. They didn&amp;rsquo;t make a show of friendship. They felt no urge, no need, for this sort of talk.</description></item><item><title>My Reading Portfolio</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-reading-portfolio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 12:00:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-reading-portfolio/</guid><description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t met anybody as devoutly fanatic about books as I am in real life. This love of mine can turn aggressive, even generously self-depreciative, which is a source of concern. I maintain a digital library simply because there won&amp;rsquo;t be enough room for all the books if I build for myself a physical library (Now you know how to impress me :winking_face:). I spend literally hours fretting about organization, intensely debating with myself what parameters to organize under, designing programs to maintain a catalog, devising makeshift ways to register progress and so on.</description></item><item><title>The Sun After A Thuderstorm</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-sun-after-a-thuderstorm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-sun-after-a-thuderstorm/</guid><description>There is something magical about the first sunshine after a thunderstorm. The coolness of the still wet ground and the warm sunshine vapourising the dew. The mist hanging low over the floor mixing with the musky smell of freshly spawned algae. The chirping of the songbird as they return to their nests mingling with the chattering of the hawkers and peddlers as they return to the streets below.</description></item><item><title>Turn Down The Music</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/turn-down-the-music/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/turn-down-the-music/</guid><description>Yes, turn down the music
Throw away the booze and
Tell them the party&amp;rsquo;s over for
she isn&amp;rsquo;t here.
Rip the sky bleed,
crush every skull I find,
burn every fucking flower that blooms coz I want her. Yes, turn down the music
Throw away the booze and
Tell them the party&amp;rsquo;s over for
she isn&amp;rsquo;t here.
Was it so much to ask for your love?
I dreamt too much about us</description></item><item><title>My First Guitar</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-first-guitar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-first-guitar/</guid><description>I admit I have become lazy. I have not written about myself for a long time. And I apologize for polluting this space with movie and book thoughts. A lot of things have been happening (or should I say, the lack thereof?). But surely, the coolest things to happen is my guitar. Yes, ladies and gentlemen! My first guitar.
At this point, I am not clear whether the pandemic screwed me or I screwed myself.</description></item><item><title>My Music Order Arrived</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-music-order-arrived/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-music-order-arrived/</guid><description>A rather crazy self-imposed project which I had the faintest of ideas will become all-devouring and pose countless hurdles for me to dodge. But yeah, did it. Don&amp;rsquo;t blame me for the CT making ethereal noises!
From left to right: Treasure, Stars and Topsoil and Heaven or Las Vegas (all CDs)
Why do I have to buy music? In a nutshell, because I want to. But seriously, why in a world of Spotify and pirated downloadable songs would I have the brilliant idea to buy music?</description></item><item><title>My First Open Source Excursion</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-first-open-source-excursion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-first-open-source-excursion/</guid><description>Granted that I have atleast a dozen projects hanging in midair (figuratively) on my hard disk (literally). And I have a couple of repos on github in near stasis but today I had my first whiff of open source. Open source doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean much without collaboration and today I dabbled in real time. Contributing code to a public repo, getting feedback and watching it getting approved. Oh! I felt rewarded.</description></item><item><title>Stuck by Fandom for the First Time in My Life</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/stuck-by-fandom-for-the-first-time-in-my-life/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/stuck-by-fandom-for-the-first-time-in-my-life/</guid><description>Ethereal, heavenly, celestial, opulent, splendid, otherworldly - these adjectives form the regular staple of people who dare to describe the music of the Cocteau Twins (pronounced: cock-tow twins). Honestly, I think it&amp;rsquo;s an effort in vain. Because this band defies all possibilities of being defined by words. Cage them in artificial genres and you will fail. You can only experience their &amp;ldquo;sacred microcosm&amp;rdquo; yourself as Azam Ali so eloquently puts it.</description></item></channel></rss>