<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal on Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/tags/personal/</link><description>Recent content in Personal on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'>Basil Labib&lt;/a> | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Basic&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 23:34:27 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My School Journey</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-school-journey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 23:34:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-school-journey/</guid><description>&lt;p>Few days back, I graduated high school. Which means a journey of 14 years came to an end. I have numerous delights, some regrets and plenty of memories to take with me. I have some to share too.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="teachers">Teachers&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>First of all, I want to thank &lt;em>every&lt;/em> teacher who has taught me. From holding my hand to write an &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo; in nursery to open discussions in Physics classes to painful lectures in Literature – I have taken a part of you all. And though, I may become whatever I will, I have irrevocably become the sum of those pieces that you all have gladly given me. I am grateful to all of you, in the truest sense of the word. Moreover, coming from an indigent family, the love and support that some of you have shown me has been something I still can&amp;rsquo;t imagine. I still remember when Mrs. Bannerjee (my 10th English teacher) borrowed a dictionary on her name from the school library for me so that I could prepare for my board exams the following day. I remember Mrs. Ali and Mrs. Khan who waived my school fees for an entire year at a time when my family was going through great turmoil. Frankly, I would had to drop-out otherwise. Mrs. Kalam, who treated me as her own son, extended every possible help she could. I always felt so at home around her given the fact that I don&amp;rsquo;t like people a lot. Mrs. Sinha, who taught me Chemistry from practically the beginning. I still have the pen you gave me after I scored a 100 in boards by your guidance and blessings. And surely many, many others I cannot recall. I am a self-motivated student and all I need is a little encouragement. I am glad I got that and a lot more from all of you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rereading 'A Thousand Splendid Suns'</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/rereading-a-thousand-splendid-suns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 18:37:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/rereading-a-thousand-splendid-suns/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are all these people constantly questioning me about my identity, my aspirations, &lt;em>my worth&lt;/em>. What I want to do? &lt;em>What I want to be?&lt;/em> So, I am forced to think about these questions. Indeed, what do I wanna do?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I reread the poignant &amp;ldquo;A Thousand Splendid Suns&amp;rdquo; by Khaled Hosseini. So, I have a habit, for better or worse, of poking around the central content to appreciate the big picture. I read a Wikipedia article on Afghanistan&amp;rsquo;s history. I found it interesting. And included 3 books on Afghan history in my library – looking forward to &amp;ldquo;A Brief History of Afghanistan&amp;rdquo; by Shaista Wahab et. al.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Friendship</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/friendship/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 11:37:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/friendship/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;How many times had she, Hasina, and Giti said those same three words to each other,
Laila wondered, said it without hesitation, after only two or three days of not seeing
each other?&lt;br>
&lt;em>I missed you, Hasina.&lt;/em> &lt;em>Oh, I missed you too&lt;/em>. In Tariq&amp;rsquo;s grimace, Laila learned
that boys differed from girls in this regard. They didn&amp;rsquo;t make a show of friendship. They
felt no urge, no need, for this sort of talk. Laila imagined it had been this way for her
brothers too. Boys, Laila came to see, treated friendship the way they treated the sun: its
existence undisputed; its radiance best enjoyed, not beheld directly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Reading Portfolio</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-reading-portfolio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 12:00:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-reading-portfolio/</guid><description>&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t met anybody as devoutly fanatic about books as I am in real life. This love of mine can turn aggressive, even generously self-depreciative, which is a source of concern. I maintain a digital library simply because &lt;em>there won&amp;rsquo;t be enough room&lt;/em> for all the books if I build for myself a physical library (Now you know how to impress me :winking_face:). I spend literally hours fretting about organization, intensely debating with myself what parameters to organize under, designing programs to maintain a catalog, devising makeshift ways to register progress and so on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Sun After A Thuderstorm</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-sun-after-a-thuderstorm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/the-sun-after-a-thuderstorm/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is something magical about the first sunshine after a thunderstorm. The coolness of the still wet ground and the warm sunshine vapourising the dew. The mist hanging low over the floor mixing with the musky smell of freshly spawned algae. The chirping of the songbird as they return to their nests mingling with the chattering of the hawkers and peddlers as they return to the streets below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Turn Down The Music</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/turn-down-the-music/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/turn-down-the-music/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Yes, turn down the music&lt;br>
Throw away the booze and&lt;br>
Tell them the party&amp;rsquo;s over for&lt;br>
she isn&amp;rsquo;t here.&lt;br>
Rip the sky bleed,&lt;br>
crush every skull I find,&lt;br>
burn every fucking flower &lt;br>
that blooms coz I want her. &lt;br>
Yes, turn down the music&lt;br>
Throw away the booze and&lt;br>
Tell them the party&amp;rsquo;s over for&lt;br>
she isn&amp;rsquo;t here.&lt;br>
Was it so much to ask for your love?&lt;br>
I dreamt too much about us&lt;br>
But you were too conceited. Now,&lt;br>
Switch off the lights &lt;br>
And, turn down the music&lt;br>
Throw away the booze and&lt;br>
Tell them the party&amp;rsquo;s over for&lt;br>
she isn&amp;rsquo;t here. &lt;br>
— b.l.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My First Guitar</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-first-guitar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-first-guitar/</guid><description>&lt;p>I admit I have become lazy. I have not written about myself for a long time. And I apologize for polluting this space with movie and book thoughts. A lot of things have been happening (or should I say, the lack thereof?). But surely, the coolest things to happen is my guitar. Yes, ladies and gentlemen! My first guitar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point, I am not clear whether the pandemic screwed me or I screwed myself. But I am certain, I feel depressed and terribly alone. When your mind is idle, it has these &lt;em>thoughts&lt;/em>, interesting thoughts. Let me share one of mine: So, people say there are introverted and so on and so forth. But they are lying. Because if they were, then they certainly wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be telling you. The point is we don&amp;rsquo;t really know any introverts. And by definition, we can never. For instance, I &lt;em>decided&lt;/em> to write about myself and my life. If I hadn&amp;rsquo;t, you would have never known anything. Now, apply this to &lt;em>every&lt;/em> person you know and let them apply it to their knowns. Those whose laughs are the most joyous are the ones truly crying.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Music Order Arrived</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-music-order-arrived/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-music-order-arrived/</guid><description>&lt;p>A rather crazy self-imposed project which I had the faintest of ideas will become all-devouring and pose countless hurdles for me to dodge. But yeah, did it. Don&amp;rsquo;t blame me for the CT making ethereal noises!&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://basil08.github.io/img/ctcd1.jpg"
 alt="From left to right: Treasure, Stars and Topsoil and Heaven or Las Vegas (all CDs)">&lt;figcaption>
 &lt;p>From left to right: Treasure, Stars and Topsoil and Heaven or Las Vegas (all CDs)&lt;/p>
 &lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>

&lt;h2 id="why-do-i-have-to-buy-music">Why do I have to buy music?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, because I want to. But seriously, why in a world of Spotify and pirated downloadable songs would I have the brilliant idea to &lt;em>buy&lt;/em> music?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My First Open Source Excursion</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-first-open-source-excursion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/my-first-open-source-excursion/</guid><description>&lt;p>Granted that I have atleast a dozen projects hanging in midair (figuratively) on my hard disk (literally).
And I have a couple of repos on github in near stasis but today I had my first whiff of open source. Open source doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean much without collaboration and today I dabbled in real time. Contributing code to a public repo, getting feedback and watching it getting approved. Oh! I felt rewarded.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stuck by Fandom for the First Time in My Life</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/stuck-by-fandom-for-the-first-time-in-my-life/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/stuck-by-fandom-for-the-first-time-in-my-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ethereal, heavenly, celestial, opulent, splendid, otherworldly - these adjectives form the regular staple of people who dare to describe the music of the Cocteau Twins (pronounced: cock-tow twins). Honestly, I think it&amp;rsquo;s an effort in vain. Because this band defies all possibilities of being defined by words. Cage them in artificial genres and you will fail. You can only &lt;em>experience&lt;/em> their &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;sacred microcosm&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> yourself as Azam Ali so eloquently puts &lt;a href="https://www.talkhouse.com/the-sacred-microcosm-of-the-cocteau-twins">it&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>