<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Economics on Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/tags/economics/</link><description>Recent content in Economics on Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/itbwtsh'>Basil Labib&lt;/a> | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Basic&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 16:56:47 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/tags/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Closer Look at 'Inside Job'</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-closer-look-at-inside-job/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 16:56:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/a-closer-look-at-inside-job/</guid><description>&lt;!-- 


&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/4XVLECplZwd2OrHFkfy6Te"
 width="100%"
 height="380"
 frameborder="0"
 allowtransparency="true"
 allow="encrypted-media">&lt;/iframe>
 -->
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Inside Job&amp;rdquo; is a 2010 documentary written, directed and produced by Charles Ferguson on the 2008 global financial crisis. It won the Oscar in the &amp;ldquo;Best Documentary Feature&amp;rdquo; category in 2011. Notwithstanding, it makes for an enlightening and thrilling watch that every citizen, who cares about where their hard earned money goes, should watch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This documentary is not an easy watch that one can grab on a lazy afternoon comfortable on their couch. It has complex sounding terms and concepts that should keep one on the edge of their seat. As those financial experts makes the layman believe, &amp;ldquo;What we do is far more complicated for you to understand so you better leave us alone as we do it.&amp;rdquo; They are soft-headed people who will make one feel witless and run away with their money. That is exactly what happened in 2008.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Freakonomics: Should you read it?</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/freakonomics-should-you-read-it/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 11:14:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/freakonomics-should-you-read-it/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Why do drug-dealers still live with their mothers?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Are Sumo wrestlers corrupt?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Legalized abortion led to decreasing crime rates&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Are real-estate agents really acting in &lt;em>your&lt;/em> best interest?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Does a child&amp;rsquo;s name have any effect on their lives?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Do parents really matter?&amp;rdquo; &lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Are swimming pools more dangerous for kids than guns?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Why should teachers cheat?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Freakonomics is a study of bizarre, mundane and exceedingly interesting questions. It employs the arsenal of mathematical sophistication to unearth truths and secrets that are hidden from plain sight. Written by an uncanny duo, Steven D. Levitt (the economist) and Stephen J. Dubner (the journalist) as part of an unexpected collaboration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is Governance Really So Difficult?</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/is-governance-really-so-difficult/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 13:15:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/is-governance-really-so-difficult/</guid><description>&lt;p>Why is taking economic decisions at a national level such a tantalizing task? Why do government policies fail (sometimes miserably)? Why are people still living on the streets under BPL?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can expose yourself to an array of criticism and theories spun by supposedly thoughtful individuals at any cafe. These folks go on blurting how the present is worse than a decade ago and on and on. I had heard about their side, I wanted to know about the other side too.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>