<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>finance on The Personal Blog of Basil Labib</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/tags/finance/</link><description>Recent content in finance on The Personal Blog of Basil Labib</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/BasilLabib'>Basil Labib&lt;/a> | Made with ❤️ using &lt;a href='https://gohugo.io'>Hugo&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href='https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic'>Basic&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 21:02:21 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basil08.github.io/tags/finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Notes: The Millionaire Fastlane by MJ DeMarco</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-millionaire-fastlane-by-mj-demarco/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 21:02:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-millionaire-fastlane-by-mj-demarco/</guid><description>Are you able to successfully leverage the opportunities at your disposal? That is the question that this book tries to answer and provides advice backed by the author&amp;rsquo;s own experiences. The book is written in a comfortable conversational style, including way too many metaphors and analogies.
The author, himself, has a remarkable lifestyle: starting a tech company during the dot-com bubble, growing it, selling it and so on. Below I have aggregated few core ideas from the book.</description></item><item><title>Notes: I Will Teach You To Be Rich by Ramit Sethi</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-i-will-teach-you-to-be-rich-by-ramit-sethi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-i-will-teach-you-to-be-rich-by-ramit-sethi/</guid><description>Sethi&amp;rsquo;s book, at it&amp;rsquo;s core, is a set of rules and tricks that can be applied by an aware and motivated individual to ensure a life of abundance relative to their current financial standings. Motivated to become rich himself (and hailing from India) at a young age, Sethi learnt from his blunders and noted his successes. He started blogging about his wins which eventually evolved into this book. Needless to say, his advice are well-researched, practical and tested.</description></item><item><title>Notes: The Richest Man in Babylon by George S. Clason</title><link>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-richest-man-in-babylon-by-george-s.-clason/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basil08.github.io/post/notes-the-richest-man-in-babylon-by-george-s.-clason/</guid><description>Notes on &amp;ldquo;The Richest Man in Babylon&amp;rdquo; by George S. Clason.
What is wealth? Wealth is a power. With wealth, many things are possible.
Essential Habits A man&amp;rsquo;s wealth is not in the purse he carries. A fat purse quickly empties if there be no golden stream to refill it.
Fate is unpredictable hence untrustworthy. It makes wanton spenders and misers alike.
Every surplus can earn for you.</description></item></channel></rss>